{
	"description": "Kanji for JLPT N3",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "一人一人", "answers": [ "ひとりひとり" ], "comment": "one by one; each; one at a time" },
	{ "question": "一体", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "...the heck (e.g. \"what the heck?\"); ...in the world (e.g. \"why in the world?\"); ...on earth (e.g. \"who on earth?\")\none object; one body; unity\none form; one style\none Buddhist image (or carving, etc.)\ngenerally; in general" },
	{ "question": "一家", "answers": [ "いっか" ], "comment": "a house; a home; a family; a household; one's family; one's folks; a style" },
	{ "question": "一層", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "much more; still more; all the more; more than ever\nsingle layer (or storey, etc.)\nrather; sooner; preferably" },
	{ "question": "一度に", "answers": [ "いちどに" ], "comment": "all at once" },
	{ "question": "一方", "answers": [ "いっぽう" ], "comment": "one (esp. of two); the other; one way; the other way; one direction; the other direction; one side; the other side; one party; the other party\non the one hand; on the other hand\nwhereas; although; but at the same time; meanwhile; in turn\njust keeps; being inclined to ...; tending to be ...; tending to do ...; continuously ...; just keeps on ...ing; only\none person\n(often in negative form) ordinary; common" },
	{ "question": "一時", "answers": [ "いちじ", "ひととき", "いっとき" ], "comment": "moment; a (short) time; a while\nformer times\ntwo-hour period\none o'clock\nonce; at one time; formerly; before\nfor a time; for a while; for the time being; for the present; for the moment; temporarily\na time; one time; once" },
	{ "question": "一生", "answers": [ "いっしょう" ], "comment": "whole life; a lifetime; all through life; one existence; a generation; an age; the whole world; the era\n(the only, the greatest, etc.) of one's life" },
	{ "question": "一番", "answers": [ "いちばん" ], "comment": "number one; first; first place\nbest; most\ngame; round; bout\nas a test; as an experiment; by way of experiment; by way of trial; tentatively\nsong (e.g. in noh); piece\npair; couple; brace" },
	{ "question": "一瞬", "answers": [ "いっしゅん" ], "comment": "instant; moment; for an instant" },
	{ "question": "一種", "answers": [ "いっしゅ" ], "comment": "species; kind; variety" },
	{ "question": "一致", "answers": [ "いっち" ], "comment": "coincidence; agreement; union; match\nconformity; consistency\ncooperation" },
	{ "question": "一般", "answers": [ "いっぱん" ], "comment": "general; universal\nordinary; average; common" },
	{ "question": "一言", "answers": [ "ひとこと" ], "comment": "single word; a few words; brief comment" },
	{ "question": "万一", "answers": [ "まんいち" ], "comment": "emergency; unlikely event\nby some chance; by some possibility" },
	{ "question": "上京", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "上等", "answers": [ "じょうとう" ], "comment": "superior; first-class; excellent; top quality\n(that's) just fine!; bring it on!" },
	{ "question": "上達", "answers": [ "じょうたつ" ], "comment": "improvement (e.g. in skill, ability); advance; progress\ncommunication of opinions of the general populace to those of high rank" },
	{ "question": "下さる", "answers": [ "くださる" ], "comment": "to give; to confer; to bestow\nto kindly do for one; to oblige; to favour; to favor" },
	{ "question": "下す", "answers": [ "おろす", "くだす" ], "comment": "to make a decision; to draw a conclusion\nto give a judgement; to hand down a verdict; to pass a sentence; to give an order\nto let go down; to lower\nto do oneself; to do by oneself\nto beat; to defeat\nto have loose bowels; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to discharge from the body\nto do in one go; to do to the end without stopping\nto take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "下り", "answers": [ "くだり" ], "comment": "down-train (going away from Tokyo)\ndown-slope; downward going" },
	{ "question": "不", "answers": [ "ふ" ], "comment": "un-; non-; negative prefix\nun-; non-\nbad ...; poor ..." },
	{ "question": "不利", "answers": [ "ふり" ], "comment": "disadvantage; handicap; unfavorable position" },
	{ "question": "不可", "answers": [ "ふか" ], "comment": "wrong; bad; improper; unjustifiable; inadvisable\nnot allowed; not possible\nfailing grade" },
	{ "question": "不安", "answers": [ "ふあん" ], "comment": "anxiety; uneasiness; insecurity; suspense" },
	{ "question": "不平", "answers": [ "ふへい" ], "comment": "complaint; discontent; dissatisfaction" },
	{ "question": "不幸", "answers": [ "ふこう" ], "comment": "unhappiness; sorrow; misfortune; disaster; accident\ndeath (usu. of a relative); bereavement" },
	{ "question": "不思議", "answers": [ "ふしぎ" ], "comment": "wonder; miracle; strange; mystery; marvel; curiosity" },
	{ "question": "不正", "answers": [ "ふせい" ], "comment": "injustice; unfairness; iniquity; impropriety; irregularity; dishonesty; illegality; fraud" },
	{ "question": "不満", "answers": [ "ふまん" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; displeasure; discontent; complaints; unhappiness; disgruntled" },
	{ "question": "不自由", "answers": [ "ふじゆう" ], "comment": "discomfort; inconvenience\npoverty; want; destitution\ndisability; impairment (physical, mental, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "不足", "answers": [ "ふそく" ], "comment": "insufficiency; shortage; deficiency; lack; dearth" },
	{ "question": "与える", "answers": [ "あたえる" ], "comment": "to give (esp. to someone of lower status); to bestow; to grant; to confer; to present; to award\nto provide; to afford; to offer; to supply\nto assign\nto cause\nto pass (a variable to a function)" },
	{ "question": "世の中", "answers": [ "よのなか" ], "comment": "society; the world; the times" },
	{ "question": "世紀", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "century; era" },
	{ "question": "世話", "answers": [ "せわ" ], "comment": "looking after; help; aid; assistance" },
	{ "question": "世間", "answers": [ "せけん" ], "comment": "world; society" },
	{ "question": "丘", "answers": [ "おか" ], "comment": "hill; height; knoll; rising ground\nbonus points awarded to the winner at the end of a game\nmound; hill" },
	{ "question": "両替", "answers": [ "りょうがえ" ], "comment": "change; money exchange" },
	{ "question": "中古", "answers": [ "ちゅうこ" ], "comment": "used; second-hand; old\nMiddle Ages" },
	{ "question": "中央", "answers": [ "ちゅうおう" ], "comment": "centre; center; middle; heart\nmetropolis; capital city; central government" },
	{ "question": "中学", "answers": [ "ちゅうがく" ], "comment": "middle school; junior high school" },
	{ "question": "中心", "answers": [ "ちゅうしん" ], "comment": "center; centre; middle; heart; core; focus; pivot; emphasis; balance\n-centered; -centred; -focussed; -oriented; centered on; focussed on\ncore\ntang (of a sword, etc.)\nmiddle of a nest of boxes" },
	{ "question": "中止", "answers": [ "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "suspension; stoppage; discontinuance; interruption" },
	{ "question": "丸", "answers": [ "まる" ], "comment": "circle\nentirety; whole; full; complete\nmoney; dough; moola\nenclosure inside a castle's walls\nsoft-shelled turtle\nsuffix for ship names; suffix for names of people (esp. infants); suffix for names of swords, armour, musical instruments, etc.; suffix for names of dogs, horses, etc.\nfishball; meatball\npill" },
	{ "question": "丸い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "主に", "answers": [ "おもに" ], "comment": "mainly; primarily" },
	{ "question": "主婦", "answers": [ "しゅふ" ], "comment": "housewife; mistress (of the house); homemaker" },
	{ "question": "主張", "answers": [ "しゅちょう" ], "comment": "claim; request; insistence; assertion; advocacy; emphasis; contention; opinion; tenet" },
	{ "question": "主義", "answers": [ "しゅぎ" ], "comment": "doctrine; rule; principle; -ism" },
	{ "question": "主要", "answers": [ "しゅよう" ], "comment": "chief; main; principal; major" },
	{ "question": "乗せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "to place on (something)\nto give (someone) a ride; to give a lift; to pick up; to help on board\nto load (luggage); to carry; to take on board\nto send out (on the airwaves, etc.)\nto deceive; to take for a ride\nto (sing) along with (musical accompaniment)\nto let (someone) take part\nto excite (someone)" },
	{ "question": "乗客", "answers": [ "じょうきゃく" ], "comment": "passenger" },
	{ "question": "予報", "answers": [ "よほう" ], "comment": "forecast; prediction" },
	{ "question": "予期", "answers": [ "よき" ], "comment": "expectation; assume will happen; forecast" },
	{ "question": "予測", "answers": [ "よそく" ], "comment": "prediction; estimation" },
	{ "question": "予算", "answers": [ "よさん" ], "comment": "estimate; budget" },
	{ "question": "予防", "answers": [ "よぼう" ], "comment": "prevention; precaution; protection against" },
	{ "question": "事", "answers": [ "こと" ], "comment": "thing; matter\nincident; occurrence; event; something serious; trouble; crisis\ncircumstances; situation; state of affairs\nwork; business; affair\nafter an inflectable word, creates a noun phrase indicating something the speaker does not feel close to\nnominalizing suffix\npretending to ...; playing make-believe ...\nalias; aka; nickname; alternative name; also known as\nindividual concrete phenomenon (as opposed to a general principle)\nnominalizing suffix\npretending to ...; playing make-believe ..." },
	{ "question": "事件", "answers": [ "じけん" ], "comment": "event; affair; incident; case; plot; trouble; scandal" },
	{ "question": "事務", "answers": [ "じむ" ], "comment": "business; office work; administration" },
	{ "question": "事実", "answers": [ "じじつ" ], "comment": "fact; truth; reality" },
	{ "question": "事情", "answers": [ "じじょう" ], "comment": "circumstances; consideration; conditions; situation; reasons; state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "事態", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "situation; (present) state of affairs; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "二十（歳）", "answers": [ "はたち" ] },
	{ "question": "互い", "answers": [ "たがい" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal" },
	{ "question": "交換", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "exchange; interchange; switching; reciprocity; barter; substitution; replacement; clearing (of checks, cheques)" },
	{ "question": "交際", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "company; friendship; association; society; acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "人工", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "artificial; man-made; human work; human skill; artificiality" },
	{ "question": "人気", "answers": [ "にんき" ], "comment": "popularity; public favor\ncondition (e.g. market); tone; character; nature\nsign of life; human presence\nhumanity; humaneness\nprevailing mood of a locality; emotional climate of a district" },
	{ "question": "人物", "answers": [ "じんぶつ" ], "comment": "person; character; figure; personage; man; woman\none's character; one's personality\nable person; talented person" },
	{ "question": "人生", "answers": [ "じんせい" ], "comment": "(human) life (i.e. conception to death)" },
	{ "question": "人種", "answers": [ "じんしゅ" ], "comment": "race (of people)\ntype of person" },
	{ "question": "人込み", "answers": [ "ひとごみ" ], "comment": "crowd of people" },
	{ "question": "人間", "answers": [ "にんげん" ], "comment": "human being; person; man; mankind; humankind\ncharacter (of a person)\nthe world" },
	{ "question": "人類", "answers": [ "じんるい" ], "comment": "mankind; humanity" },
	{ "question": "今に", "answers": [ "いまに" ], "comment": "before long; even now" },
	{ "question": "今にも", "answers": [ "いまにも" ], "comment": "at any time; soon" },
	{ "question": "今回", "answers": [ "こんかい" ], "comment": "now; this time; lately" },
	{ "question": "今後", "answers": [ "こんご" ], "comment": "from now on; hereafter" },
	{ "question": "今日", "answers": [ "こんにち" ], "comment": "today; this day\nthese days; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "仏", "answers": [ "ほとけ", "ぶつ", "ふつ" ], "comment": "France\nBuddha; Buddhism\nBuddha; merciful person; Buddhist image\nthe dead; dead person; spirit of the dead" },
	{ "question": "他", "answers": [ "た", "ほか" ], "comment": "other (place, thing, person); the rest\noutside; beyond\nnothing except; nothing but; nothing apart from; nothing aside from; no choice (but to)\nbesides...; in addition to...\nother (esp. people and abstract matters)" },
	{ "question": "他人", "answers": [ "たにん" ], "comment": "another person; other people; others\nunrelated person (i.e. not related by blood)\noutsider; stranger" },
	{ "question": "付き合い", "answers": [ "つきあい" ], "comment": "association; socializing; socialising; fellowship" },
	{ "question": "付ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment)\nto furnish (a house with)\nto wear; to put on\nto keep a diary; to make an entry\nto appraise; to set (a price)\nto allot; to budget; to assign\nto bring alongside\nto place (under guard or doctor)\nto follow; to shadow\nto load; to give (courage to)\nto keep (an eye on)\nto establish (relations or understanding)\nto turn on (light)\nto produce flowers; to produce fruit" },
	{ "question": "代理", "answers": [ "だいり" ], "comment": "representation; agency; proxy; deputy; agent; attorney; substitute; alternate; acting (principal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "代表", "answers": [ "だいひょう" ], "comment": "representative; representation; delegation; type; example; model" },
	{ "question": "代金", "answers": [ "だいきん" ], "comment": "price; cost; charge; payment; bill; fee" },
	{ "question": "以前", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "ago; since; before; previous" },
	{ "question": "以来", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "since; henceforth" },
	{ "question": "仲", "answers": [ "なか" ], "comment": "relation; relationship\nbroker; brokerage; brokerage fee" },
	{ "question": "仲間", "answers": [ "なかま" ], "comment": "samurai's attendant; footman\ncompany; fellow; colleague; associate; comrade; mate; group; circle of friends; partner\nmember of the same category" },
	{ "question": "任せる", "answers": [ "まかせる" ], "comment": "to entrust (e.g. a task) to another; to leave to\nto passively leave to someone else's facilities\nto leave to take its natural course\nto continue (something) in a natural fashion (without particular aim)\nto rely fully on one's (full strength, great ability, long time taken) to get something done" },
	{ "question": "企業", "answers": [ "きぎょう" ], "comment": "enterprise; undertaking; corporation; business" },
	{ "question": "休憩", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "rest; break; recess; intermission" },
	{ "question": "休暇", "answers": [ "きゅうか" ], "comment": "holiday; day off; furlough; absence (from work)" },
	{ "question": "会", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.)\nmeeting; assembly; party\nassociation; club" },
	{ "question": "会合", "answers": [ "かいごう" ], "comment": "meeting; assembly; gathering\nassociation\nconjunction" },
	{ "question": "会員", "answers": [ "かいいん" ], "comment": "member; the membership" },
	{ "question": "会計", "answers": [ "かいけい" ], "comment": "account; finance; accountant; treasurer; paymaster; reckoning; bill" },
	{ "question": "伝統", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "tradition; convention" },
	{ "question": "伸ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "to grow long (e.g. hair, nails)\nto lengthen; to extend; to stretch\nto reach out; to hold out\nto straighten; to smooth out\nto spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.)\nto dilute; to thin out\nto postpone\nto prolong\nto strengthen; to develop; to expand" },
	{ "question": "伸びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "to stretch; to extend; to lengthen; to spread\nto make progress; to grow (beard, body height)\nto grow stale (soba)\nto be straightened; to be flattened; to be smoothed\nto be exhausted" },
	{ "question": "伺う", "answers": [ "うかがう" ], "comment": "to ask; to inquire; to hear; to be told\nto implore (a god for an oracle); to seek direction (from your superior)\nto visit\nto speak to (a large crowd at a theatre, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "似合う", "answers": [ "にあう" ], "comment": "to suit; to match; to become; to be like" },
	{ "question": "位", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "throne; crown; (nobleman's) seat\ngovernment position; court rank\nsocial standing; rank; class; echelon; rung\ngrade (of quality, etc.); level; tier; rank\ndigit (e.g. the tens, the hundreds, etc.); place\ndegree; extent; amount\nrank; place (e.g. first place)\ndecimal place\ncounter for ghosts" },
	{ "question": "位置", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "place; situation; position; location" },
	{ "question": "住宅", "answers": [ "じゅうたく" ], "comment": "residence; housing; residential building" },
	{ "question": "住民", "answers": [ "じゅうみん" ], "comment": "citizens; inhabitants; residents; population" },
	{ "question": "体温", "answers": [ "たいおん" ], "comment": "temperature; body temperature (human, animal)" },
	{ "question": "体育", "answers": [ "たいいく" ], "comment": "physical education; gymnastics; athletics" },
	{ "question": "何か", "answers": [ "なにか" ], "comment": "something" },
	{ "question": "何で", "answers": [ "なんで" ], "comment": "why?; what for?\nhow?; by what means?" },
	{ "question": "何でも", "answers": [ "なんでも" ], "comment": "any; whatever one likes; by all means; anything; everything\nI am told; I understand; they say; I hear" },
	{ "question": "何とか", "answers": [ "なんとか" ], "comment": "something; something or other; so-and-so\nsomehow; anyhow; one way or another" },
	{ "question": "余り", "answers": [ "あまり" ], "comment": "remainder; rest; balance; remains; scraps; residue; remnant\nnot very (with negative sentence); not much\nsurplus; excess; fullness; too much\nmore than; over" },
	{ "question": "余分", "answers": [ "よぶん" ], "comment": "extra; excess; surplus" },
	{ "question": "余裕", "answers": [ "よゆう" ], "comment": "surplus; margin; leeway; room; time; allowance; flexibility; scope; rope\ncomposure; placidity; complacency; calm" },
	{ "question": "作品", "answers": [ "さくひん" ], "comment": "work (e.g. book, film, composition, etc.); opus; performance; production" },
	{ "question": "作家", "answers": [ "さっか" ], "comment": "author; writer; novelist; artist" },
	{ "question": "作曲", "answers": [ "さっきょく" ], "comment": "composition; setting (of music)" },
	{ "question": "作業", "answers": [ "さぎょう" ], "comment": "work; operation; manufacturing; fatigue duty" },
	{ "question": "作法", "answers": [ "さほう" ], "comment": "manners; etiquette; propriety\nmanner of production (esp. of prose, poetry, etc.); way of making" },
	{ "question": "作物", "answers": [ "さくもつ" ], "comment": "literary work\nproduce (e.g. agricultural); crops" },
	{ "question": "使用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "use; application; employment; utilization; utilisation" },
	{ "question": "例", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "custom; practice; habit; usual\nsaid; aforementioned\ninstance; example; case; illustration; usage\nprecedent\nprecedent; example" },
	{ "question": "供給", "answers": [ "きょうきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; provision" },
	{ "question": "依頼", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "request; commission; dispatch; despatch\ndependence; trust" },
	{ "question": "価値", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "value; worth; merit" },
	{ "question": "価格", "answers": [ "かかく" ], "comment": "price; value; cost" },
	{ "question": "便", "answers": [ "びん", "べん" ], "comment": "flight (e.g. airline flight); trip (e.g. train trip); service\nmail; post; letter\nopportunity; chance\nconvenience; service; facility; accommodation\nexcreta (esp. faeces); excrement; stool\nsomething to rely on; aid; clue; way; means\nsomeone to rely on; relative\nreminder; memento" },
	{ "question": "便り", "answers": [ "たより" ], "comment": "news; tidings; information; correspondence; letter" },
	{ "question": "係", "answers": [ "かかり" ], "comment": "charge; duty; person in charge; official; clerk\nconnection; linking\ncharge; duty; person in charge; official; clerk" },
	{ "question": "保存", "answers": [ "ほぞん" ], "comment": "preservation; conservation; storage; saving (e.g. to disk); maintenance" },
	{ "question": "保証", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "guarantee; security; assurance; pledge; warranty" },
	{ "question": "信じる", "answers": [ "しんじる" ], "comment": "to believe; to believe in; to place trust in; to confide in; to have faith in" },
	{ "question": "信仰", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(religious) faith; belief; creed" },
	{ "question": "信号", "answers": [ "しんごう" ], "comment": "signal; signalling; signaling\ntraffic light; traffic signal" },
	{ "question": "信用", "answers": [ "しんよう" ], "comment": "confidence; dependence; credit; faith; reliance; belief; credence; trust" },
	{ "question": "信頼", "answers": [ "しんらい" ], "comment": "reliance; trust; faith; confidence" },
	{ "question": "修正", "answers": [ "しゅうせい" ], "comment": "amendment; correction; revision; modification; alteration; retouching; update; fix" },
	{ "question": "修理", "answers": [ "しゅうり" ], "comment": "repairing; mending; servicing" },
	{ "question": "俳優", "answers": [ "はいゆう" ], "comment": "actor; actress; player; performer" },
	{ "question": "個人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "individual; private person; personal; private" },
	{ "question": "倒す", "answers": [ "たおす" ], "comment": "to throw down; to bring down; to blow down; to fell; to knock down; to set (something) down on its side; to turn (something) on its side\nto kill; to defeat; to beat\nto overthrow; to trip up; to ruin\nto leave unpaid; to cheat\nto knock down; to knock over" },
	{ "question": "候補", "answers": [ "こうほ" ], "comment": "candidate; contender; prospect; pick; choice; list\ncandidacy; candidature; nomination" },
	{ "question": "借金", "answers": [ "しゃっきん" ], "comment": "debt; loan; liabilities; borrowing money" },
	{ "question": "値", "answers": [ "ね", "あたい" ], "comment": "price; cost\nvalue; worth; merit\nvalue; count; number\nvariable (computer programming, programing)\nlevel; value" },
	{ "question": "値段", "answers": [ "ねだん" ], "comment": "price; cost" },
	{ "question": "偉大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "greatness" },
	{ "question": "停留所", "answers": [ "ていりゅうじょ" ], "comment": "bus stop; tram stop; stop; station" },
	{ "question": "健康", "answers": [ "けんこう" ], "comment": "health; sound; wholesome" },
	{ "question": "側", "answers": [ "そば", "かわ", "がわ" ], "comment": "near; close; beside; vicinity; proximity; besides; while\nthird person\nside (of something, or taking someone's side); part\n(watch) case\nside; edge; beside; besides; nearby\nwhile (doing); in addition to; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "偶々", "answers": [ "たまたま" ], "comment": "casually; unexpectedly; accidentally; by chance" },
	{ "question": "偶然", "answers": [ "ぐうぜん" ], "comment": "coincidence; chance; accident; fortuity\nby chance; unexpectedly\ncontingency (philosophy)" },
	{ "question": "備える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install\nto have ready; to prepare for\nto possess (all that is needed); to be endowed with; to be armed with\nto be born with; to have since birth" },
	{ "question": "傷", "answers": [ "きず" ], "comment": "wound; injury; cut; gash; bruise; scratch; scrape; scar\nchip; crack; scratch; nick\nflaw; defect; weakness; weak point\nstain (on one's reputation); disgrace; dishonor; dishonour\n(emotional) hurt; hurt feelings" },
	{ "question": "傾向", "answers": [ "けいこう" ], "comment": "tendency; trend; inclination" },
	{ "question": "働き", "answers": [ "はたらき" ], "comment": "work; labor; labour\nachievement; performance; ability; talent\nsalary; income; earnings\naction; activity; workings; function; operation; movement; motion\nconjugation; inflection" },
	{ "question": "優れる", "answers": [ "すぐれる" ], "comment": "to surpass; to outstrip; to excel" },
	{ "question": "優勝", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "overall victory; championship" },
	{ "question": "優秀", "answers": [ "ゆうしゅう" ], "comment": "superiority; excellence" },
	{ "question": "元", "answers": [ "もと" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\n(somebody's) side; (somebody's) location\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip\nunknown (e.g. in an equation)\nelement (of a set)\nyuan (monetary unit of China)\nYuan dynasty (China)\nformer; ex-; past; one-time\nyuan (monetary unit of China)" },
	{ "question": "先ず", "answers": [ "まず" ], "comment": "first (of all); to start with; about; almost; anyway; well; now\nhardly (with neg. verb)" },
	{ "question": "先日", "answers": [ "せんじつ" ], "comment": "the other day; a few days ago" },
	{ "question": "光景", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "scene; spectacle; sight; view" },
	{ "question": "克服", "answers": [ "こくふく" ], "comment": "conquest (of a difficulty, illness, handicap, etc.); overcoming; bringing under control; subjugation; victory over" },
	{ "question": "免許", "answers": [ "めんきょ" ], "comment": "license; permit; licence; certificate" },
	{ "question": "党", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "party (political)\nfaction; -ite\ngathering; place where people gather\npolice station; camp; barracks" },
	{ "question": "入場", "answers": [ "にゅうじょう" ], "comment": "entrance; admission; entering" },
	{ "question": "全く", "answers": [ "まったく" ], "comment": "really; truly; entirely; completely; wholly; perfectly\nindeed\ngood grief (expression of exasperation)" },
	{ "question": "全て", "answers": [ "すべて" ], "comment": "everything; all; the whole\nentirely; completely; wholly; all" },
	{ "question": "全体", "answers": [ "ぜんたい" ], "comment": "whole; entirety; whatever (is the matter)" },
	{ "question": "全員", "answers": [ "ぜんいん" ], "comment": "all members (unanimity); all hands; the whole crew; everyone; everybody" },
	{ "question": "全国", "answers": [ "ぜんこく" ], "comment": "countrywide; nationwide; whole country; national" },
	{ "question": "全然", "answers": [ "ぜんぜん" ], "comment": "not at all (with neg. verb)\nwholly; entirely; completely" },
	{ "question": "公平", "answers": [ "こうへい" ], "comment": "chopped burdock root (and sometimes carrot) cooked in sugar and soy sauce\nfairness; impartial; justice" },
	{ "question": "共に", "answers": [ "ともに" ], "comment": "together; jointly\nat the same time; with; as ...; including; along with\nboth" },
	{ "question": "共同", "answers": [ "きょうどう" ], "comment": "doing together (as equals); sharing; common (land, etc.); joint (statement, etc.); cooperation; co-operation; collaboration; association" },
	{ "question": "共通", "answers": [ "きょうつう" ], "comment": "commonness; community\nto be common; to be shared\n-wide" },
	{ "question": "具体", "answers": [ "ぐたい" ], "comment": "concrete; tangible; material" },
	{ "question": "典型", "answers": [ "てんけい" ], "comment": "type; pattern; model; epitome; exemplar; archetypal; representative" },
	{ "question": "内容", "answers": [ "ないよう" ], "comment": "subject; contents; matter; substance; detail; import" },
	{ "question": "再び", "answers": [ "ふたたび" ], "comment": "again; once more; a second time" },
	{ "question": "冒険", "answers": [ "ぼうけん" ], "comment": "risk; venture; adventure" },
	{ "question": "冗談", "answers": [ "じょうだん" ], "comment": "jest; joke; funny story" },
	{ "question": "冷蔵庫", "answers": [ "れいぞうこ" ], "comment": "refrigerator" },
	{ "question": "冷静", "answers": [ "れいせい" ], "comment": "calm; composure; coolness; serenity" },
	{ "question": "凍る", "answers": [ "こおる" ], "comment": "to freeze; to be frozen over; to congeal" },
	{ "question": "処理", "answers": [ "しょり" ], "comment": "processing; dealing with; treatment; disposition; disposal" },
	{ "question": "出会い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "meeting; rendezvous; encounter\nconfluence" },
	{ "question": "出会う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "to meet (by chance); to come across; to run across; to encounter; to happen upon\nto meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)\nto emerge and engage (an enemy)" },
	{ "question": "出席", "answers": [ "しゅっせき" ], "comment": "attendance; presence; appearance\nto attend; to be present; to appear" },
	{ "question": "出来るだけ", "answers": [ "できるだけ" ], "comment": "as much as one can; as much as possible; if at all possible" },
	{ "question": "出来事", "answers": [ "できごと" ], "comment": "incident; affair; happening; event" },
	{ "question": "出版", "answers": [ "しゅっぱん" ], "comment": "publication" },
	{ "question": "出発", "answers": [ "しゅっぱつ" ], "comment": "departure" },
	{ "question": "出身", "answers": [ "しゅっしん" ], "comment": "person's origin (e.g. city, country, parentage, school)" },
	{ "question": "刀", "answers": [ "かたな", "とう" ], "comment": "(single-edged) sword; katana\ndagger; knife\nscalpel" },
	{ "question": "分", "answers": [ "ぶん", "ぶ" ], "comment": "minute\nfun (one tenth of a monme, 5.787 grains)\none-tenth; one percent (one-tenth of a wari); 3 mm (one-tenth of a sun); 2.4 mm (one-tenth of a mon, a traditional unit used to measure shoe sizes); 0.1 degree (one-tenth of a do, used to measure body temperature on any temperature scale)\none-quarter of a ryou (obsolete unit of currency)\nthickness\nadvantageous circumstances\none-tenth of a monme of silver\npart; segment; share; ration\nrate\ndegree; one's lot; one's status; relation; duty; kind; lot\nin proportion to; just as much as" },
	{ "question": "分ける", "answers": [ "わける" ], "comment": "to divide (into); to split (into); to part; to separate; to divide up; to classify; to sort out; to divide out\nto share; to distribute; to deal out; to dish out\nto distinguish; to discriminate; to differentiate (between)\nto break up (a fight); to mediate\nto call a draw; to tie\nto push one's way through (a crowd)\nto sell" },
	{ "question": "分析", "answers": [ "ぶんせき" ], "comment": "analysis" },
	{ "question": "分野", "answers": [ "ぶんや" ], "comment": "field; sphere; realm; division; branch" },
	{ "question": "切れ", "answers": [ "きれ" ], "comment": "piece; slice; strip; scrap\ncloth\nsharpness\ncounter for scraps, pieces, etc.\ncompletely using up ...; running out of ...; exhausting ..." },
	{ "question": "切れる", "answers": [ "きれる" ], "comment": "to break; to snap; to be cut; to split; to crack\nto be injured\nto wear out; to be worn out\nto break; to burst; to collapse\nto wear off; to stop working; to go dead\nto expire (time limit, etc.); to run out; to become due\nto run out (of stock, etc.); to be exhausted; to be used up; to be sold out; to be out of\nto be broken off (e.g. of a relationship); to break up; to have severed ties; to be cut off; to be disconnected\nto cut well; to be sharp\nto be sharp-minded; to be keen; to be shrewd; to be quick-witted; to be able\nto be short of; to drop under (a certain figure); to beat (e.g. a record time)\nto dry off\nto curve; to veer\nto shuffle (cards)\nto get angry; to snap; to blow one's top; to lose one's temper; to flip\nto be able to do completely" },
	{ "question": "刈る", "answers": [ "かる" ], "comment": "to cut (hair); to mow (grass); to harvest; to clip; to shear; to reap; to trim; to prune" },
	{ "question": "刑事", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "(police) detective\ncriminal matter" },
	{ "question": "列", "answers": [ "れつ" ], "comment": "queue; line; row; column; sequence; string; train" },
	{ "question": "列車", "answers": [ "れっしゃ" ], "comment": "train (ordinary)" },
	{ "question": "判断", "answers": [ "はんだん" ], "comment": "judgment; judgement; decision; conclusion; adjudication\ndivination\njudgement" },
	{ "question": "別に", "answers": [ "べつに" ], "comment": "(not) particularly; (not) especially; (not) specially\nseparately; apart; additionally; extra" },
	{ "question": "別れ", "answers": [ "わかれ" ], "comment": "parting; separation; farewell; (lateral) branch; fork; offshoot; division; section" },
	{ "question": "利口", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "clever; intelligent; wise; bright; sharp; sensible; smart; shrewd\nwell-behaved (of kids, animals, etc); obedient; good\ngood (with words)" },
	{ "question": "利益", "answers": [ "りえき" ], "comment": "profit; gains\nbenefit; advantage; interest (of the public, etc.)\ngrace (of God, Buddha, etc.) (esp. as attained through rightful actions, prayer, adherence to one's faith, etc.); blessing; miracle" },
	{ "question": "到着", "answers": [ "とうちゃく" ], "comment": "arrival" },
	{ "question": "制度", "answers": [ "せいど" ], "comment": "system; institution; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "制限", "answers": [ "せいげん" ], "comment": "restriction; restraint; limitation; limit" },
	{ "question": "券", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "ticket; coupon; bond; certificate" },
	{ "question": "刺激", "answers": [ "しげき" ], "comment": "stimulus; impetus; incentive; encouragement; motivation; provocation; excitement; thrill" },
	{ "question": "前者", "answers": [ "ぜんしゃ" ], "comment": "the former" },
	{ "question": "前進", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "advance; drive; progress" },
	{ "question": "割る", "answers": [ "わる" ], "comment": "to divide\nto cut; to halve; to separate; to split; to rip\nto break; to crack; to smash\nto dilute\nto fall below\nto discount\nto step over (a line, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "劇", "answers": [ "げき" ], "comment": "drama; play\npowerful drug" },
	{ "question": "劇場", "answers": [ "げきじょう" ], "comment": "theatre; theater; playhouse" },
	{ "question": "加える", "answers": [ "くわえる" ], "comment": "to add; to add up; to sum up; to append; to annex\nto increase; to gather (e.g. speed); to pick up\nto include; to count in; to let join\nto inflict (damage); to deal; to give" },
	{ "question": "加わる", "answers": [ "くわわる" ], "comment": "to be added to; to be appended\nto join in (e.g. a group of friends); to participate\nto increase (e.g. heat); to gain in (e.g. influence); to grow; to gather (speed)\nto be applied (e.g. heat, pressure); to be exerted" },
	{ "question": "加減", "answers": [ "かげん" ], "comment": "degree; extent; just right amount of\ncondition; state of health\nadjustment; moderation\naddition and subtraction" },
	{ "question": "劣る", "answers": [ "おとる" ], "comment": "to be inferior to; to be less good at; to fall behind" },
	{ "question": "助ける", "answers": [ "たすける" ], "comment": "to save; to rescue\nto help; to assist\nto aid; to contribute (financially)\nto facilitate; to stimulate" },
	{ "question": "助手", "answers": [ "じょしゅ" ], "comment": "helper; helpmeet; assistant; tutor" },
	{ "question": "努力", "answers": [ "どりょく" ], "comment": "great effort; exertion; endeavour; endeavor; effort" },
	{ "question": "労働", "answers": [ "ろうどう" ], "comment": "manual labor; manual labour; toil; work\nLabour Party" },
	{ "question": "効く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to be effective; to show effect\nto do its work; to carry out its function well\nto be possible to use" },
	{ "question": "効果", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "effect; effectiveness; efficacy; result\neffects (e.g. sound effects, visual effects, special effects)" },
	{ "question": "勇気", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; valour; valor; nerve; boldness" },
	{ "question": "動かす", "answers": [ "うごかす" ], "comment": "to move; to shift; to stir; to budge; to change position\nto inspire; to rouse; to move (e.g. feeling); to influence\nto change; to alter; to deny\nto operate; to set in motion; to get going\nto mobilize (e.g. troops); to mobilise; to deploy\nto manage (e.g. funds)" },
	{ "question": "動詞", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "verb" },
	{ "question": "勘", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "perception; intuition; the sixth sense" },
	{ "question": "勘定", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "calculation; computation; counting; reckoning; count\nbill; check; account; payment (of a bill); settlement (of an account)\nconsideration; allowance" },
	{ "question": "務め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "service; duty; business; responsibility; task\nBuddhist religious services" },
	{ "question": "勝ち", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "win; victory\napt to do; liable to do; tend to do (used to describe a negative tendency)" },
	{ "question": "勢い", "answers": [ "いきおい" ], "comment": "force; vigor; vigour; energy; spirit; life\ninfluence; authority; power; might\nimpetus; momentum; course (of events)\nnaturally; necessarily" },
	{ "question": "勤め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "service; duty; business; responsibility; task\nBuddhist religious services" },
	{ "question": "勤める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "勧める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to recommend; to advise; to encourage; to offer (wine)" },
	{ "question": "匂い", "answers": [ "におい" ], "comment": "odour; odor; scent; smell; stench\naura; whiff; smacks of ...; sense; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "包み", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "bundle; package; parcel\ncounter for wrapped objects" },
	{ "question": "化学", "answers": [ "かがく" ], "comment": "chemistry\nchemical company (e.g. Acme Chemical Co.)" },
	{ "question": "化粧", "answers": [ "けしょう" ], "comment": "make-up; makeup; cosmetics" },
	{ "question": "区別", "answers": [ "くべつ" ], "comment": "distinction; differentiation; classification" },
	{ "question": "医師", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "doctor; physician\ndoctor" },
	{ "question": "医療", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "medical care; medical treatment" },
	{ "question": "十", "answers": [ "じゅう", "とお" ], "comment": "ten\nten" },
	{ "question": "半ば", "answers": [ "なかば" ], "comment": "middle; half; semi; halfway; partly" },
	{ "question": "協力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "cooperation; collaboration" },
	{ "question": "単なる", "answers": [ "たんなる" ], "comment": "mere; simple; sheer" },
	{ "question": "単に", "answers": [ "たんに" ], "comment": "simply; merely; only; solely" },
	{ "question": "単位", "answers": [ "たんい" ], "comment": "unit; denomination\ncredit (in school)" },
	{ "question": "単純", "answers": [ "たんじゅん" ], "comment": "simplicity; simple; uncomplicated" },
	{ "question": "単語", "answers": [ "たんご" ], "comment": "word; vocabulary; (usually) single-character word" },
	{ "question": "博士", "answers": [ "はかせ", "はくし" ], "comment": "doctorate; PhD; Dr (as a title)\nexpert; learned person" },
	{ "question": "博物館", "answers": [ "はくぶつかん" ], "comment": "museum" },
	{ "question": "占める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to occupy; to hold\nto account for; to make up; to take up" },
	{ "question": "印", "answers": [ "しるし", "いん" ], "comment": "seal; stamp; mark; print\nmudra (symbolic hand gesture)\nIndia\nmark; sign\nsymbol; emblem\nbadge; crest; flag\nevidence; proof\ntoken (of gratitude, affection, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "印刷", "answers": [ "いんさつ" ], "comment": "printing" },
	{ "question": "印象", "answers": [ "いんしょう" ], "comment": "impression" },
	{ "question": "危ない", "answers": [ "あぶない" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow\nlook out!; watch out!" },
	{ "question": "卵", "answers": [ "たまご" ], "comment": "eggs; egg; spawn; roe\nhen egg\n(an expert) in the making\nbeginning; origin; infancy\negg; eggshell\novum; ovule; egg cell" },
	{ "question": "厄介", "answers": [ "やっかい" ], "comment": "trouble; burden; nuisance; bother; worry\ncare; dependence; support; kindness; obligation; staying (with a person)" },
	{ "question": "厚い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "thick; deep; heavy\nkind; cordial; hospitable; warm; faithful\nabundant" },
	{ "question": "原", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "original; primitive; primary; fundamental; raw\nfield; plain; prairie; tundra; moor; wilderness\nsuffixed to words indicating a class of people to create a plural (esp. in impolite contexts)" },
	{ "question": "去る", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "to leave; to go away\nto pass; to elapse\nto be distant\nto send away; to drive off; to divorce\n... completely\nlast ... (e.g. \"last April\")" },
	{ "question": "参加", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "participation" },
	{ "question": "参考", "answers": [ "さんこう" ], "comment": "reference; consultation" },
	{ "question": "又", "answers": [ "また" ], "comment": "again; and; also; still (doing something)" },
	{ "question": "及ぼす", "answers": [ "およぼす" ], "comment": "to exert; to cause; to exercise" },
	{ "question": "友", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "friend; companion; comrade; pal" },
	{ "question": "友人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "friend" },
	{ "question": "友情", "answers": [ "ゆうじょう" ], "comment": "friendship; fellowship; camaraderie" },
	{ "question": "双子", "answers": [ "ふたご" ], "comment": "twins; twin" },
	{ "question": "反抗", "answers": [ "はんこう" ], "comment": "opposition; resistance; insubordination; defiance; hostility; rebellion" },
	{ "question": "収める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "収入", "answers": [ "しゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "income; receipts; revenue" },
	{ "question": "収穫", "answers": [ "しゅうかく" ], "comment": "harvest; crop; ingathering\nfruits (of one's labors); results" },
	{ "question": "取り上げる", "answers": [ "とりあげる" ], "comment": "to pick up; to take up\nto adopt; to feature; to accept; to listen to\nto take away; to confiscate; to deprive; to disqualify\nto deliver (a child)" },
	{ "question": "取れる", "answers": [ "とれる" ], "comment": "to come off; to be removed\n(of pain, a fever, etc.) to disappear\nto be caught; to be harvested\nto be interpreted (as); to be taken as\n(of balance, etc.) to be attained\nto be obtainable" },
	{ "question": "受け取る", "answers": [ "うけとる" ], "comment": "to receive; to get; to accept\nto take; to interpret; to understand" },
	{ "question": "句", "answers": [ "く" ], "comment": "section (i.e. of text); sentence; passage; paragraph\nphrase\nverse (of 5 or 7 mora in Japanese poetry; of 4, 5, or 7 characters in Chinese poetry)\nhaiku; first 17 morae of a renga, etc.\nmaxim; saying; idiom; expression" },
	{ "question": "叫ぶ", "answers": [ "さけぶ" ], "comment": "to shout; to cry; to scream; to shriek; to yell; to exclaim\nto clamor (for or against); to clamour (for or against)" },
	{ "question": "可", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "passable; acceptable; tolerable; fair" },
	{ "question": "可能", "answers": [ "かのう" ], "comment": "potential; possible; practicable; feasible" },
	{ "question": "台", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "stand; rack; table; bench; podium; pedestal; platform; stage\nsupport; holder; rack\ncounter for machines, incl. vehicles\nsetting (e.g. in jewellery)\nlevel (e.g. price level); range (e.g. after physical units); period (of time, e.g. a decade of one's life)\nelevated area\nviewing platform\ndish tray\nmeal\ntall building; tower\ntower\nstand; pedestal\ncalyx\nTaiwan" },
	{ "question": "叱る", "answers": [ "しかる" ], "comment": "to scold; to chide; to rebuke; to reprimand" },
	{ "question": "合わせる", "answers": [ "あわせる" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "合図", "answers": [ "あいず" ], "comment": "sign; signal" },
	{ "question": "合格", "answers": [ "ごうかく" ], "comment": "success; passing (e.g. exam); eligibility" },
	{ "question": "合計", "answers": [ "ごうけい" ], "comment": "sum total; total amount" },
	{ "question": "同一", "answers": [ "どういつ" ], "comment": "identical; same; one and the same; equal\nfair; equal treatment; without discrimination" },
	{ "question": "同僚", "answers": [ "どうりょう" ], "comment": "coworker; co-worker; colleague; associate" },
	{ "question": "同時", "answers": [ "どうじ" ], "comment": "simultaneous; concurrent; same time; synchronous; together" },
	{ "question": "同様", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "identical; equal to; same (kind); like; similarity" },
	{ "question": "名", "answers": [ "な" ], "comment": "name; given name\ntitle\nfame; renown; reputation\npretext; pretense; justification; appearance\ncounter for people (usu. seating, reservations and such)\nfirst name\nfamous; great\nname\nnoun" },
	{ "question": "名人", "answers": [ "めいじん" ], "comment": "master; expert" },
	{ "question": "吐く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to breathe out; to breathe\nto tell (a lie); to use (foul language)\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto emit; to send forth; to breathe out\nto give (an opinion); to make (a comment); to express; to tell\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "向かい", "answers": [ "むかい" ], "comment": "facing; opposite; across the street; other side" },
	{ "question": "向く", "answers": [ "むく" ], "comment": "to face\nto turn toward\nto be suited to; to be fit for" },
	{ "question": "向ける", "answers": [ "むける" ], "comment": "to turn towards; to point" },
	{ "question": "否", "answers": [ "いや", "いな" ], "comment": "no; the noes\nno; nay\nwell; er; why\nyou're welcome; not at all; don't mention it" },
	{ "question": "否定", "answers": [ "ひてい" ], "comment": "negation; denial; repudiation; disavowal\nNOT operation" },
	{ "question": "含む", "answers": [ "ふくむ" ], "comment": "to contain; to comprise; to have; to hold; to include; to embrace\nto hold in the mouth\nto bear in mind; to understand; to harbor (grudge, etc.); to harbour\nto express (emotion, etc.); to imply" },
	{ "question": "吸収", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "absorption; suction; attraction" },
	{ "question": "周囲", "answers": [ "しゅうい" ], "comment": "surroundings; environs\ncircumference" },
	{ "question": "味方", "answers": [ "みかた" ], "comment": "friend; ally; supporter" },
	{ "question": "呼吸", "answers": [ "こきゅう" ], "comment": "breathing; respiration\nknack; trick; secret (of doing something)\nharmony; balance; synchronization; accord\nshort interval; short pause" },
	{ "question": "命", "answers": [ "いのち" ], "comment": "life; life force\nlifetime; lifespan\nmost important thing; foundation; core\npaired tattoos of the \"life\" kanji on the upper arms of a man and woman (indicating unwavering love)\nfate; destiny; karma\ncommand; decree\nlife\ndestiny\nLord; Highness\nyou\nthe spoken words of the emperor or a noble" },
	{ "question": "命じる", "answers": [ "めいじる" ], "comment": "to order; to command; to appoint" },
	{ "question": "命令", "answers": [ "めいれい" ], "comment": "order; command; decree; directive\n(software) instruction; statement" },
	{ "question": "哀れ", "answers": [ "あわれ" ], "comment": "pity; sorrow; grief; misery; compassion; pathos\npitiable; pitiful; pathetic; miserable\nalack; alas" },
	{ "question": "品", "answers": [ "しな" ], "comment": "article; item; thing; goods; stock\nquality\nflirtatiousness; coquetry\ncourt rank\nlevel; grade\nchapter; section; volume\nelegance; grace; refinement; class; dignity\narticle; item\ncounter for items (of food, etc.); counter for dishes or courses (at a restaurant)" },
	{ "question": "哲学", "answers": [ "てつがく" ], "comment": "philosophy" },
	{ "question": "唯", "answers": [ "ただ" ], "comment": "ordinary; common; usual\nfree of charge\nunaffected; as is; safe\nonly; merely; just; simply\nbut; however; nevertheless" },
	{ "question": "唯一", "answers": [ "ゆいいつ" ], "comment": "only; sole; unique" },
	{ "question": "商人", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "trader; shopkeeper; merchant" },
	{ "question": "商品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "commodity; article of commerce; goods; stock; merchandise" },
	{ "question": "商売", "answers": [ "しょうばい" ], "comment": "trade; business; commerce; transaction; occupation" },
	{ "question": "問い", "answers": [ "とい" ], "comment": "question; query" },
	{ "question": "善", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "good; goodness; right; virtue" },
	{ "question": "喜び", "answers": [ "よろこび" ], "comment": "joy; delight; rapture; pleasure; gratification; rejoicing; congratulations; felicitations" },
	{ "question": "喫茶店", "answers": [ "きっさてん" ], "comment": "coffee shop; tearoom; coffee lounge; coffeehouse; cafe" },
	{ "question": "営業", "answers": [ "えいぎょう" ], "comment": "business; trade; sales; operations" },
	{ "question": "器用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "skilful; skillfull; adroit; dexterous; dextrous; deft; nimble; handy\nclever; shrewd; ingenious" },
	{ "question": "回", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "counter for occurrences\na time; an instance\ninning (baseball); round; game\nepisode; chapter; instalment\nHui (people)\nIslam" },
	{ "question": "回す", "answers": [ "まわす" ], "comment": "to turn; to rotate; to gyrate\nto circulate; to send around\nto surround\nto put something to a new use (e.g. leftovers)\n... around (e.g. to chase someone around)\nto dial (e.g. telephone number)\nto invest\nto gang-rape" },
	{ "question": "回り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "rotation\nmaking the rounds\nspreading\neffect; efficacy\nby way of; via\nround; turn\nsize\n12-year period; 12-year age difference" },
	{ "question": "回復", "answers": [ "かいふく" ], "comment": "restoration; rehabilitation; recovery; return; replevin; improvement\nrecovery (from an illness); recuperation; convalescence" },
	{ "question": "団体", "answers": [ "だんたい" ], "comment": "organization; organisation; association" },
	{ "question": "困難", "answers": [ "こんなん" ], "comment": "difficulty; hardship; trouble; distress" },
	{ "question": "囲む", "answers": [ "かこむ" ], "comment": "to surround; to encircle; to enclose; to fence; to wall in\nto besiege; to lay siege to\nto play (go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "図", "answers": [ "ず" ], "comment": "drawing; picture; diagram; figure; illustration; chart; graph\nsight; scene" },
	{ "question": "図書", "answers": [ "としょ" ], "comment": "books" },
	{ "question": "国会", "answers": [ "こっかい" ], "comment": "National Diet; legislative assembly of Japan (1947-)\nImperial Diet; legislative assembly of Japan (1889-1947)\nlegislative assembly; parliament; congress" },
	{ "question": "国境", "answers": [ "こっきょう" ], "comment": "national border; provincial border" },
	{ "question": "国家", "answers": [ "こっか" ], "comment": "state; country; nation" },
	{ "question": "国民", "answers": [ "こくみん" ], "comment": "nation; nationality; people; citizen" },
	{ "question": "国語", "answers": [ "こくご" ], "comment": "national language\nJapanese language (often as a school subject in Japan)\nnative Japanese words (as opposed to loanwords)" },
	{ "question": "土地", "answers": [ "とち" ], "comment": "plot of land; lot; soil\nlocality; region; place" },
	{ "question": "土産", "answers": [ "みやげ" ], "comment": "present; souvenir\nproduct of the land\npresent; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "地", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "earth; ground; land; soil\nplace\nterritory\nbottom (of a package, book, etc.)\nearth (one of the five elements)\nearth; soil; dirt; clay; mud\nthe earth (historically, esp. as opposed to the heavens); the ground; the land\nlow-quality torinoko-gami (containing mud)\n(period of) refraining from construction in the direction of the god of the earth (in Onmyōdō)\nground; land; earth; soil\nthe region in question; the local area\nskin\ntexture; fabric; material; weave\nbase; background\none's true nature\nnarrative (i.e. descriptive part of a story)\nreal life; actuality\n(in the game of go) captured territory\nnoh chorus\n(in Japanese dance) accompaniment music\n(in Japanese music) basic phrase (usu. repetitive)\nbase part (of multiple shamisens)" },
	{ "question": "地下", "answers": [ "ちか" ], "comment": "basement; cellar; underground place\nunderground; below ground\nsecret; under cover\nunderground (railway); subway; metro" },
	{ "question": "地位", "answers": [ "ちい" ], "comment": "(social) position; status" },
	{ "question": "地区", "answers": [ "ちく" ], "comment": "district; section; sector" },
	{ "question": "地域", "answers": [ "ちいき" ], "comment": "area; region" },
	{ "question": "地平線", "answers": [ "ちへいせん" ], "comment": "horizon (related to land)" },
	{ "question": "地方", "answers": [ "ちほう" ], "comment": "district; region; area; locality\nthe country; countryside; the provinces; rural area\nperson in charge of music (in a Japanese dance performance)\nperson singing ballads (in noh)\ncoast (esp. as seen from the water); shore\nthe country; countryside; the provinces; rural area" },
	{ "question": "地球", "answers": [ "ちきゅう" ], "comment": "the earth; the globe" },
	{ "question": "型", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "model; type (e.g. of machine, goods, etc.)\ntype; style; pattern\nmold (mould); template; model\nkata (standard form of a movement, posture, etc. in martial arts, sport, etc.)\nform (i.e. customary procedure)\nsize (i.e. clothing, shoes)\n(taxonomical) form" },
	{ "question": "城", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "castle\ncastle (in place names)\nfortress (surrounded by a wall, moat, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "基", "answers": [ "もと", "もとい" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip\ngroup\n(free) radical\ncounter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)\nbasis; foundation\ncause" },
	{ "question": "基づく", "answers": [ "もとづく" ], "comment": "to be grounded on; to be based on; to be due to; to originate from" },
	{ "question": "基本", "answers": [ "きほん" ], "comment": "foundation; basis; standard" },
	{ "question": "堀", "answers": [ "ほり" ], "comment": "moat; fosse\ncanal; ditch" },
	{ "question": "報告", "answers": [ "ほうこく" ], "comment": "report; information" },
	{ "question": "場", "answers": [ "ば" ], "comment": "place; spot; space\nfield; discipline; sphere; realm\noccasion; situation\nscene (of a play, movie, etc.)\nsession (of the stock market)\narea in which cards are laid out (in a card game)\nround (i.e. east, south, etc.)\nfield\nfield (gestalt psychology)\nplace; spot; grounds; arena; stadium; range; course" },
	{ "question": "場面", "answers": [ "ばめん" ], "comment": "scene; setting (e.g. of novel)" },
	{ "question": "塀", "answers": [ "へい" ], "comment": "wall\nfence" },
	{ "question": "塔", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "tower; steeple; spire\nstupa; pagoda; dagoba" },
	{ "question": "塩", "answers": [ "しお" ], "comment": "salt (i.e. sodium chloride); common salt; table salt\nsalt (e.g. sodium chloride, calcium sulfate, etc.)\nhardship; toil; trouble\nsaltiness" },
	{ "question": "境", "answers": [ "さかい" ], "comment": "border; boundary\nturning point; watershed\narea; region; spot; space; environment\npsychological state; mental state\ncognitive object; something perceptible by the sense organs or mind" },
	{ "question": "墓", "answers": [ "はか" ], "comment": "gravesite; tomb" },
	{ "question": "増す", "answers": [ "ます" ], "comment": "to increase; to grow" },
	{ "question": "増加", "answers": [ "ぞうか" ], "comment": "increase; rise; growth; addition; increment" },
	{ "question": "売れる", "answers": [ "うれる" ], "comment": "to sell (well)\nto be well known; to be popular; to be famous" },
	{ "question": "変化", "answers": [ "へんか" ], "comment": "change; variation; alteration; mutation; transition; transformation; transfiguration; metamorphosis\nvariety; diversity\ninflection; declension; conjugation\nsidestepping\nshapeshifting (of an animal or spirit); goblin; ghost; apparition; bugbear\nincarnation\ntransformation" },
	{ "question": "変更", "answers": [ "へんこう" ], "comment": "change; modification; alteration; revision; amendment" },
	{ "question": "夕べ", "answers": [ "ゆうべ" ], "comment": "evening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "外す", "answers": [ "はずす" ], "comment": "to unfasten; to undo\nto remove; to take off; to deinstall\nto leave; to step out; to slip away\nto miss (a target)" },
	{ "question": "外交", "answers": [ "がいこう" ], "comment": "diplomacy\nselling (e.g. door-to-door); canvassing" },
	{ "question": "外出", "answers": [ "がいしゅつ" ], "comment": "going out; outing; leaving (one's home, office, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "多分", "answers": [ "たぶん" ], "comment": "perhaps; probably\ngenerous; many; much; great" },
	{ "question": "多少", "answers": [ "たしょう" ], "comment": "more or less; somewhat; a little; a few; some\namount; quantity" },
	{ "question": "夜", "answers": [ "よ", "よる" ], "comment": "evening; night\ncounter for nights" },
	{ "question": "夜中", "answers": [ "よなか" ], "comment": "middle of the night; dead of night\nduring the night; at night\nall night; the whole night" },
	{ "question": "夜明け", "answers": [ "よあけ" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak" },
	{ "question": "夢中", "answers": [ "むちゅう" ], "comment": "daze; (in a) trance; ecstasy; delirium; engrossment; within a (deep) dream" },
	{ "question": "大いに", "answers": [ "おおいに" ], "comment": "very; much; greatly; a lot of" },
	{ "question": "大した", "answers": [ "たいした" ], "comment": "considerable; great; important; significant; a big deal" },
	{ "question": "大会", "answers": [ "たいかい" ], "comment": "convention; tournament; mass meeting; rally" },
	{ "question": "大使", "answers": [ "たいし" ], "comment": "ambassador" },
	{ "question": "大半", "answers": [ "たいはん" ], "comment": "majority; more than half; most (of)\nmostly; largely; mainly; predominately; nearly" },
	{ "question": "大変", "answers": [ "たいへん" ], "comment": "very; greatly\nimmense; enormous; great\nserious; grave; dreadful; terrible\ndifficult; hard\nmajor incident; disaster" },
	{ "question": "大家", "answers": [ "おおや" ], "comment": "landlord; landlady\nmaster; expert; authority; leading figure\nmansion; large house\nrich family; distinguished family\nrich family; distinguished family" },
	{ "question": "大戦", "answers": [ "たいせん" ], "comment": "great war; great battle" },
	{ "question": "大抵", "answers": [ "たいてい" ], "comment": "mostly; ordinarily; usually; generally\nprobably\nmost; almost all\nordinary\nproper; appropriate; moderate" },
	{ "question": "大気", "answers": [ "たいき" ], "comment": "atmosphere" },
	{ "question": "大統領", "answers": [ "だいとうりょう" ], "comment": "president; chief executive" },
	{ "question": "大臣", "answers": [ "だいじん" ], "comment": "cabinet minister\nminister (of government); noble\nnobleman's residence" },
	{ "question": "大部分", "answers": [ "だいぶぶん" ], "comment": "most part; greater part; majority" },
	{ "question": "大陸", "answers": [ "たいりく" ], "comment": "continent\ncontinental Asia (esp. mainland China)\ncontinental Europe" },
	{ "question": "天候", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "weather" },
	{ "question": "天然", "answers": [ "てんねん" ], "comment": "nature; spontaneity\nnatural airhead" },
	{ "question": "太陽", "answers": [ "たいよう" ], "comment": "sun; solar" },
	{ "question": "夫人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "wife; Mrs; madam\nwife of a nobleman (aristocrat, etc.)\nconsort of the emperor" },
	{ "question": "夫婦", "answers": [ "ふうふ" ], "comment": "married couple; spouses; husband and wife; couple; pair\nhis and hers; pair of objects, one larger (for man), one smaller (for woman)" },
	{ "question": "失う", "answers": [ "うしなう" ], "comment": "to lose; to part with" },
	{ "question": "失望", "answers": [ "しつぼう" ], "comment": "disappointment; despair" },
	{ "question": "失業", "answers": [ "しつぎょう" ], "comment": "unemployment" },
	{ "question": "奇妙", "answers": [ "きみょう" ], "comment": "strange; queer; curious" },
	{ "question": "契約", "answers": [ "けいやく" ], "comment": "contract; compact; agreement" },
	{ "question": "奥", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "inner part; inside; interior; depths (e.g. of a forest); back (of a house, drawer, etc.); bottom (e.g. of one's heart); recesses; heart" },
	{ "question": "奨学金", "answers": [ "しょうがくきん" ], "comment": "scholarship; stipend; bursary\nstudent loan" },
	{ "question": "奪う", "answers": [ "うばう" ], "comment": "to snatch away; to dispossess; to steal" },
	{ "question": "女優", "answers": [ "じょゆう" ], "comment": "actress" },
	{ "question": "女子", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "woman; girl\nvagina\ngirl" },
	{ "question": "女王", "answers": [ "じょおう" ], "comment": "queen" },
	{ "question": "好み", "answers": [ "このみ" ], "comment": "liking; taste; choice\nfriendship; friendly relations; connection; relation; intimacy\nbeing fond of; having a liking for\nto the liking of; favored by; popular with" },
	{ "question": "好む", "answers": [ "このむ" ], "comment": "to like; to prefer" },
	{ "question": "妙", "answers": [ "みょう" ], "comment": "strange; weird; odd; curious\nwonder; mystery; miracle; excellence\ncleverness; adroitness; knack; skill" },
	{ "question": "姉妹", "answers": [ "しまい" ], "comment": "sisters" },
	{ "question": "始まり", "answers": [ "はじまり" ], "comment": "origin; beginning" },
	{ "question": "委員", "answers": [ "いいん" ], "comment": "committee member" },
	{ "question": "姿", "answers": [ "すがた" ], "comment": "figure; form; shape\nappearance; dress; guise\nstate; condition; picture; image\nform (of a waka)\ndressed in ...; wearing ..." },
	{ "question": "婚約", "answers": [ "こんやく" ], "comment": "engagement; betrothal" },
	{ "question": "婦人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "woman; lady; adult female" },
	{ "question": "嫁", "answers": [ "よめ" ], "comment": "wife; bride\n(one's) daughter-in-law" },
	{ "question": "嫌う", "answers": [ "きらう" ], "comment": "to hate; to dislike; to loathe" },
	{ "question": "存在", "answers": [ "そんざい" ], "comment": "existence; being" },
	{ "question": "学", "answers": [ "がく" ], "comment": "-ology; -ics; study of ...\nlearning; scholarship; erudition; knowledge" },
	{ "question": "学ぶ", "answers": [ "まなぶ" ], "comment": "to study (in depth); to learn; to take lessons in" },
	{ "question": "学問", "answers": [ "がくもん" ], "comment": "scholarship; study; learning\ndiscipline; branch of learning; (a) science" },
	{ "question": "学期", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "school term; semester" },
	{ "question": "学習", "answers": [ "がくしゅう" ], "comment": "study; learning; tutorial" },
	{ "question": "学者", "answers": [ "がくしゃ" ], "comment": "scholar" },
	{ "question": "孫", "answers": [ "まご" ], "comment": "grandchild" },
	{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "universe; cosmos; space" },
	{ "question": "守る", "answers": [ "まもる" ], "comment": "to protect; to guard; to defend\nto keep (i.e. a promise); to abide (by the rules); to observe; to obey; to follow" },
	{ "question": "安定", "answers": [ "あんてい" ], "comment": "stability; steadiness; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "完了", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "completion; conclusion\nperfect (tense, form, aspect)\nend; completion" },
	{ "question": "完全", "answers": [ "かんぜん" ], "comment": "perfection; completeness" },
	{ "question": "完成", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "complete; completion\nperfection; accomplishment" },
	{ "question": "宗教", "answers": [ "しゅうきょう" ], "comment": "religion; religious affiliation; belief; faith; creed\nreligious activity" },
	{ "question": "定期", "answers": [ "ていき" ], "comment": "fixed period; fixed term\nregular; periodic; periodical\nfixed-term commutation pass\nfixed-term deposit\nfutures contracts" },
	{ "question": "宜しい", "answers": [ "よろしい" ], "comment": "good; OK; all right; fine; very well; will do; may; can" },
	{ "question": "宝", "answers": [ "たから" ], "comment": "treasure" },
	{ "question": "宝石", "answers": [ "ほうせき" ], "comment": "gem; jewel; precious stone" },
	{ "question": "実", "answers": [ "み", "じつ" ], "comment": "truth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; fidelity\ncontent; substance\n(good) result\nfruit; nut\nseed\n(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.\ncontent; substance\ntruth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; integrity; fidelity\nthat's right (used when recalling forgotten information, suddenly changing the subject, etc.)\npit (of a fruit); stone\ncore\ntongue (piece of wood used to connect two boards)\nclitoris\nthe real person; said person\nreal thing; genuine article" },
	{ "question": "実に", "answers": [ "じつに" ], "comment": "indeed; really; absolutely; truly; actually; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "実は", "answers": [ "じつは" ], "comment": "as a matter of fact; by the way; to tell you the truth; to be honest; frankly" },
	{ "question": "実施", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "enforcement; implementation; putting into practice; carrying out; operation; working (e.g. working parameters); enactment" },
	{ "question": "実現", "answers": [ "じつげん" ], "comment": "implementation (e.g. of a system); materialization; materialisation; realization; realisation" },
	{ "question": "実行", "answers": [ "じっこう" ], "comment": "practice; practising; performance; execution (e.g. program) (programme); realization; realisation; implementation" },
	{ "question": "実際", "answers": [ "じっさい" ], "comment": "practicality; practical\nreality; actuality; actual conditions\nbhutakoti (limit of reality)" },
	{ "question": "実験", "answers": [ "じっけん" ], "comment": "experiment" },
	{ "question": "害", "answers": [ "がい" ], "comment": "injury; harm; evil influence; damage" },
	{ "question": "家事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "housework; domestic chores\nfamily affairs; household matters" },
	{ "question": "家具", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "furniture" },
	{ "question": "家賃", "answers": [ "やちん" ], "comment": "rent" },
	{ "question": "容易", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "easy; simple; plain" },
	{ "question": "宿", "answers": [ "やど" ], "comment": "outcasts common around the Kyoto region from the Kamakura period to the Edo period\nlodging; inn; hotel\nhouse; home; dwelling\nhome of a servant's parents (or guarantor, etc.)\nlodging\nrelay station; post town\nconstellation; mansion (in Chinese astronomy)" },
	{ "question": "宿泊", "answers": [ "しゅくはく" ], "comment": "lodging" },
	{ "question": "寄付", "answers": [ "きふ" ], "comment": "contribution; donation" },
	{ "question": "密な", "answers": [ "みつな" ] },
	{ "question": "審判", "answers": [ "しんぱん" ], "comment": "refereeing; trial; judgement; judgment; umpire; referee" },
	{ "question": "対", "answers": [ "たい", "つい" ], "comment": "opposite; opposition\nversus; vs.; v.\nto (e.g. \"winning a game five to three\")\nequal footing; equal terms\nagainst ...; anti-; toward ...; to ...\npair; couple; set\nantithesis\ncounter for items that come in pairs\ncounter for sets (of clothes, small furniture, utensils, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "対する", "answers": [ "たいする" ], "comment": "to face (each other); to be facing\nto be directed toward (the future, etc.); to be in response to; to be related to\nto receive (a client, etc.)\nto compare with; to contrast with; to be in opposition with; to be opposed to\nto confront; to oppose; to compete with" },
	{ "question": "対象", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "target; object (of worship, study, etc.); subject (of taxation, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "専攻", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "major subject; special study" },
	{ "question": "尊敬", "answers": [ "そんけい" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; reverence; honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "尊重", "answers": [ "そんちょう" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; regard" },
	{ "question": "小", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "smallness; small item\nshort month (i.e. having fewer than 31 days)\nelementary school\nyounger or inferior (of two items or people with the same name)\nunit of field area (approx. 400 sq m)\nsmall; little; slight\nslightly less than; just about\nsomewhat; somehow\nminor (sometimes derogatory); petty\nsmall; narrow\nfamiliar prefix\nslightly; a bit\nsmall; little\nsmall; little; dear (figurative sense)\nnarrow; thin" },
	{ "question": "小包", "answers": [ "こづつみ" ], "comment": "parcel; package" },
	{ "question": "小屋", "answers": [ "こや" ], "comment": "hut; cabin; shed; (animal) pen\nsmall theatre (theater); temporary playhouse; circus tent; booth\none's own house" },
	{ "question": "小麦", "answers": [ "こむぎ" ], "comment": "wheat" },
	{ "question": "少々", "answers": [ "しょうしょう" ], "comment": "just a minute; small quantity" },
	{ "question": "少しも", "answers": [ "すこしも" ], "comment": "anything of; not one bit (with negative sentence)" },
	{ "question": "少女", "answers": [ "しょうじょ" ], "comment": "little girl; maiden; young lady; female usually between 7 and 18 years old\nfemale between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period)" },
	{ "question": "少年", "answers": [ "しょうねん" ], "comment": "boy; juvenile; young boy; youth; lad" },
	{ "question": "就く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to ascend (the throne); to accede\nto take (seat, position, course, etc.); to assume\nto start (on a journey); to commence; to depart\nto study (under teacher); to be an apprentice" },
	{ "question": "就職", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "finding employment; getting a job" },
	{ "question": "尻", "answers": [ "しり" ], "comment": "ass; arse; buttocks\nrear; end\nbuttocks; behind; rump; bottom\nundersurface; bottom\nlast place; end\nconsequence" },
	{ "question": "局", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "bureau; department\noffice (e.g. post, telephone); broadcasting station (e.g. television, radio); channel; exchange\naffair; situation\ngame (of go, shogi, etc.)\ncourt lady; lady-in-waiting (Heian period)\nseparate room in a palace (esp. for a lady) (Heian period)\nroom for a very low class prostitute\nvery low class prostitute" },
	{ "question": "居眠り", "answers": [ "いねむり" ], "comment": "nodding off (while sitting); dozing" },
	{ "question": "居間", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "living room (Western style)" },
	{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at\nto be attentive; to pay attention\nto be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)" },
	{ "question": "屋根", "answers": [ "やね" ], "comment": "roof" },
	{ "question": "履く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to put on (or wear) lower-body clothing (i.e. pants, skirt, etc.); to put on (or wear) footwear\nto affix a sword to one's hip\nto affix a bowstring to a bow" },
	{ "question": "岩", "answers": [ "いわ" ], "comment": "rock; boulder\ncrag; cliff\nanchor" },
	{ "question": "岸", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "bank; coast; shore" },
	{ "question": "嵐", "answers": [ "あらし" ], "comment": "storm; tempest\ndifficulty; trouble" },
	{ "question": "州", "answers": [ "しゅう", "す" ], "comment": "state; province; county; oblast; department (of ancient China)\ncontinent\ndear\nsandbank; sandbar" },
	{ "question": "巣", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "nest; rookery; breeding place; hive\nden\nhaunt\n(spider's) web" },
	{ "question": "左右", "answers": [ "さゆう" ], "comment": "left and right\ninfluence; control; domination\n(doing) various things; (doing) this and that\nbeing apt to; being prone to; tending to become\nsomehow or other; anyhow; anyway" },
	{ "question": "巨大", "answers": [ "きょだい" ], "comment": "huge; gigantic; enormous" },
	{ "question": "差", "answers": [ "さ" ], "comment": "difference; variation\ndifference\nbetween (e.g. two people); face to face\nhindrance; impediment\narrhythmic section of recitative in noh music\nprefix used for stress or emphasis\ncounter for traditional dance songs" },
	{ "question": "差別", "answers": [ "さべつ" ], "comment": "discrimination; distinction; differentiation" },
	{ "question": "市場", "answers": [ "いちば", "しじょう" ], "comment": "(town) market\n(the) marketplace\n(the) market (as a concept)" },
	{ "question": "布", "answers": [ "ぬの" ], "comment": "cloth\nbujian (spade-shaped bronze coin of ancient China)\nunit of measurement for cloth breadth (30-38 cm)" },
	{ "question": "希望", "answers": [ "きぼう" ], "comment": "hope; wish; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "帯", "answers": [ "おび" ], "comment": "obi; kimono sash\npaper wrapper on books, CDs, etc.\nband (e.g. conduction, valence); belt (e.g. Van-Allen, asteroid, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "帰宅", "answers": [ "きたく" ], "comment": "returning home" },
	{ "question": "常に", "answers": [ "つねに" ], "comment": "always; constantly" },
	{ "question": "常識", "answers": [ "じょうしき" ], "comment": "common sense; good sense; common knowledge; general knowledge; common practice; accepted practice; social etiquette" },
	{ "question": "帽子", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "hat; cap" },
	{ "question": "幅", "answers": [ "はば" ], "comment": "width; breadth\nfreedom (e.g. of thought); latitude\ngap; difference (e.g. in price); range (e.g. of voice)\nunit of measurement for cloth breadth (30-38 cm)\nscroll\ncounter for scrolls" },
	{ "question": "幕", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "curtain; bunting\nact (in play)" },
	{ "question": "平ら", "answers": [ "たいら" ], "comment": "flatness; level; smooth; calm; plain; sitting tailor fashion" },
	{ "question": "平和", "answers": [ "へいわ" ], "comment": "peace; harmony\nconcealed winning hand consisting of chows, a pair that isn't a value pair, and an open wait" },
	{ "question": "平均", "answers": [ "へいきん" ], "comment": "average; mean\nbalance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "平等", "answers": [ "びょうどう" ], "comment": "equality; impartiality; evenness" },
	{ "question": "年中", "answers": [ "ねんじゅう" ], "comment": "whole year; all year round; throughout the year\nalways; all the time\nmiddle class (of a nursery school, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "年代", "answers": [ "ねんだい" ], "comment": "age; era; period; date" },
	{ "question": "年寄", "answers": [ "としより" ], "comment": "old people; the aged\ntrustee of the Japan Sumo Association; retired high-ranking wrestler who is licensed to coach and receives retirement pay\nsenior statesman (of the Tokugawa shogunate)\nimportant local official (under the Tokugawa Shogunate)" },
	{ "question": "年月", "answers": [ "ねんげつ" ], "comment": "months and years" },
	{ "question": "年間", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "years (period of)" },
	{ "question": "年齢", "answers": [ "ねんれい" ], "comment": "age; years" },
	{ "question": "幸い", "answers": [ "さいわい" ], "comment": "happiness; blessedness; luck; fortune; felicity\nluckily; fortunately" },
	{ "question": "幸せ", "answers": [ "しあわせ" ], "comment": "happiness; good fortune; luck; blessing" },
	{ "question": "幸福", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "happiness; blessedness; joy; well-being" },
	{ "question": "幸運", "answers": [ "こううん" ], "comment": "good luck; fortune" },
	{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない" ], "comment": "very young\nchildish; immature" },
	{ "question": "幾つ", "answers": [ "いくつ" ], "comment": "how many?\nhow old?" },
	{ "question": "幾ら", "answers": [ "いくら" ], "comment": "how much?; how many?\neven; even if" },
	{ "question": "広がる", "answers": [ "ひろがる" ], "comment": "to spread (out); to extend; to stretch; to reach to; to get around; to fill (e.g. a space)" },
	{ "question": "広告", "answers": [ "こうこく" ], "comment": "advertisement" },
	{ "question": "床", "answers": [ "ゆか", "とこ" ], "comment": "bed; bedding\nsickbed\nalcove\nriverbed\nseedbed\nstraw \"core\" of a tatami mat\nfloor\nfloor\nstage (for the narrator and the shamisen player)\ndining platform built across a river\ncounter for beds" },
	{ "question": "底", "answers": [ "そこ" ], "comment": "bottom; sole\nbase (logarithmic, exponential, number system); radix\nbase (triangle, cone, cylinder, etc.)\ntype; kind; extent; degree" },
	{ "question": "度", "answers": [ "たび", "ど" ], "comment": "time (three times, each time, etc.); times\ndegree (angle, temperature, scale, etc.)\ncounter for occurrences and times\nstrength (of alcohol)" },
	{ "question": "座席", "answers": [ "ざせき" ], "comment": "seat" },
	{ "question": "延期", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "postponement; adjournment" },
	{ "question": "建築", "answers": [ "けんちく" ], "comment": "construction; architecture (of buildings)" },
	{ "question": "建設", "answers": [ "けんせつ" ], "comment": "construction; establishment" },
	{ "question": "弁当", "answers": [ "べんとう" ], "comment": "bento; Japanese box lunch" },
	{ "question": "式", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "equation; formula; expression\nceremony\nstyle\nenforcement regulations (of the ritsuryo)" },
	{ "question": "引っ張る", "answers": [ "ひっぱる" ], "comment": "to pull; to draw; to pull tight\nto string (lines); to run (cable); to stretch\nto pull towards oneself (e.g. someone's sleeve)\nto drag; to haul; to tow\nto lead (e.g. one's followers)\nto take someone somewhere (e.g. a suspect to the police)\nto tempt into joining; to strongly invite to join\nto delay; to prolong\nto lengthen the pronunciation (of a word)\nto quote; to cite; to reference\nto pull the ball\nto wear; to put on" },
	{ "question": "引用", "answers": [ "いんよう" ], "comment": "quotation; citation; reference" },
	{ "question": "引退", "answers": [ "いんたい" ], "comment": "retire" },
	{ "question": "張る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "to stick; to paste; to affix\nto stretch; to spread; to strain; to tighten; to put up (tent)\nto form (e.g. ice on a pond)\nto fill; to swell\nto stick out; to put; to slap\nto be expensive\nto keep a watch on; to be on the lookout\nto become one tile away from completion\nto span; to generate\nto be prominently ...; to be persistently ..." },
	{ "question": "強力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "powerful; strong\nherculean strength; mountain carrier-guide" },
	{ "question": "強盗", "answers": [ "ごうとう" ], "comment": "robber; mugger\nrobbery; burglary" },
	{ "question": "強調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "emphasis; highlight; stress; stressed point" },
	{ "question": "当たる", "answers": [ "あたる" ], "comment": "to be hit; to strike\nto touch; to be in contact; to be affixed\nto be equivalent to; to be applicable; to apply to\nto be right on the money (of a prediction, criticism, etc.)\nto be selected (in a lottery, etc.); to win\nto be successful; to go well; to be a hit\nto face; to confront\nto lie (in the direction of)\nto undertake; to be assigned\nto be stricken (by food poisoning, heat, etc.); to be afflicted\nto be called upon (by the teacher)\nto treat (esp. harshly); to lash out at\nto be unnecessary\nto be hitting well; to be on a hitting streak\n(in fishing) to feel a bite\n(of fruit, etc.) to be bruised; to spoil\nto feel (something) out; to probe into; to check (i.e. by comparison)\nto shave\nto be a relative of a person; to stand in a relationship" },
	{ "question": "当てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "to hit\nto expose\nto apply (e.g. patch); to put on; to put against; to hold on; to hold against\nto allot; to call on someone (e.g. in class)\nto guess (an answer)\nto make a hit (e.g. in a lottery)" },
	{ "question": "当時", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "at that time; in those days" },
	{ "question": "影", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "shadow; silhouette; figure; shape\nreflection; image\nominous sign\nlight (stars, moon)\ntrace; shadow (of one's former self)" },
	{ "question": "影響", "answers": [ "えいきょう" ], "comment": "influence; effect\nto influence; to affect; to have an influence on; to impact; to have an effect on" },
	{ "question": "役", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "war; campaign; battle\nunpaid work (ritsuryo system); forced labor\nuse; service; role\npost; position\nscoring combination (e.g. in mahjong, card games, etc.); hand" },
	{ "question": "役割", "answers": [ "やくわり" ], "comment": "part; assigning (allotment of) parts; role; duties" },
	{ "question": "彼等", "answers": [ "かれら" ], "comment": "they (usually male); them\nthose (indicating something distant from both speaker and listener, or something understood without naming it directly)\nthey (of people) (used to refer to one's equals or inferiors)" },
	{ "question": "後者", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "the latter" },
	{ "question": "徐々に", "answers": [ "じょじょに" ] },
	{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany" },
	{ "question": "従兄弟", "answers": [ "いとこ" ], "comment": "cousin (male)" },
	{ "question": "得る", "answers": [ "える", "うる" ], "comment": "to be able to ...; can ...\nto get; to acquire; to obtain; to procure; to earn; to win; to gain; to secure; to attain\nto get; to earn; to acquire; to procure; to gain; to secure; to attain; to obtain; to win\nto understand; to comprehend\nto receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment); to get (ill)\nto be able to ..., can ..." },
	{ "question": "得意", "answers": [ "とくい" ], "comment": "triumph; prosperity\npride\none's strong point; one's forte; one's specialty\nfrequent customer (client, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "御", "answers": [ "お", "ご" ], "comment": "honorific/polite/humble prefix\nhonorific suffix\nhonorific affix\nhonorific prefix\naugust\nbeautiful\naugust (in ref. to the emperor or the gods); imperial; divine\nhonorific/polite/humble prefix" },
	{ "question": "微妙", "answers": [ "びみょう" ], "comment": "delicate; subtle; sensitive\ndifficult; delicate (situation); complicated\ndoubtful; questionable; dicey; tricky\nunspeakably wonderful; sublime; exquisite; marvelous" },
	{ "question": "微笑む", "answers": [ "ほほえむ" ], "comment": "to smile" },
	{ "question": "徹夜", "answers": [ "てつや" ], "comment": "all night; all-night vigil; sleepless night" },
	{ "question": "徹底", "answers": [ "てってい" ], "comment": "thoroughness; completeness; consistency\nthorough enforcement; seeing to it that a policy, etc. is carried out without exception" },
	{ "question": "心理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "state of mind; mentality; psychology" },
	{ "question": "心臓", "answers": [ "しんぞう" ], "comment": "heart\nguts; nerve; cheek; gall; spine\ncentral part" },
	{ "question": "心配", "answers": [ "しんぱい" ], "comment": "worry; concern; anxiety\ncare; help; aid; assistance" },
	{ "question": "必ずしも", "answers": [ "かならずしも" ], "comment": "not always; not necessarily; not all; not entirely" },
	{ "question": "必死", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "frantic; desperate\ninevitable death\nbrinkmate (inevitable checkmate)" },
	{ "question": "応じる", "answers": [ "おうじる" ], "comment": "to respond; to satisfy; to accept; to comply with; to apply for" },
	{ "question": "快適", "answers": [ "かいてき" ], "comment": "pleasant; agreeable; comfortable" },
	{ "question": "思い出", "answers": [ "おもいで" ], "comment": "memories; recollections; reminiscence" },
	{ "question": "思わず", "answers": [ "おもわず" ], "comment": "unintentionally; reflexively; spontaneously; involuntarily; instinctively" },
	{ "question": "思想", "answers": [ "しそう" ], "comment": "thought; idea; ideology" },
	{ "question": "怠ける", "answers": [ "なまける" ], "comment": "to be idle; to slacken\nto neglect (e.g. one's work)" },
	{ "question": "急に", "answers": [ "きゅうに" ], "comment": "swiftly; rapidly\nsuddenly; abruptly; immediately" },
	{ "question": "急激", "answers": [ "きゅうげき" ], "comment": "sudden; precipitous; radical" },
	{ "question": "急速", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "rapid (e.g. progress)" },
	{ "question": "性", "answers": [ "せい", "さが" ], "comment": "one's nature; one's destiny\ncustom; tradition; habit\nnature (of a person)\nsex\ngender\n-ty; -ity; -ness; -cy\nnature (of a person or thing)\nthat which does not change according to external influences" },
	{ "question": "性格", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "character; personality; disposition; nature" },
	{ "question": "怪我", "answers": [ "けが" ], "comment": "injury (to animate object); hurt" },
	{ "question": "恋", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "(romantic) love" },
	{ "question": "恋人", "answers": [ "こいびと" ], "comment": "lover; sweetheart" },
	{ "question": "恐れる", "answers": [ "おそれる" ], "comment": "to fear; to be afraid of" },
	{ "question": "恐ろしい", "answers": [ "おそろしい" ], "comment": "terrible; dreadful; terrifying; frightening; frightened\nsurprising; startling; tremendous; amazing" },
	{ "question": "恐怖", "answers": [ "きょうふ" ], "comment": "fear; dread; dismay; terror; horror; scare; panic" },
	{ "question": "恩", "answers": [ "おん" ], "comment": "favour; favor; obligation; debt of gratitude" },
	{ "question": "息", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "breath; breathing\ntone; mood\nson\npenis" },
	{ "question": "患者", "answers": [ "かんじゃ" ], "comment": "(a) patient" },
	{ "question": "悩む", "answers": [ "なやむ" ], "comment": "to be worried; to be troubled" },
	{ "question": "悪口", "answers": [ "わるくち", "わるぐち", "あっこう" ], "comment": "abuse; insult; slander; evil speaking; bad mouth" },
	{ "question": "悪魔", "answers": [ "あくま" ], "comment": "devil; demon; fiend\nSatan; the Devil\nMāra; evil spirits or forces that hinder one's path to enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "悲しむ", "answers": [ "かなしむ" ], "comment": "to be sad; to mourn for; to regret" },
	{ "question": "悲劇", "answers": [ "ひげき" ], "comment": "tragedy; tragic drama; tragic play\ntragedy; calamity; disaster" },
	{ "question": "情報", "answers": [ "じょうほう" ], "comment": "information; news; intelligence; advices\ninformation; data contained in characters, signals, code, etc." },
	{ "question": "想像", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "imagination; guess" },
	{ "question": "愉快", "answers": [ "ゆかい" ], "comment": "pleasant; happy" },
	{ "question": "意外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "unexpected; surprising" },
	{ "question": "意志", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "will; volition; intention; intent; determination" },
	{ "question": "意思", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "intention; purpose" },
	{ "question": "意識", "answers": [ "いしき" ], "comment": "consciousness\nawareness; sense\nmano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information)" },
	{ "question": "愛", "answers": [ "あい" ], "comment": "love; affection; care\nattachment; craving; desire\nbeloved; dear" },
	{ "question": "愛する", "answers": [ "あいする" ], "comment": "to love" },
	{ "question": "愛情", "answers": [ "あいじょう" ], "comment": "love; affection" },
	{ "question": "感じ", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "feeling; sense; impression" },
	{ "question": "感じる", "answers": [ "かんじる" ], "comment": "to feel; to sense; to experience" },
	{ "question": "感動", "answers": [ "かんどう" ], "comment": "being deeply moved emotionally; excitement; passion; inspiration; deep emotion; strong impression" },
	{ "question": "感心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "admiration; being impressed\nadmirable; praiseworthy\nastonishment; being appalled" },
	{ "question": "感情", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "emotion; feeling; feelings; sentiment" },
	{ "question": "感覚", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "sense; sensation; feeling; intuition" },
	{ "question": "感謝", "answers": [ "かんしゃ" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude" },
	{ "question": "態度", "answers": [ "たいど" ], "comment": "attitude; manner; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "慎重", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "careful; cautious; prudent; discreet; deliberate" },
	{ "question": "憲法", "answers": [ "けんぽう" ], "comment": "constitution" },
	{ "question": "成る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "to become; to get; to grow; to be; to reach; to attain\nto result in; to prove to be\nto consist of; to be composed of\nto succeed; to be complete\nto change into; to be exchanged for\nto play a role\nto be promoted\nto do ..." },
	{ "question": "成人", "answers": [ "せいじん" ], "comment": "adult\nto grow up; to mature\nto come of age" },
	{ "question": "成功", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "success; hit" },
	{ "question": "成績", "answers": [ "せいせき" ], "comment": "results; record; grades; marks" },
	{ "question": "成長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "growth; grow to adulthood" },
	{ "question": "我々", "answers": [ "われわれ" ], "comment": "we" },
	{ "question": "我慢", "answers": [ "がまん" ], "comment": "patience; endurance; perseverance; tolerance; self-control; self-denial" },
	{ "question": "戦い", "answers": [ "たたかい" ], "comment": "battle; fight; struggle; conflict" },
	{ "question": "戦う", "answers": [ "たたかう" ], "comment": "to make war (on); to wage war (against); to go to war (with); to fight (with); to do battle (against)\nto compete (against)\nto struggle (against adversities, etc.); to fight; to contend; to resist" },
	{ "question": "戻す", "answers": [ "もどす" ], "comment": "to put back; to return; to give back; to restore (to a previous state, e.g. defrosting, reconstituting, reconciling); to turn back (e.g. clock hand)\nto vomit; to throw up\nto recover (of a market price)" },
	{ "question": "手伝い", "answers": [ "てつだい" ], "comment": "helper; assistant\nhelp" },
	{ "question": "手品", "answers": [ "てじな" ], "comment": "magic (illusion); conjuring; magic trick; conjuring trick; sleight of hand" },
	{ "question": "手段", "answers": [ "しゅだん" ], "comment": "means; way; measure" },
	{ "question": "手術", "answers": [ "しゅじゅつ" ], "comment": "(surgical) operation; procedure" },
	{ "question": "手間", "answers": [ "てま" ], "comment": "time; labour; labor" },
	{ "question": "才能", "answers": [ "さいのう" ], "comment": "talent; ability" },
	{ "question": "扱う", "answers": [ "あつかう" ], "comment": "to deal with (a person); to treat; to handle; to take care of; to entertain\nto deal with (a problem); to handle; to manage\nto operate (e.g. a machine); to handle; to work\nto deal in; to sell\nto cover (a topic); to treat; to discuss; to take up\nto treat A as B\nto mediate (an argument)\nto be too much for one; to find unmanageable\nto gossip" },
	{ "question": "批判", "answers": [ "ひはん" ], "comment": "criticism; judgement; judgment; comment" },
	{ "question": "批評", "answers": [ "ひひょう" ], "comment": "criticism; review; commentary" },
	{ "question": "承知", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "knowledge; awareness\nconsent; acceptance; assent; admitting; compliance; agreement; acknowledgment; acknowledgement\nforgiving; pardoning; excusing" },
	{ "question": "承認", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "recognition; acknowledgement; acknowledgment; approval; consent; agreement" },
	{ "question": "技師", "answers": [ "ぎし" ], "comment": "engineer; technician" },
	{ "question": "投票", "answers": [ "とうひょう" ], "comment": "voting; poll" },
	{ "question": "抜く", "answers": [ "ぬく" ], "comment": "to extract; to omit; to draw out; to unplug\nto do something to the end\nto surpass; to overtake\nto masturbate (of a male); to ejaculate (while masturbating)\nto take (a photo); to record (video)" },
	{ "question": "抜ける", "answers": [ "ぬける" ], "comment": "to come out; to fall out; to be omitted; to be missing; to escape; to come loose\nto fade; to discolour\nto wear a hole (e.g. clothes)\nto leave (e.g. a meeting)\nto be clear; to be transparent (e.g. of the sky)\nto be stupid; to be absentminded; to be careless; to be inattentive\nto exit (a program loop)\nto go through; to pass through" },
	{ "question": "抱える", "answers": [ "かかえる" ], "comment": "to hold or carry under or in the arms\nto have (esp. problems, debts, etc.)\nto employ; to engage; to hire" },
	{ "question": "抱く", "answers": [ "だく", "いだく" ], "comment": "to embrace; to hold in the arms (e.g. a baby); to hug\nto harbour (e.g. grudge); to harbor; to bear; to have (e.g. ambition); to entertain (e.g. hope, suspicion)\nto have sex with; to make love to; to sleep with\nto sit on eggs" },
	{ "question": "抵抗", "answers": [ "ていこう" ], "comment": "resistance; opposition; standing up to\nreluctance; repulsion; repugnance\nresistance; drag; friction\nelectrical resistance\nresistor" },
	{ "question": "担当", "answers": [ "たんとう" ], "comment": "being in charge (of an area of responsibility); being responsible (for a work role, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "拍手", "answers": [ "はくしゅ" ], "comment": "clapping hands; applause\nclapping one's hands in prayer (at a shrine)" },
	{ "question": "招く", "answers": [ "まねく" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask\nto beckon; to wave someone in; to gesture to\nto call in; to send for; to summon\nto bring on oneself; to cause; to incur; to lead to; to result in" },
	{ "question": "招待", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "拡大", "answers": [ "かくだい" ], "comment": "magnification; enlargement; expansion; amplification" },
	{ "question": "持ち上げる", "answers": [ "もちあげる" ], "comment": "to elevate; to raise; to lift up\nto flatter; to extol; to praise to the sky" },
	{ "question": "指す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to point\nto nominate; to select someone; to specify some person\nto identify; to indicate; to point out\nto play (a game of shogi); to move (a piece)\nto extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance)" },
	{ "question": "指導", "answers": [ "しどう" ], "comment": "leadership; guidance; coaching\nshido (disciplinary action for a minor infringement of the rules of judo)" },
	{ "question": "振る", "answers": [ "ふる" ], "comment": "to wave; to shake; to swing\nto sprinkle; to throw (dice)\nto cast (actor); to allocate (work)\nto turn down (somebody); to reject; to jilt; to dump\nto abandon; to give up; to ruin\nto add kana indicating a reading of a word\nto slightly change headings; to change directions\nto extract by broiling; to prepare an infusion of; to decoct\nto carry with great vigor (e.g. a portable shrine)\nto bring up a topic; to lead to a topic\nto replace; to substitute\nto set up a joke for somebody else\nassuming the air of ...; behaving like ...\nto put on airs; to be self-important" },
	{ "question": "捕まる", "answers": [ "つかまる" ], "comment": "to be caught; to be arrested\nto hold on to; to grasp\nto find (e.g. proof); to get (e.g. a taxi)\nto be detained by" },
	{ "question": "掃除", "answers": [ "そうじ" ], "comment": "cleaning; sweeping; dusting; scrubbing" },
	{ "question": "掛かる", "answers": [ "かかる" ], "comment": "to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)\nto hang\nto come into view; to arrive\nto come under (a contract, a tax)\nto start (engines, motors)\nto attend; to deal with; to handle\nto have started to; to be on the verge of\nto overlap (e.g. information in a manual); to cover\nto (come) at\nto be fastened\nto be covered (e.g. with dust, a table-cloth, etc.)\nto be caught in\nto get a call\nto depend on" },
	{ "question": "掲示", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "notice; bulletin; post; posting; placard" },
	{ "question": "描く", "answers": [ "かく", "えがく" ], "comment": "to draw; to paint; to sketch\nto depict; to describe\nto picture in one's mind; to imagine\nto form a certain shape (e.g. path of an action, appearance of an object, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "提出", "answers": [ "ていしゅつ" ], "comment": "to present; to submit (e.g. a report or a thesis); to hand in; to file; to turn in\npresentation; submission; filing" },
	{ "question": "提案", "answers": [ "ていあん" ], "comment": "proposal; proposition; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "換える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "握る", "answers": [ "にぎる" ], "comment": "to clasp; to grasp; to grip; to clutch\nto make (nigirizushi, rice ball, etc.); to form; to press into shape; to mold; to mould\nto seize (power, etc.); to take hold of" },
	{ "question": "握手", "answers": [ "あくしゅ" ], "comment": "handshake" },
	{ "question": "援助", "answers": [ "えんじょ" ], "comment": "assistance; aid; support" },
	{ "question": "損", "answers": [ "そん" ], "comment": "loss; damage; harm; unprofitable\ndisadvantage; handicap; drawback; unfavorable" },
	{ "question": "損害", "answers": [ "そんがい" ], "comment": "damage; injury; loss" },
	{ "question": "撃つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "to shoot (at)\nto attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge" },
	{ "question": "操作", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "operation; management; handling\nmanipulating to one's benefit" },
	{ "question": "支える", "answers": [ "ささえる" ], "comment": "to support; to prop; to sustain; to underlay; to hold up\nto hold at bay; to stem; to check\nto stick; to get stuck; to get caught; to get jammed; to clog\nto be unavailable; to be busy; to be occupied; to be full\nto be piled up (e.g. of work)\nto halt (in one's speech); to stumble (over one's words); to stutter; to stammer\nto feel blocked (of one's chest or throat, due to grief, anxiety, illness, etc.); to feel pressure; to feel pain" },
	{ "question": "支出", "answers": [ "ししゅつ" ], "comment": "expenditure; expenses" },
	{ "question": "支店", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "branch office; branch store" },
	{ "question": "支度", "answers": [ "したく" ], "comment": "preparation; arrangements" },
	{ "question": "支払", "answers": [ "しはらい" ], "comment": "payment" },
	{ "question": "支払う", "answers": [ "しはらう" ], "comment": "to pay" },
	{ "question": "支給", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "provision; supply; payment; allowance; grant" },
	{ "question": "支配", "answers": [ "しはい" ], "comment": "domination; rule; control; direction; guidance" },
	{ "question": "改善", "answers": [ "かいぜん" ], "comment": "betterment; improvement\nkaizen (Japanese business philosophy of continuous improvement)" },
	{ "question": "攻撃", "answers": [ "こうげき" ], "comment": "attack; strike; offensive\ncriticism; censure; denunciation; condemnation" },
	{ "question": "放す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to release; to let go; to free; to set free; to let loose; to turn loose\nto add (pieces of eggplant, potato, etc.) to water, broth, etc." },
	{ "question": "放送", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "broadcast; broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "政府", "answers": [ "せいふ" ], "comment": "government; administration" },
	{ "question": "故郷", "answers": [ "こきょう" ], "comment": "home town; birthplace; native place; one's old home\nruins; historic remains" },
	{ "question": "救う", "answers": [ "すくう" ], "comment": "to rescue from; to help out of; to save" },
	{ "question": "救助", "answers": [ "きゅうじょ" ], "comment": "relief; aid; rescue" },
	{ "question": "教師", "answers": [ "きょうし" ], "comment": "teacher (classroom)" },
	{ "question": "教授", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "professor\nteaching; instruction" },
	{ "question": "教科書", "answers": [ "きょうかしょ" ], "comment": "textbook; coursebook; schoolbook" },
	{ "question": "敬意", "answers": [ "けいい" ], "comment": "respect; honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "数", "answers": [ "かず", "すう" ], "comment": "often; again and again; frequently; repeatedly\nnumber; amount\nseveral; a number of\nquantity; amount\ncounting; figures; numbers\nnumber; numeral; figure\ngrammatical number\ndestiny; fate; course of events; trend" },
	{ "question": "数える", "answers": [ "かぞえる" ], "comment": "to count; to enumerate" },
	{ "question": "数字", "answers": [ "すうじ" ], "comment": "numeral; figure; digit; numeric character" },
	{ "question": "整理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "sorting; arrangement; organization; putting in order; adjustment; regulation\nliquidation; settlement; consolidation; clearance (e.g. debt); paying off\nretrenchment; curtailment; cutting down; disposal" },
	{ "question": "敵", "answers": [ "てき", "かたき" ], "comment": "rival; opponent; adversary; competitor; enemy (esp. one with which there is longstanding enmity); foe\nrevenge\nspouse\nopponent; rival; adversary\nmenace; danger; threat; enemy" },
	{ "question": "文", "answers": [ "ぶん", "ふみ" ], "comment": "letter; writings\nsentence\ncomposition; text; writings\nthe literary arts (as opposed to the military arts); academia; literature\nfigure; design\nstyle (of writing); figure (of speech)\ndesign; plot; plan\nminor market fluctuation; technical correction\ncat's cradle\nlease rod (in a loom)\none-thousandth of a kan (obsolete unit of currency)\n2.4 cm (traditional unit used to measure shoe sizes)\nletter; character; sentence\nscripture; incantation" },
	{ "question": "文句", "answers": [ "もんく" ], "comment": "complaint; grumbling; objection\nphrase; words; expression" },
	{ "question": "文字", "answers": [ "もじ" ], "comment": "letter (of alphabet); character\nliteral" },
	{ "question": "文明", "answers": [ "ぶんめい" ], "comment": "civilization; civilisation; culture\nBummei era (1469.4.28-1487.7.20)" },
	{ "question": "料金", "answers": [ "りょうきん" ], "comment": "fee; charge; fare" },
	{ "question": "断る", "answers": [ "ことわる" ], "comment": "to refuse; to reject; to dismiss; to turn down; to decline\nto inform; to give notice; to tell in advance\nto ask leave; to excuse oneself (from)" },
	{ "question": "新た", "answers": [ "あらた" ], "comment": "new; fresh; novel" },
	{ "question": "新鮮", "answers": [ "しんせん" ], "comment": "fresh" },
	{ "question": "方", "answers": [ "ほう", "かた" ], "comment": "direction; way\nperson; lady; gentleman\nmethod of; manner of; way of\ncare of ..\nperson in charge of ..\nside (e.g. \"on my mother's side\")\ndirection; way; side; area (in a particular direction)\nside (of an argument, etc.); one's part\ntype; category\nfield (of study, etc.)\nindicates one side of a comparison\nway; method; manner; means\nlength (of each side of a square)\nMr.; Mrs.; Miss; Ms.\nmakes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)\nstate; situation; appearance\nhonorific pluralizing suffix (used only for people)\naround (the time that, etc.); about\nsurrounding area\nshore (of the sea)\nsuffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc." },
	{ "question": "方々", "answers": [ "ほうぼう", "かたがた" ], "comment": "they (of people); gentlemen (of the ...)\nyou (usu. plural)\nvarious\nhere and there; this way and that way; everywhere; all over" },
	{ "question": "方向", "answers": [ "ほうこう" ], "comment": "direction; orientation; bearing; way\ncourse (e.g. of action)" },
	{ "question": "方法", "answers": [ "ほうほう" ], "comment": "method; process; manner; way; means; technique" },
	{ "question": "旅", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "travel; trip; journey\n500-man battalion (Zhou-dynasty Chinese army)" },
	{ "question": "旗", "answers": [ "はた" ], "comment": "flag" },
	{ "question": "既に", "answers": [ "すでに" ], "comment": "already; too late" },
	{ "question": "日中", "answers": [ "にっちゅう" ], "comment": "daytime; during the day\nSino-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "日付", "answers": [ "ひづけ" ], "comment": "date; dating" },
	{ "question": "日光", "answers": [ "にっこう" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日常", "answers": [ "にちじょう" ], "comment": "ordinary; regular; everyday; usual" },
	{ "question": "日曜", "answers": [ "にちよう" ], "comment": "Sunday" },
	{ "question": "日本", "answers": [ "にほん", "にっぽん" ], "comment": "Japan" },
	{ "question": "旧", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "ex-; former; old\nused item; secondhand item\nold; used; previous\nformer; ex-; past; one-time" },
	{ "question": "昇る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "明かり", "answers": [ "あかり" ], "comment": "light; illumination; glow; gleam\nlamp; light" },
	{ "question": "明ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "to empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole)" },
	{ "question": "明らか", "answers": [ "あきらか" ], "comment": "obvious; evident; clear; plain" },
	{ "question": "明後日", "answers": [ "あさって", "みょうごにち" ], "comment": "day after tomorrow" },
	{ "question": "明確", "answers": [ "めいかく" ], "comment": "clear; precise; definite; distinct" },
	{ "question": "易しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "easy; plain; simple" },
	{ "question": "是非", "answers": [ "ぜひ" ], "comment": "certainly; without fail\nright and wrong; pros and cons" },
	{ "question": "昼食", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょく" ], "comment": "lunch; midday meal\nfood served at a tea party (tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "時刻", "answers": [ "じこく" ], "comment": "instant; time; moment" },
	{ "question": "時期", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "time; season; period; phase; stage\nsoon; shortly" },
	{ "question": "普段", "answers": [ "ふだん" ], "comment": "usual; habitual; ordinary; everyday; usually; generally; always" },
	{ "question": "景気", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "business conditions; the market; economic activity; economic climate\ngood (economic) times; prosperity; boom\nliveliness; energy; vigour; vigor; spirit" },
	{ "question": "暖かい", "answers": [ "あたたかい" ], "comment": "warm; mild; genial" },
	{ "question": "暗記", "answers": [ "あんき" ], "comment": "memorization; memorisation; learning by heart" },
	{ "question": "暮らし", "answers": [ "くらし" ], "comment": "life; living; livelihood; life circumstances" },
	{ "question": "暮らす", "answers": [ "くらす" ], "comment": "to live; to get along\nto spend (time)" },
	{ "question": "暮れ", "answers": [ "くれ" ], "comment": "sunset; sundown; nightfall; dusk\nend; close\nyear-end; end of the year" },
	{ "question": "曜日", "answers": [ "ようび" ], "comment": "day of the week" },
	{ "question": "更に", "answers": [ "さらに" ], "comment": "furthermore; again; after all; more and more; moreover; even more" },
	{ "question": "書斎", "answers": [ "しょさい" ], "comment": "study; library; den; home office; reading room" },
	{ "question": "書物", "answers": [ "しょもつ" ], "comment": "books" },
	{ "question": "書類", "answers": [ "しょるい" ], "comment": "documents; official papers" },
	{ "question": "替える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "最も", "answers": [ "もっとも" ], "comment": "most; extremely" },
	{ "question": "最中", "answers": [ "さいちゅう" ], "comment": "in the middle of; height of; in course of; midst\nwafer cake filled with bean jam" },
	{ "question": "最低", "answers": [ "さいてい" ], "comment": "least; lowest; minimum\nworst\nawful; horrible; nasty; disgusting\nat the very least" },
	{ "question": "最終", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "last; final; closing" },
	{ "question": "最高", "answers": [ "さいこう" ], "comment": "most; highest; maximum; uppermost; supreme\nbest; wonderful; finest" },
	{ "question": "月曜", "answers": [ "げつよう" ], "comment": "Monday" },
	{ "question": "有る", "answers": [ "ある" ], "comment": "to be (usu. of inanimate objects); to exist; to live\nto have\nto be located\nto be equipped with\nto happen; to come about" },
	{ "question": "有利", "answers": [ "ゆうり" ], "comment": "advantageous; better; profitable; lucrative" },
	{ "question": "有効", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "valid; effective\nyuko (judo)" },
	{ "question": "有能", "answers": [ "ゆうのう" ], "comment": "able; capable; efficient; skill" },
	{ "question": "服装", "answers": [ "ふくそう" ], "comment": "garments; attire" },
	{ "question": "望み", "answers": [ "のぞみ" ], "comment": "wish; desire; hope\nprospect; expectation; (one's) hopes" },
	{ "question": "望む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "to desire\nto wish for; to expect\nto see; to command (a view of)" },
	{ "question": "期待", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; hope" },
	{ "question": "期間", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "period; term; interval" },
	{ "question": "未だ", "answers": [ "いまだ", "まだ" ], "comment": "as yet; hitherto; only; still\nnot yet (with negative verb)\nmore; besides\nunfinished; incomplete; not yet finished with" },
	{ "question": "未来", "answers": [ "みらい" ], "comment": "the future (usually distant)\nfuture tense\nthe world to come" },
	{ "question": "末", "answers": [ "すえ" ], "comment": "top end; tip\nnew shoots; new growth (of a tree)\ntip; top\nend; close (e.g. close of the month)\nyoungest child\ndescendants; offspring; posterity\nfuture\nfinally\ntrivialities\nthe end of\npowder" },
	{ "question": "本人", "answers": [ "ほんにん" ], "comment": "the person himself" },
	{ "question": "本当", "answers": [ "ほんとう" ], "comment": "truth; reality; actuality; fact\nproper; right; correct; official\ngenuine; authentic; natural; veritable" },
	{ "question": "本物", "answers": [ "ほんもの" ], "comment": "genuine article; real thing; real deal" },
	{ "question": "札", "answers": [ "ふだ", "さつ" ], "comment": "note; paper money\nticket; token; check; receipt\nlabel; tag\nsign; card; plate\nplaying card\ncharm; talisman\nslips of paper posted on shrine pillars by pilgrims\narmor platelet" },
	{ "question": "材料", "answers": [ "ざいりょう" ], "comment": "ingredients; material\nmaterial (for a novel, experiment, etc.); subject matter; data\nbasis (for a decision); grounds; evidence\n(market) factor" },
	{ "question": "束", "answers": [ "たば", "つか" ], "comment": "bundle; bunch; sheaf\nstrut; short vertical post\nthickness (of a book minus the cover, a sheaf of paper, etc.)\nhandbreadth; bundle\nlattice\ncounter for large bundles (e.g. 10 sheafs of rice, 200 sheets of calligraphy paper, 20 whistling arrows, 100 fish)\nhandbreadth (unit for measuring the length of arrows)" },
	{ "question": "条件", "answers": [ "じょうけん" ], "comment": "condition; conditions; term; terms; requirement; requirements" },
	{ "question": "来", "answers": [ "らい" ], "comment": "next (year, etc.)\nsince (last month, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "松", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "pine tree (Pinus spp.)\nhighest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "板", "answers": [ "いた" ], "comment": "board; plank\nsheet (of metal); plate (of glass); pane; slab\ncutting board; chopping board\nchef (esp. of high-end Japanese cuisine); cook\nstage (i.e. at a theatre)" },
	{ "question": "柄", "answers": [ "がら" ], "comment": "handle; grip\nstalk (of a mushroom, leaf, etc.)\npattern; design\nbody build; figure; physique\nessential qualities; character; nature\nappropriate to; fitting of; suitable for\nhilt (of a sword); haft (of a dagger); handgrip\ntrunk; stem; stalk\nshaft (of an arrow)\nhandle" },
	{ "question": "栄養", "answers": [ "えいよう" ], "comment": "nutrition; nourishment" },
	{ "question": "株", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "stock; share\nstump\nroot; rootstock\nstrain (of bacteria, etc.)\ntradeable rank; goodwill\none's forte" },
	{ "question": "根", "answers": [ "ね" ], "comment": "root (of a plant)\nroot (of a tooth, hair, etc.); center (of a pimple, etc.)\nroot (of all evil, etc.); source; origin; cause; basis\none's true nature\n(fishing) reef\nstick-to-itiveness; perseverance; persistence\nradical (esp. one that tends to ionize easily)\nroot\nindriya (faculty of the body having a specific function, i.e. the sensory organs)" },
	{ "question": "格好", "answers": [ "かっこう" ], "comment": "shape; form; figure; posture; pose\nappearance\nstate; situation\nsuitable; fit; reasonable\nabout" },
	{ "question": "案", "answers": [ "あん" ], "comment": "idea; plan; thought\ndraft plan; motion; rough copy\nexpectation\ndesk" },
	{ "question": "案内", "answers": [ "あんない" ], "comment": "information; guidance; leading\nto guide; to show (around); to conduct" },
	{ "question": "桜", "answers": [ "さくら" ], "comment": "cherry tree; cherry blossom\ndecoy; fake buyer; shill\nhired applauder\nhorse meat" },
	{ "question": "梅", "answers": [ "うめ" ], "comment": "Japanese apricot (Prunus mume); Chinese plum\nlowest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "梅雨", "answers": [ "つゆ" ], "comment": "rainy season (in Japan from early June to mid-July)\nrain during the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "棒", "answers": [ "ぼう" ], "comment": "pole; rod; stick" },
	{ "question": "椅子", "answers": [ "いす" ], "comment": "chair; stool\npost; office; position\ntraditional square chair with armrests and a torii-shaped back (used by the emperor, etc. during ceremonies)" },
	{ "question": "植物", "answers": [ "しょくぶつ" ], "comment": "plant; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "検査", "answers": [ "けんさ" ], "comment": "inspection (e.g. customs, factory); examination; scan (e.g. MRI, PET, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "検討", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "consideration; examination; investigation; study; scrutiny; discussion; analysis; review" },
	{ "question": "極", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "quite; very\n10^48; quindecillion\npole\nclimax; extreme; extremity; culmination; height; zenith; nadir\nend; limit; extremity" },
	{ "question": "楽", "answers": [ "らく" ], "comment": "comfort; ease\nraku pottery" },
	{ "question": "構う", "answers": [ "かまう" ], "comment": "to mind; to care about; to be concerned about\nto care for; to look after\nto prepare for\nto interfere with; to meddle in\nto tease" },
	{ "question": "構成", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "organization; organisation; configuration; composition" },
	{ "question": "様", "answers": [ "よう", "よう" ], "comment": "mess; sorry state; plight; sad sight\n-ways; -wards\nin the act of ...; just as one is ...\nmanner of ...; way of ...\nMr.; Mrs.; Miss; Ms.\nmakes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)\nstate; situation; appearance\nappearing ...; looking ...\nway to ...; method of ...ing\nform; style; design\nlike; similar to\nthing (thought or spoken)\nMr.; Mrs.; Ms.\nprecedent; example" },
	{ "question": "様々", "answers": [ "さまざま" ], "comment": "varied; various\nour gracious (e.g. Queen); honorific that attaches to name of a person or thing that has bestowed grace or favour upon you" },
	{ "question": "様子", "answers": [ "ようす" ], "comment": "state; state of affairs; situation; circumstances\nappearance; look; aspect\nsign; indication" },
	{ "question": "模様", "answers": [ "もよう" ], "comment": "pattern; figure; design\nstate; condition\nconjecture of the current situation; the way it seems\nmodel; pattern; example\nindicates that that noun seems likely (e.g. rain or storm)\nframework (in go); territorial framework; moyo" },
	{ "question": "権利", "answers": [ "けんり" ], "comment": "right; privilege" },
	{ "question": "横切る", "answers": [ "よこぎる" ], "comment": "to cross (e.g. road); to traverse" },
	{ "question": "横断", "answers": [ "おうだん" ], "comment": "crossing; traversing\ntraversing horizontally; passing west to east (or east to west)\ncutting horizontally" },
	{ "question": "機嫌", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "humour; humor; temper; mood; spirits\nsafety; health; well-being; one's situation\nin a good mood; in high spirits; happy; cheery; merry; chipper" },
	{ "question": "機械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "machine; mechanism\ninstrument; appliance; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "機能", "answers": [ "きのう" ], "comment": "function; facility; faculty; feature" },
	{ "question": "機関", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "mechanism; machinery; contrivance; device\ntrick; dodge\nmechanical doll; string puppet\nengine\nagency; organisation; organization; institution; organ; body\nsystem; facility; facilities" },
	{ "question": "欠ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to be chipped; to be damaged; to be broken\nto be lacking; to be missing\nto be insufficient; to be short; to be deficient; to be negligent toward\n(of the moon) to wane; to go into eclipse" },
	{ "question": "欠席", "answers": [ "けっせき" ], "comment": "absence; non-attendance" },
	{ "question": "欠点", "answers": [ "けってん" ], "comment": "fault; defect; flaw; weak point; weakness; shortcoming; drawback\nfailure (in an examination); failing grade" },
	{ "question": "欠陥", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "defect; fault; deficiency; deformity\nshortage; gap" },
	{ "question": "次々", "answers": [ "つぎつぎ" ], "comment": "in succession; one by one" },
	{ "question": "次第", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "depending on\nas soon as; immediately (upon)\nin accordance with\norder; program; programme; precedence\ncircumstances; course of events; reason" },
	{ "question": "歌手", "answers": [ "かしゅ" ], "comment": "singer" },
	{ "question": "歓迎", "answers": [ "かんげい" ], "comment": "welcome; reception" },
	{ "question": "正", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(logical) true; regular\n10^40; ten thousand undecillion\noriginal\npositive; greater than zero\ngreater (of equal court ranks); upper; senior\ndirector (highest of the four administrative positions of the ritsuryo period); chief\nexactly; precisely\nexact; precise" },
	{ "question": "正午", "answers": [ "しょうご" ], "comment": "noon; mid-day" },
	{ "question": "正式", "answers": [ "せいしき" ], "comment": "due form; official; formality" },
	{ "question": "正直", "answers": [ "しょうじき" ], "comment": "honesty; integrity; frankness\nhonestly; frankly" },
	{ "question": "正確", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "accurate; punctual; exact; authentic; veracious; correct" },
	{ "question": "武器", "answers": [ "ぶき" ], "comment": "weapon; arms; ordnance\nweapon (something used to gain an advantage); asset" },
	{ "question": "歩道", "answers": [ "ほどう" ], "comment": "footpath; walkway; sidewalk" },
	{ "question": "死亡", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "death; mortality\nto die; to pass away" },
	{ "question": "残す", "answers": [ "のこす" ], "comment": "to leave (behind, over); to bequeath; to save; to reserve" },
	{ "question": "残り", "answers": [ "のこり" ], "comment": "remnant; residue; remaining; left-over" },
	{ "question": "段", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "variable measure of fabric (28.8 cm in width); for kimonos: at least 10 m in length; for haori: at least 7.27 m in length; for other clothes: at least 6.06 m in length\n300 tsubo (991.74 meters square, 0.24506 acres)\nsix ken (10.91 m)\nstep; stair; (flight of) steps; (row of) stitches; columns (of print)\ngrade; rank; level\ncounter for breaks in written language (or speech, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "殺す", "answers": [ "ころす" ], "comment": "to kill" },
	{ "question": "母親", "answers": [ "ははおや" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "毒", "answers": [ "どく" ], "comment": "poison; toxicant\nharm; evil influence\nill will; spite; malice\nabusive language" },
	{ "question": "比較", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "comparison" },
	{ "question": "毛布", "answers": [ "もうふ" ], "comment": "blanket" },
	{ "question": "氏", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "family name; lineage; birth\nclan\nMr; Mrs; Ms; Miss\nclan\nhe; him\ncounter for people" },
	{ "question": "気に入る", "answers": [ "きにいる" ], "comment": "to be pleased with; to suit" },
	{ "question": "気の毒", "answers": [ "きのどく" ], "comment": "pitiful; unfortunate; (a) pity" },
	{ "question": "気付く", "answers": [ "きづく" ], "comment": "to notice; to recognize; to recognise; to become aware of; to perceive; to realize; to realise" },
	{ "question": "気候", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "climate" },
	{ "question": "気味", "answers": [ "きみ" ], "comment": "sensation; feeling\ntendency; propensity\n-like; -looking; -looked; tending to ...\nmarket sentiment (stock market); market tone" },
	{ "question": "気温", "answers": [ "きおん" ], "comment": "atmospheric temperature" },
	{ "question": "水準", "answers": [ "すいじゅん" ], "comment": "level; standard\nwater level" },
	{ "question": "氷", "answers": [ "こおり" ], "comment": "ice\nshaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup)\nice\nhail" },
	{ "question": "永久", "answers": [ "えいきゅう" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity; immortality\nEikyuu era (1113.7.13-1118.4.3)" },
	{ "question": "永遠", "answers": [ "えいえん" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity; immortality; permanence" },
	{ "question": "求める", "answers": [ "もとめる" ], "comment": "to want; to wish for\nto request; to demand\nto seek; to search for; to pursue (pleasure); to hunt (a job)\nto purchase; to buy" },
	{ "question": "汗", "answers": [ "あせ" ], "comment": "sweat; perspiration\nmoisture; condensation\nkhan (medieval ruler of a Tatary tribe)" },
	{ "question": "汚染", "answers": [ "おせん" ], "comment": "pollution; contamination" },
	{ "question": "決まり", "answers": [ "きまり" ], "comment": "rule; regulation\nsettlement; conclusion; end; agreement; arrangement\nhabit; custom; habitual way\ncountenance in front of another person; face\nlove relationship between a customer and a prostitute" },
	{ "question": "決定", "answers": [ "けってい" ], "comment": "decision; determination" },
	{ "question": "決心", "answers": [ "けっしん" ], "comment": "determination; resolution" },
	{ "question": "沈む", "answers": [ "しずむ" ], "comment": "to sink; to go under; to submerge\nto go down (e.g. sun); to set; to descend\nto feel depressed" },
	{ "question": "沖", "answers": [ "おき" ], "comment": "open sea" },
	{ "question": "河", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "river; stream\nthe .... river; (suffix used with the names of rivers)\ndiscarded tiles; discards" },
	{ "question": "油", "answers": [ "あぶら" ], "comment": "oil" },
	{ "question": "泉", "answers": [ "いずみ" ], "comment": "spring; fountain" },
	{ "question": "法", "answers": [ "ほう" ], "comment": "law; act; principle\nmethod\nmood\ndharma" },
	{ "question": "泡", "answers": [ "あわ" ], "comment": "bubble; foam; froth; head on beer" },
	{ "question": "波", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "wave\nPoland" },
	{ "question": "泥", "answers": [ "どろ" ], "comment": "mud; slush; (wet) dirt; mire\nthief" },
	{ "question": "注", "answers": [ "ちゅう" ], "comment": "annotation; explanatory note; comment" },
	{ "question": "注ぐ", "answers": [ "そそぐ", "つぐ" ], "comment": "to pour (into); to fill\nto sprinkle on from above; to shed (e.g. tears)\nto concentrate one's spirit (strength, attention) on\nto fall onto (of rain, snow)\nto pour (into a vessel); to fill; to dish out food or drink" },
	{ "question": "注文", "answers": [ "ちゅうもん" ], "comment": "order; request\nannotation; explanatory note" },
	{ "question": "注目", "answers": [ "ちゅうもく" ], "comment": "notice; attention; observation" },
	{ "question": "泳ぎ", "answers": [ "およぎ" ], "comment": "swimming" },
	{ "question": "活動", "answers": [ "かつどう" ], "comment": "action; activity\nmovie (esp. during the silent movie period)" },
	{ "question": "活気", "answers": [ "かっき" ], "comment": "energy; liveliness" },
	{ "question": "活用", "answers": [ "かつよう" ], "comment": "practical use; application\nconjugation; declension; inflection" },
	{ "question": "流す", "answers": [ "ながす" ], "comment": "to drain; to pour; to spill; to shed (blood, tears)\nto wash away\nto distribute (e.g. electricity over wires, music over a PA system, etc.); to circulate; to broadcast; to beam\nto cruise (e.g. taxi)\nto float; to set adrift\nto call off (a meeting, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "流れ", "answers": [ "ながれ" ], "comment": "stream; current; flow\ncourse of events" },
	{ "question": "流れる", "answers": [ "ながれる" ], "comment": "to stream; to flow (liquid, time, etc.); to run (ink)\nto be washed away; to be carried\nto drift; to float (e.g. clouds); to wander; to stray\nto sweep (e.g. rumour, fire); to spread; to circulate\nto be heard (e.g. music); to be played\nto lapse (e.g. into indolence, despair)\nto pass; to elapse; to be transmitted\nto be called off; to be forfeited\nto disappear; to be removed" },
	{ "question": "流行", "answers": [ "りゅうこう" ], "comment": "fashion; fad; vogue; craze\nprevalence (e.g. of a disease)" },
	{ "question": "浴びる", "answers": [ "あびる" ], "comment": "to dash over oneself (e.g. water); to take (e.g. shower); to bask in (e.g. the sun); to bathe in; to be flooded with (e.g. light); to be covered in\nto suffer (e.g. an attack); to draw (e.g. criticism, attention, praise); to have heaped upon; to be showered with" },
	{ "question": "海外", "answers": [ "かいがい" ], "comment": "foreign; abroad; overseas" },
	{ "question": "消費", "answers": [ "しょうひ" ], "comment": "consumption; expenditure" },
	{ "question": "消防", "answers": [ "しょうぼう" ], "comment": "fire fighting\nfire department; fire brigade" },
	{ "question": "涙", "answers": [ "なみだ" ], "comment": "tear; tears; lachrymal secretion\nsympathy" },
	{ "question": "深刻", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "serious; severe; grave; acute" },
	{ "question": "混乱", "answers": [ "こんらん" ], "comment": "disorder; chaos; confusion; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "混雑", "answers": [ "こんざつ" ], "comment": "congestion; crush; crowding; jam\nconfusion; disorder" },
	{ "question": "清潔", "answers": [ "せいけつ" ], "comment": "clean; hygienic; sanitary\npure; virtuous; immaculate" },
	{ "question": "済ませる", "answers": [ "すませる" ], "comment": "to finish; to make an end of; to get through with; to let end" },
	{ "question": "渋滞", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "congestion (e.g. traffic); delay; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "減らす", "answers": [ "へらす" ], "comment": "to abate; to decrease; to diminish; to shorten" },
	{ "question": "減る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "to decrease (in size or number); to diminish; to abate" },
	{ "question": "渡す", "answers": [ "わたす" ], "comment": "to ferry across (e.g. a river); to carry across; to traverse\nto lay across; to build across\nto hand over; to hand in; to pass; to give; to transfer" },
	{ "question": "渡る", "answers": [ "わたる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to go across\nto extend; to cover; to range; to span" },
	{ "question": "温度", "answers": [ "おんど" ], "comment": "temperature" },
	{ "question": "温暖", "answers": [ "おんだん" ], "comment": "warm; mild; temperate; warmth" },
	{ "question": "湾", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "bay; gulf; inlet" },
	{ "question": "満ちる", "answers": [ "みちる" ], "comment": "to be full\nto wax (e.g. moon)\nto rise (e.g. tide)\nto mature; to expire" },
	{ "question": "満足", "answers": [ "まんぞく" ], "comment": "satisfaction; contentment; complacency\nsufficient; enough; adequate; proper" },
	{ "question": "準備", "answers": [ "じゅんび" ], "comment": "preparation; setup; arrangements; provision; reserve" },
	{ "question": "溺れる", "answers": [ "おぼれる" ], "comment": "to drown; to nearly drown; to sink below the surface (of water)\nto indulge in; to lose one's head over something; to wallow in" },
	{ "question": "滅多に", "answers": [ "めったに" ], "comment": "rarely; seldom" },
	{ "question": "滞在", "answers": [ "たいざい" ], "comment": "stay; sojourn" },
	{ "question": "演奏", "answers": [ "えんそう" ], "comment": "musical performance" },
	{ "question": "演技", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "acting; performance" },
	{ "question": "演説", "answers": [ "えんぜつ" ], "comment": "speech; address" },
	{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "violent; furious; tempestuous\nextreme; intense; fierce; strong\nfervent; vehement\nincessant; relentless\nprecipitous; steep" },
	{ "question": "濃い", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "deep (colour); dark\nstrong (flavour, smell, etc.)\nthick (consistency); dense\nstrong (possibility, etc.)\nthick (i.e. \"as thick as thieves\"); close; deep (love, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "火曜", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "Tuesday" },
	{ "question": "火災", "answers": [ "かさい" ], "comment": "conflagration; fire" },
	{ "question": "灯", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "light; lamp; torch\nlamp; light\nlight (esp. as a religious offering); lamp\nlight; lamp\ncounter for electric lights\nlight; lamp\nbaiting deer with a lighted torch\nlight; lamp" },
	{ "question": "灰", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "ash; ashes" },
	{ "question": "炎", "answers": [ "ほのお" ], "comment": "flame; blaze\nflames (of intense emotion, e.g. love, jealousy, anger); passion\n-itis (indicating an inflammatory disease)" },
	{ "question": "為る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "to do\nto cause to become; to make (into); to turn (into)\nto serve as; to act as; to work as\nto wear (clothes, a facial expression, etc.)\nto judge as being; to view as being; to think of as; to treat as; to use as\nto decide on; to choose\nto be sensed (of a smell, noise, etc.)\nto be (in a state, condition, etc.)\nto be worth; to cost\nto pass (of time); to elapse\nto place, or raise, person A to a post or status B\nto transform A to B; to make A into B; to exchange A for B\nto make use of A for B; to view A as B; to handle A as if it were B\nto feel A about B\nverbalizing suffix (applies to nouns noted in this dictionary with the part of speech \"vs\")\ncreates a humble verb (after a noun prefixed with \"o\" or \"go\")\nto be just about to; to be just starting to; to try to; to attempt to\nto become; to get; to grow; to be; to reach; to attain\nto result in; to prove to be\nto consist of; to be composed of\nto succeed; to be complete\nto change into; to be exchanged for\nto play a role\nto be promoted\nto do ..." },
	{ "question": "無", "answers": [ "む" ], "comment": "nothing; naught; nought; nil; zero\nun-; non-\nun-; non-\nbad ...; poor ..." },
	{ "question": "無し", "answers": [ "なし" ], "comment": "without\nunacceptable; not alright; unsatisfactory" },
	{ "question": "無事", "answers": [ "ぶじ" ], "comment": "safety; peace; quietness" },
	{ "question": "無料", "answers": [ "むりょう" ], "comment": "free; no charge" },
	{ "question": "無視", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "disregarding; ignoring" },
	{ "question": "無駄", "answers": [ "むだ" ], "comment": "futility; uselessness; pointlessness" },
	{ "question": "煙", "answers": [ "けむり" ], "comment": "smoke; fumes" },
	{ "question": "熱中する", "answers": [ "ねっちゅうする" ], "comment": "become enthusiastic about; be full of enthusiasm for; be crazy about; be keen on; be absorbed in; be intent on; devote oneself to; give oneself up to; abandon oneself to; put one's heart into; go heart and soul into; be infatuated with; enthuse over; be hooked on; go in for in a big way; be nuts about" },
	{ "question": "熱帯", "answers": [ "ねったい" ], "comment": "tropics" },
	{ "question": "熱心", "answers": [ "ねっしん" ], "comment": "zeal; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "燃える", "answers": [ "もえる" ], "comment": "to burn; to get fired up" },
	{ "question": "爆発", "answers": [ "ばくはつ" ], "comment": "explosion; detonation; eruption" },
	{ "question": "父親", "answers": [ "ちちおや" ], "comment": "father" },
	{ "question": "牛", "answers": [ "うし" ], "comment": "cattle (Bos taurus); cow; bull; ox; calf\nbeef\nChinese \"Ox\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "物事", "answers": [ "ものごと" ], "comment": "things; everything" },
	{ "question": "物価", "answers": [ "ぶっか" ], "comment": "prices of commodities; prices (in general); cost-of-living" },
	{ "question": "物理", "answers": [ "ぶつり" ], "comment": "physics; law of nature" },
	{ "question": "物語", "answers": [ "ものがたり" ], "comment": "tale; story; legend" },
	{ "question": "物質", "answers": [ "ぶっしつ" ], "comment": "material; substance\nmatter" },
	{ "question": "物音", "answers": [ "ものおと" ], "comment": "sounds" },
	{ "question": "特徴", "answers": [ "とくちょう" ], "comment": "feature; trait; characteristic; peculiarity; distinction" },
	{ "question": "犯人", "answers": [ "はんにん" ], "comment": "offender; criminal" },
	{ "question": "犯罪", "answers": [ "はんざい" ], "comment": "crime; offence; offense" },
	{ "question": "状態", "answers": [ "じょうたい" ], "comment": "current status; condition; situation; circumstances; state" },
	{ "question": "状況", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "state of affairs (around you); situation; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "狂う", "answers": [ "くるう" ], "comment": "to go mad\nto get out of order; to go amiss" },
	{ "question": "独り", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "独特", "answers": [ "どくとく" ], "comment": "peculiarity; uniqueness; characteristic" },
	{ "question": "独立", "answers": [ "どくりつ" ], "comment": "independence (e.g. Independence Day); self-support" },
	{ "question": "独身", "answers": [ "どくしん" ], "comment": "bachelorhood; single; unmarried; celibate" },
	{ "question": "猿", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "monkey (esp. the Japanese macaque, Macaca fuscata); ape; non-human primate\nsly person\nidiot; hick\nsliding wooden bolt (for holding a door or window shut)\nclasp used to control the height of a pot-hook\nbathhouse prostitute\nmonkey (esp. the Japanese macaque, Macaca fuscata); ape; non-human primate" },
	{ "question": "率", "answers": [ "りつ" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; proportion; percentage" },
	{ "question": "玉", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "ball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent\nprecious stone (esp. jade)\negg (sometimes esp. as a sushi topping)\nstock or security being traded; product being bought or sold\nposition (in finance, the amount of a security either owned or owed by an investor or dealer)\ngeisha\ntime charge for a geisha\nking (of the junior player)" },
	{ "question": "王", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "king; ruler; sovereign; monarch\ntycoon; magnate; champion; master\nking (of the senior player)\nemperor; king; prince" },
	{ "question": "王子", "answers": [ "おうじ" ], "comment": "prince\nsubordinate Kumano shrine" },
	{ "question": "王様", "answers": [ "おうさま" ], "comment": "king" },
	{ "question": "現す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known" },
	{ "question": "現れ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "embodiment; manifestation; materialization; materialisation; expression; indication" },
	{ "question": "現れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "現代", "answers": [ "げんだい" ], "comment": "nowadays; modern era; modern times; present-day" },
	{ "question": "現在", "answers": [ "げんざい" ], "comment": "now; current; present; present time; as of" },
	{ "question": "現場", "answers": [ "げんば" ], "comment": "actual spot; scene; scene of the crime; site; location; setting\nshop floor; factory floor; (on) site" },
	{ "question": "現実", "answers": [ "げんじつ" ], "comment": "reality; actuality; hard fact" },
	{ "question": "現状", "answers": [ "げんじょう" ], "comment": "present condition; existing state; status quo; current state" },
	{ "question": "現象", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "phenomenon" },
	{ "question": "現金", "answers": [ "げんきん" ], "comment": "cash; ready money; money on hand; currency\nmercenary; self-interested; calculating" },
	{ "question": "球", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "ball (for sport, games, etc.)\nsphere\ncounter for balls\nball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent" },
	{ "question": "理想", "answers": [ "りそう" ], "comment": "ideal; ideals" },
	{ "question": "理解", "answers": [ "りかい" ], "comment": "understanding; comprehension; appreciation; sympathy" },
	{ "question": "環境", "answers": [ "かんきょう" ], "comment": "environment; circumstance" },
	{ "question": "瓶", "answers": [ "びん" ], "comment": "earthenware pot\nbottle; jar; decanter; flagon; phial; vial" },
	{ "question": "生", "answers": [ "なま", "せい", "しょう", "き" ], "comment": "pure; undiluted; raw; crude\nraw; uncooked; fresh\nnatural; as it is; unedited; unprocessed\nunprotected (i.e. not wearing a condom)\nlive (i.e. not recorded)\ninexperienced; unpolished; green; crude\nimpudence; sauciness\nunpasteurized beer; draft beer; draught beer\njust a little; somehow; vaguely; partially; somewhat; half-; semi-\nirresponsibly; half-baked\ncash\ntipsiness\ninnocent; naive; unsophisticated; inexperienced; green; wet behind the ears\nbirth-\nlife; living\nI; me; myself\nvital; virile; lively\narea of thick growth (of trees, grass, etc.)\nboiled and half-dried bonito" },
	{ "question": "生き物", "answers": [ "いきもの" ], "comment": "living thing; animal" },
	{ "question": "生じる", "answers": [ "しょうじる" ], "comment": "to produce; to yield; to cause\nto result from; to arise; to be generated" },
	{ "question": "生まれ", "answers": [ "うまれ" ], "comment": "birth; birthplace\nborn in (country, month, imperial era, zodiac year, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "生命", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "life; existence" },
	{ "question": "生地", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "cloth; fabric; material; texture\none's true character\nunglazed pottery\nuncooked dough; batter\nbirthplace" },
	{ "question": "生物", "answers": [ "せいぶつ", "なまもの" ], "comment": "living things; creature\nbiology\nraw food; perishables" },
	{ "question": "産業", "answers": [ "さんぎょう" ], "comment": "industry\nlivelihood; occupation" },
	{ "question": "用いる", "answers": [ "もちいる" ], "comment": "to use; to make use of; to utilize; to utilise" },
	{ "question": "用心", "answers": [ "ようじん" ], "comment": "care; precaution; guarding; caution" },
	{ "question": "田", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "rice field" },
	{ "question": "申し訳", "answers": [ "もうしわけ" ], "comment": "apology; excuse" },
	{ "question": "申し込む", "answers": [ "もうしこむ" ], "comment": "to apply for; to make an application; to propose (marriage); to offer (mediation); to make an overture (of peace); to challenge; to lodge (objections); to request (an interview); to subscribe for; to book; to reserve" },
	{ "question": "男の人", "answers": [ "おとこのひと" ], "comment": "man" },
	{ "question": "男子", "answers": [ "だんし" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "画家", "answers": [ "がか" ], "comment": "painter; artist" },
	{ "question": "畑", "answers": [ "はたけ" ], "comment": "field (for fruits, vegetables, etc.); cultivated land; vegetable plot; kitchen garden; plantation\nfield (of specialization); sphere; area\nwomb; birth; birthplace" },
	{ "question": "留める", "answers": [ "とめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to turn off\nto park\nto prevent; to suppress (a cough); to hold back (tears); to hold (one's breath); to relieve (pain)\nto stop (someone from doing something); to dissuade; to forbid; to prohibit\nto notice; to be aware of; to concentrate on; to pay attention to; to remember; to bear in mind\nto fix (in place); to fasten; to tack; to pin; to nail; to button; to staple\nto detain; to keep in custody\nto stop; to stay (e.g. the night); to cease; to put an end to\nto contain; to keep (in position, in place); to limit\nto record (e.g. a fact); to retain" },
	{ "question": "留学", "answers": [ "りゅうがく" ], "comment": "studying abroad (usu. at university level)" },
	{ "question": "番", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "number (in a series)\n(one's) turn\nwatch; guard; lookout\nbout; match\n(one) pair (e.g. of birds); brace; couple\njoint; hinge" },
	{ "question": "異なる", "answers": [ "ことなる" ], "comment": "to differ; to vary; to disagree" },
	{ "question": "異常", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "strangeness; abnormality; disorder" },
	{ "question": "疑う", "answers": [ "うたがう" ], "comment": "to doubt; to distrust; to be suspicious of; to suspect" },
	{ "question": "疑問", "answers": [ "ぎもん" ], "comment": "question; problem; doubt; guess" },
	{ "question": "疲れ", "answers": [ "つかれ" ], "comment": "tiredness; fatigue" },
	{ "question": "症状", "answers": [ "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "symptoms; condition" },
	{ "question": "痛み", "answers": [ "いたみ" ], "comment": "pain; ache; soreness; grief; distress\ndamage; injury; wear; bruise; break" },
	{ "question": "癖", "answers": [ "くせ" ], "comment": "habit (often a bad habit, i.e. vice); tendency\npeculiarity; idiosyncrasy; mannerism\ncrease; wrinkle; curl; kink" },
	{ "question": "発展", "answers": [ "はってん" ], "comment": "development; growth; advancement; unfurling\nexpansion; extension; enlargement\nplaying around; having an active sex life" },
	{ "question": "発明", "answers": [ "はつめい" ], "comment": "invention\nintelligent; clever\nbeing enlightened; having the meaning of everything become clear" },
	{ "question": "発行", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "issue (publications); publishing\nraising an event (software)" },
	{ "question": "発表", "answers": [ "はっぴょう" ], "comment": "announcement; publication; presenting; statement; communique; making known; breaking (news story); expressing (one's opinion); releasing; unveiling" },
	{ "question": "発見", "answers": [ "はっけん" ], "comment": "discovery; detection; finding" },
	{ "question": "発車", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "departure of a vehicle" },
	{ "question": "発達", "answers": [ "はったつ" ], "comment": "development; growth" },
	{ "question": "登山", "answers": [ "とざん" ], "comment": "mountain climbing" },
	{ "question": "皮", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "skin; hide; pelt; fur\nrind; peel; husk; bark\nshell; sheath; wrapping\nmask (hiding one's true nature); seeming" },
	{ "question": "皿", "answers": [ "さら" ], "comment": "plate; dish; platter; disc\nserving; helping; course\nkanji radical 108 (at the bottom)" },
	{ "question": "盛り", "answers": [ "さかり" ], "comment": "peak (e.g. of cherry blossom season); height (e.g. of summer)\nprime (of one's life); one's best days\nrutting; being in heat\nserving (of food); helping\nchilled soba served on a dish (often on a wicker basket or in a shallow steaming basket) with dipping sauce" },
	{ "question": "監督", "answers": [ "かんとく" ], "comment": "supervision; control; superintendence; direction\ndirector; superintendent; supervisor; coach; foreman; manager; overseer; controller; boss" },
	{ "question": "目標", "answers": [ "もくひょう" ], "comment": "mark; sign; landmark; benchmark\nmark; objective; target" },
	{ "question": "目的", "answers": [ "もくてき" ], "comment": "purpose; goal; aim; objective; intention" },
	{ "question": "直ちに", "answers": [ "ただちに" ], "comment": "at once; immediately; directly; in person; automatically" },
	{ "question": "直に", "answers": [ "じかに" ], "comment": "directly; in person; firsthand\nimmediately; directly; soon; shortly; before long\neasily; readily" },
	{ "question": "直接", "answers": [ "ちょくせつ" ], "comment": "direct; immediate; personal; firsthand" },
	{ "question": "相当", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "befitting; becoming; worthy of; proportionate; in keeping with; suitable\nconsiderable; substantial\nto be worthy of; to be proportionate to\nto correspond to (in meaning, function, etc.); to be equivalent\nextremely; considerably" },
	{ "question": "相手", "answers": [ "あいて" ], "comment": "companion; partner; company\nother party; addressee\nopponent (sports, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "相続", "answers": [ "そうぞく" ], "comment": "succession; inheritance" },
	{ "question": "相談", "answers": [ "そうだん" ], "comment": "consultation; discussion" },
	{ "question": "省く", "answers": [ "はぶく" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to exclude; to eliminate\nto curtail; to save; to cut down; to economize; to economise" },
	{ "question": "県", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "prefecture (of Japan)\ncounty (of China)\nterritory (pre-Taika: under the Yamato court; Heian: under a provincial governor, etc.)\ncountryside" },
	{ "question": "真っ直ぐ", "answers": [ "まっすぐ" ], "comment": "straight (ahead); direct; upright; erect\nstraightforward; honest; frank" },
	{ "question": "真っ赤", "answers": [ "まっか" ], "comment": "bright red; deep red; flushed (of face)\ndownright (e.g. lie); complete; utter" },
	{ "question": "真似", "answers": [ "まね" ], "comment": "imitating; copying; mimicry\nbehavior; behaviour; action; conduct" },
	{ "question": "真剣", "answers": [ "しんけん" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness\nreal sword (as opposed to unsharpened or wooden practice weapon)" },
	{ "question": "真面目", "answers": [ "まじめ" ], "comment": "one's true character; one's true self; oneself\nseriousness; earnestness\ndiligent; serious; honest; sober; grave; earnest; steady" },
	{ "question": "眺め", "answers": [ "ながめ" ], "comment": "scene; view; prospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "眺める", "answers": [ "ながめる" ], "comment": "to view; to gaze at" },
	{ "question": "睡眠", "answers": [ "すいみん" ], "comment": "sleep" },
	{ "question": "瞬間", "answers": [ "しゅんかん" ], "comment": "moment; second; instant" },
	{ "question": "知らせ", "answers": [ "しらせ" ], "comment": "news; word; tidings; notice; notification; information\nomen" },
	{ "question": "知事", "answers": [ "ちじ" ], "comment": "prefectural governor" },
	{ "question": "知恵", "answers": [ "ちえ" ], "comment": "wisdom; wit; sagacity; sense; intelligence\nprajna (insight leading to enlightenment)" },
	{ "question": "知能", "answers": [ "ちのう" ], "comment": "intelligence; intellect; brains" },
	{ "question": "知識", "answers": [ "ちしき" ], "comment": "knowledge; information" },
	{ "question": "石油", "answers": [ "せきゆ" ], "comment": "oil; petroleum; kerosene" },
	{ "question": "石炭", "answers": [ "せきたん" ], "comment": "coal" },
	{ "question": "砂漠", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "desert" },
	{ "question": "破る", "answers": [ "やぶる" ], "comment": "to tear; to break; to destroy\nto break through (opponent's defense etc.); to breach\nto defeat; to beat\nto shatter (dream, peace, etc.); to disturb\nto violate (a rule etc.); to break (a promise etc.)\nto break (a record)" },
	{ "question": "破産", "answers": [ "はさん" ], "comment": "bankruptcy; insolvency" },
	{ "question": "硬貨", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "coin\nhard currency" },
	{ "question": "確かめる", "answers": [ "たしかめる" ], "comment": "to ascertain; to check; to make sure" },
	{ "question": "確実", "answers": [ "かくじつ" ], "comment": "certainty; reliability; soundness" },
	{ "question": "確認", "answers": [ "かくにん" ], "comment": "confirmation; verification; validation; review; check; affirmation; identification" },
	{ "question": "示す", "answers": [ "しめす" ], "comment": "to (take out and) show; to demonstrate; to tell; to exemplify; to make apparent\nto point out (finger, clock hand, needle, etc.)\nto indicate; to show; to represent; to signify; to display" },
	{ "question": "礼", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude\nmanners; etiquette\nbow\nreward; gift\nceremony; ritual" },
	{ "question": "礼儀", "answers": [ "れいぎ" ], "comment": "manners; courtesy; etiquette" },
	{ "question": "祝い", "answers": [ "いわい" ], "comment": "congratulation; congratulations; celebration; festival; congratulatory gift" },
	{ "question": "祝う", "answers": [ "いわう" ], "comment": "to congratulate; to celebrate; to observe (a festival)" },
	{ "question": "神", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "god; deity; divinity; spirit; kami\nincredible; fantastic\nemperor of Japan\nthunder\nspirit; psyche\ngod; deity; divinity; kami\nsoul; spirit; divine spirit" },
	{ "question": "神経", "answers": [ "しんけい" ], "comment": "nerve\nnerves; sensitivity" },
	{ "question": "禁止", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "prohibition; inhibition; ban" },
	{ "question": "禁煙", "answers": [ "きんえん" ], "comment": "abstaining from smoking; quitting smoking\nNo Smoking!; Smoking Prohibited!" },
	{ "question": "科目", "answers": [ "かもく" ], "comment": "(school) subject; curriculum; course" },
	{ "question": "秒", "answers": [ "びょう" ], "comment": "second (60th min)" },
	{ "question": "秘密", "answers": [ "ひみつ" ], "comment": "secret; secrecy; confidentiality; privacy\nsecret; mystery\nesoteric teachings" },
	{ "question": "移す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to change; to swap; to substitute; to transfer\nto change the object of one's interest or focus\nto spend or take time\nto infect\nto permeate something with the smell or colour of something\nto move on to the next or different stage of (a plan, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "移動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "movement; transfer; migration; removal; travel\nmobile; moving; traveling; travelling; roving" },
	{ "question": "程", "answers": [ "ほど" ], "comment": "degree; extent; bounds; limit\nindicates approx. amount or maximum; upper limit" },
	{ "question": "程度", "answers": [ "ていど" ], "comment": "degree; amount; grade; standard; of the order of (following a number); about; approximately" },
	{ "question": "税", "answers": [ "ぜい" ], "comment": "tax" },
	{ "question": "税金", "answers": [ "ぜいきん" ], "comment": "tax; duty" },
	{ "question": "種", "answers": [ "たね" ], "comment": "kind; variety\n(biological) species\n(logical) species\nseed (e.g. of a plant); pip; kind; variety; quality; tone\nmaterial (e.g. for an article); matter (e.g. of a story); subject; theme; (news) copy\ningredient; leaven (bread); main ingredient of a sushi\ncause; source\ntrick; secret; magician's trick; inside story\npaternal blood; lineage\nbreed (of a stock); sperm; semen\ncause; seed; origin\nvariety; kind\ncounter for varieties" },
	{ "question": "種類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "variety; kind; type; category\ncounter for different sorts of things" },
	{ "question": "稲", "answers": [ "いね" ], "comment": "rice plant" },
	{ "question": "稼ぐ", "answers": [ "かせぐ" ], "comment": "to earn (income); to make (money)\nto score (points, victory); to gain (time); to play (for time)\nto work hard (at one's job); to labor; to labour; to toil" },
	{ "question": "穀物", "answers": [ "こくもつ" ], "comment": "grain; cereal; corn" },
	{ "question": "積もる", "answers": [ "つもる" ], "comment": "to pile up; to accumulate\nto estimate" },
	{ "question": "積極的", "answers": [ "せっきょくてき" ], "comment": "positive; assertive; active; proactive; aggressive" },
	{ "question": "穏やか", "answers": [ "おだやか" ], "comment": "calm; gentle; quiet" },
	{ "question": "穴", "answers": [ "あな" ], "comment": "hole\ndeficit; shortage; missing person (in a team, meeting, etc.)\nvacancy; opening\nflaw\nprofitable place (or item, etc.) not well known by others\nupset victory (with a large payoff)\npit (of a theater)\nhiding place\nunderbelly (of society, etc.)\nass; arse; buttocks\nrear; end\nacupuncture point\nhole; notch" },
	{ "question": "空き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "space; room; gap; emptiness\nvacancy; opening; empty seat\nfree time; time to spare\ndisuse; unused thing" },
	{ "question": "空く", "answers": [ "すく", "あく" ], "comment": "to become less crowded; to thin out; to get empty\nto be hungry\nto open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "突然", "answers": [ "とつぜん" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden; unexpected; all at once" },
	{ "question": "立ち上がる", "answers": [ "たちあがる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to get up\nto rise\nto recover\nto take action; to start\nto make the initial charge\nto start up; to boot up" },
	{ "question": "立場", "answers": [ "たちば" ], "comment": "standpoint; position; situation" },
	{ "question": "立派", "answers": [ "りっぱ" ], "comment": "splendid; fine; handsome; elegant; imposing; prominent\npraiseworthy; creditable; worthy\nlegal; legitimate; lawful\nundeniable (e.g. crime); indisputable; solid" },
	{ "question": "章", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "chapter; section\nmedal" },
	{ "question": "端", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "near; close; beside; vicinity; proximity; besides; while\nthird person\nend (e.g. of street); tip; point; edge; margin\nbeginning; start; first\nodds and ends; scrap; odd bit; least\nfraction; odd sum\nloose change\nlow class female servant\nedge; tip; end\ngable wall\ngable\norigin\nvariable measure of fabric (28.8 cm in width); for kimonos: at least 10 m in length; for haori: at least 7.27 m in length; for other clothes: at least 6.06 m in length\ntip; extremity" },
	{ "question": "競技", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "game; match; contest" },
	{ "question": "笑い", "answers": [ "わらい" ], "comment": "laugh; laughter\nsmile\nsneer\nsex aids (e.g. dildos, pornographic books, erotic woodblock prints, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "笑顔", "answers": [ "えがお" ], "comment": "smiling face; smile" },
	{ "question": "笛", "answers": [ "ふえ" ], "comment": "flute; fife; pipe; recorder; flageolet; shakuhachi; clarinet\nwhistle" },
	{ "question": "筆", "answers": [ "ふで" ], "comment": "writing brush" },
	{ "question": "等", "answers": [ "など" ], "comment": "et cetera; etc.; and the like; and so forth\nor something\nthe likes of\nclass; order; rank\net cetera; etc.; and the like\nequal; iso-\npluralizing suffix\nor so; rough indicator of direction, location, amount, etc.\nnominalizing suffix" },
	{ "question": "等しい", "answers": [ "ひとしい" ], "comment": "equal; similar; like; equivalent" },
	{ "question": "筋", "answers": [ "すじ" ], "comment": "muscle; tendon; sinew\nvein; artery\nfiber; fibre; string\nline; stripe; streak\nreason; logic\nplot; storyline\nlineage; descent\nschool (e.g. of scholarship or arts)\naptitude; talent\nsource (of information, etc.); circle; channel\nwell-informed person (in a transaction)\nlogical move (in go, shogi, etc.)\nninth vertical line\nseam on a helmet\ngristly fish paste (made of muscle, tendons, skin, etc.)\nsocial position; status\non (a river, road, etc.); along\ncounter for long thin things; counter for roads or blocks when giving directions\n(Edo period) counter for hundreds of mon (obsolete unit of currency)\nmuscle" },
	{ "question": "筋肉", "answers": [ "きんにく" ], "comment": "muscle; sinew\nsinewy meat" },
	{ "question": "答案", "answers": [ "とうあん" ], "comment": "examination paper; examination script" },
	{ "question": "管", "answers": [ "くだ" ], "comment": "pipe; tube" },
	{ "question": "管理", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "control; management (e.g. of a business)" },
	{ "question": "節", "answers": [ "ふし" ], "comment": "occasion; time\nsection (of a literary work); paragraph; verse; stanza; passage\nprinciple; integrity\nnode (of a plant stem)\nclause\n(taxonomical) section\nknot (nautical mile per hour)\njoint; knuckle\ntune; melody\nknot (in wood); node in a bamboo stem\npart; notable characteristic\ncharacteristic way of speaking\nspace between two nodes (on bamboo, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "節約", "answers": [ "せつやく" ], "comment": "economising; saving" },
	{ "question": "範囲", "answers": [ "はんい" ], "comment": "extent; scope; sphere; range; span" },
	{ "question": "粉", "answers": [ "こな" ], "comment": "flour; meal; powder" },
	{ "question": "粗い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "coarse; rough" },
	{ "question": "粗末", "answers": [ "そまつ" ], "comment": "crude; rough; plain; humble; shabby" },
	{ "question": "精々", "answers": [ "せいぜい" ], "comment": "at the most; at best; to the utmost; as much (far) as possible" },
	{ "question": "精神", "answers": [ "せいしん" ], "comment": "mind; soul; heart; spirit; intention" },
	{ "question": "約", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "approximately; about\npromise\nshortening; reduction; simplification\ncontraction (in phonetics)" },
	{ "question": "納得", "answers": [ "なっとく" ], "comment": "consent; assent; agreement\nunderstanding; comprehension; grasp" },
	{ "question": "級", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "class (e.g. school); grade; rank" },
	{ "question": "素晴らしい", "answers": [ "すばらしい" ], "comment": "wonderful; splendid; magnificent" },
	{ "question": "終える", "answers": [ "おえる" ], "comment": "to finish\nto graduate" },
	{ "question": "組", "answers": [ "くみ" ], "comment": "set (of items)\ngroup (of people); class (of students); company (esp. construction); family (i.e. mafia); team\ntypesetting; composition" },
	{ "question": "組む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "to cross (legs or arms); to link (arms)\nto put together; to construct; to assemble; to produce (e.g. TV program)\nto braid; to plait\nto grapple; to wrestle\nto unite; to join; to link up; to form an alliance\nto set (e.g. type)\nto issue (e.g. money order)" },
	{ "question": "組合", "answers": [ "くみあい" ], "comment": "association; union; guild" },
	{ "question": "組織", "answers": [ "そしき" ], "comment": "organization; organisation\nstructure; construction\ntissue\nsystem" },
	{ "question": "経つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to pass (of time); to elapse" },
	{ "question": "経営", "answers": [ "けいえい" ], "comment": "management; administration; operation; running (business); conducting" },
	{ "question": "経由", "answers": [ "けいゆ" ], "comment": "through; by way of; via\nto go via; to go by way of" },
	{ "question": "経験", "answers": [ "けいけん" ], "comment": "experience" },
	{ "question": "結ぶ", "answers": [ "むすぶ" ], "comment": "to tie; to bind; to link\nto bear (fruit)\nto close (e.g. deal); to confirm; to conclude\nto connect (two distant places)\nto close tightly; to purse (e.g. lips)\nto unite (with); to ally; to join hands" },
	{ "question": "結局", "answers": [ "けっきょく" ], "comment": "after all; eventually; in the end\nconclusion; end\nending of a game of Go" },
	{ "question": "結果", "answers": [ "けっか" ], "comment": "result; consequence; outcome; effect\ncoming to fruition; bearing fruit" },
	{ "question": "結論", "answers": [ "けつろん" ], "comment": "conclusion" },
	{ "question": "給料", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "salary; wages" },
	{ "question": "絵画", "answers": [ "かいが" ], "comment": "picture; painting" },
	{ "question": "絶対", "answers": [ "ぜったい" ], "comment": "absolutely; unconditionally\nabsolute; unconditional; unmistakable\nabsoluteness" },
	{ "question": "絶滅", "answers": [ "ぜつめつ" ], "comment": "destruction; extinction" },
	{ "question": "続き", "answers": [ "つづき" ], "comment": "sequel; continuation; (also suffix) continuation (in time and space); second series; succession; spell" },
	{ "question": "維持", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "maintenance; preservation; improvement" },
	{ "question": "綿", "answers": [ "わた" ], "comment": "cotton\ncotton plant (Gossypium spp.)\nbatting; wadding; padding" },
	{ "question": "緊張", "answers": [ "きんちょう" ], "comment": "tension; mental strain; nervousness" },
	{ "question": "縁", "answers": [ "エン", "ふち", "へり", "ゆかり", "えにし" ], "comment": "related to (some person or place); affinity; connection\nfate; destiny (esp. as a mysterious force that binds two people together)\nrelationship (e.g. between two people); bond; link; connection\nfamily ties; affinity\nopportunity; chance (to meet someone and start a relationship)\npratyaya (indirect conditions, as opposed to direct causes)\nnarrow open-air veranda\nrim; brim; edge; brink\nreason; significance; cause\nsomething to rely on; aid; clue; way; means\nsomeone to rely on; relative\nreminder; memento\nedge (of a river, woods, etc.); shoulder (of a road)\nrim; brim; hem; margin; fringe; selvage\nfabric border (of a tatami mat, etc.); edging" },
	{ "question": "縄", "answers": [ "なわ" ], "comment": "rope; cord\npoliceman's rope" },
	{ "question": "縦", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "the vertical; height\nfront-to-back; length\nnorth-to-south\nvertical (relationship); hierarchy\n(weaving) warp\nselfish; self-indulgent; arbitrary\neven if" },
	{ "question": "繰り返す", "answers": [ "くりかえす" ], "comment": "to repeat; to do something over again" },
	{ "question": "缶", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "can; tin\ncanned food\nboiler\nfat-bodied, small-mouthed earthenware jar for carrying water\nwater vessel used for a baby's first bath" },
	{ "question": "罪", "answers": [ "つみ" ], "comment": "crime; sin; wrongdoing; indiscretion\npenalty; sentence; punishment\nfault; responsibility; culpability\nthoughtlessness; lack of consideration" },
	{ "question": "罰する", "answers": [ "ばっする" ], "comment": "to punish; to penalize; to penalise" },
	{ "question": "署名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "signature" },
	{ "question": "美人", "answers": [ "びじん" ], "comment": "beautiful woman" },
	{ "question": "義務", "answers": [ "ぎむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "羽", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "feather; plume; down\nwing\nblade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)\nshuttlecock\ncounter for birds and rabbits\nfifth degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)" },
	{ "question": "翼", "answers": [ "つばさ" ], "comment": "wing\nChinese \"Wings\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\ncounter for birds or bird wings" },
	{ "question": "老い", "answers": [ "おい" ], "comment": "old age; old person; the old; the aged" },
	{ "question": "老人", "answers": [ "ろうじん" ], "comment": "the aged; old person" },
	{ "question": "考え", "answers": [ "かんがえ" ], "comment": "thinking; thought; view; opinion; concept\nidea; notion; imagination\nintention; plan; design\nconsideration; judgement; deliberation; reflection\nwish; hope; expectation" },
	{ "question": "考慮", "answers": [ "こうりょ" ], "comment": "consideration; taking into account" },
	{ "question": "者", "answers": [ "もの" ], "comment": "person\nsomeone of that nature; someone doing that work" },
	{ "question": "職", "answers": [ "しょく" ], "comment": "job; work; employment; occupation; position\nduties\ntrade; skill\nagency (government department between a ministry and a bureau under the ritsuryo system)" },
	{ "question": "職業", "answers": [ "しょくぎょう" ], "comment": "occupation; business" },
	{ "question": "肌", "answers": [ "はだ" ], "comment": "skin\nbody (in the context of intimate bodily contact)\nsurface; grain (e.g. of wood); texture\ndisposition; temperament; character; type" },
	{ "question": "肩", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "shoulder" },
	{ "question": "育つ", "answers": [ "そだつ" ], "comment": "to be raised (e.g. child); to be brought up; to grow (up)" },
	{ "question": "胃", "answers": [ "い" ], "comment": "stomach\nChinese \"stomach\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "胸", "answers": [ "むね" ], "comment": "chest; breast\nbreasts; bosom; bust\nheart\nlungs\nstomach\nheart; mind; feelings" },
	{ "question": "能", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "talent; gift; function\nnoh (theatre)" },
	{ "question": "能力", "answers": [ "のうりょく" ], "comment": "ability; faculty\nlow-ranking priest who does manual labour at a temple; male temple employee" },
	{ "question": "脇", "answers": [ "わき" ], "comment": "armpit; under one's arm; side; flank\nbeside; close to; near; by\naside; to the side; away; out of the way\noff-track; off-topic\ndeuteragonist; supporting role\nsecond verse (in a linked series of poems)\nside; edge; beside; besides; nearby\nwhile (doing); in addition to; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "腐る", "answers": [ "くさる" ], "comment": "to rot; to go bad; to decay; to spoil; to fester; to decompose; to turn sour (e.g. milk)\nto corrode; to weather; to crumble\nto become useless; to blunt; to weaken (from lack of practice)\nto become depraved; to be degenerate; to be morally bankrupt; to be corrupt\nto be depressed; to be dispirited; to feel discouraged; to feel down\nindicates scorn or disdain for another's action\nto lose a bet\nto be drenched; to become sopping wet" },
	{ "question": "腰", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "back; lower back; waist; hips; lumbar region\nbody (of hair, noodle, paper, etc.); resilience; spring\nposture; position; pose; attitude" },
	{ "question": "腹", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "abdomen; belly; stomach\nwomb\none's mind; one's real intentions; one's true motive\ncourage; nerve; willpower\ngenerosity; magnanimity\nfeelings; emotions\nwide middle part; bulging part\ninside; interior; inner part\nanti-node\ncounter for hard roe\ncounter for containers with bulging middles (pots, vases, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "膝", "answers": [ "ひざ" ], "comment": "knee\nlap; knee and thigh (while sitting)" },
	{ "question": "自動", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "automatic; self-motion\nintransitive verb" },
	{ "question": "自慢", "answers": [ "じまん" ], "comment": "pride; boast" },
	{ "question": "自殺", "answers": [ "じさつ" ], "comment": "suicide" },
	{ "question": "自然", "answers": [ "しぜん" ], "comment": "nature\nnatural; spontaneous\nnaturally; spontaneously" },
	{ "question": "自身", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "by oneself; personally" },
	{ "question": "臭い", "answers": [ "くさい" ], "comment": "stinking; smelly\nsuspicious; fishy\nclumsy; unskilled\nsmelling of\nlooking like; appearing like; smacking of; -ish\nodour; odor; scent; smell; stench\naura; whiff; smacks of ...; sense; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "至る", "answers": [ "いたる" ], "comment": "to arrive at (e.g. a decision); to reach (a stage); to attain\nto lead to (a place); to get to\nto come; to arrive; to result in" },
	{ "question": "舌", "answers": [ "した" ], "comment": "tongue\ntongue-like object; clapper (of a bell); talon (of a lock)" },
	{ "question": "舞台", "answers": [ "ぶたい" ], "comment": "stage (theatre, theater)\nscene or setting (e.g. of novel, play, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "航空", "answers": [ "こうくう" ], "comment": "aviation; flying" },
	{ "question": "芝居", "answers": [ "しばい" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "芝生", "answers": [ "しばふ" ], "comment": "lawn" },
	{ "question": "芸術", "answers": [ "げいじゅつ" ], "comment": "(fine) art; the arts" },
	{ "question": "芽", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "sprout" },
	{ "question": "苦しい", "answers": [ "くるしい" ], "comment": "painful; difficult; agonizing\nneedy; tight (budget); straitened (circumstances)\nforced (smile, joke); lame (excuse); strained (interpretation)\nawkward (situation); painful (position)\n(after masu stem) hard to do; unpleasant" },
	{ "question": "苦しむ", "answers": [ "くるしむ" ], "comment": "to suffer; to groan; to be worried" },
	{ "question": "苦労", "answers": [ "くろう" ], "comment": "troubles; hardships" },
	{ "question": "苦手", "answers": [ "にがて" ], "comment": "poor (at); weak (in); not very good (at)\ndislike (of); difficult to deal with" },
	{ "question": "苦痛", "answers": [ "くつう" ], "comment": "pain; agony; bitterness" },
	{ "question": "茶", "answers": [ "ちゃ" ], "comment": "tea\ntea plant (Camellia sinensis)\ntea preparation; making tea\nbrown\nmockery" },
	{ "question": "著者", "answers": [ "ちょしゃ" ], "comment": "author (usu. of a particular book); writer" },
	{ "question": "虎", "answers": [ "とら" ], "comment": "tiger (Panthera tigris)\ndrunkard; drunk; sot" },
	{ "question": "虫歯", "answers": [ "むしば" ], "comment": "cavity; tooth decay; decayed tooth; dental caries" },
	{ "question": "行き", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "bound for ...\ngoing (to)" },
	{ "question": "行儀", "answers": [ "ぎょうぎ" ], "comment": "manners; behavior; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "行動", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "action; conduct; behaviour; behavior; mobilization; mobilisation" },
	{ "question": "街", "answers": [ "まち" ], "comment": ".. street; .. quarter; .. district\ntown; block; neighbourhood; neighborhood\nstreet; road\ndowntown; main street" },
	{ "question": "衛星", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "satellite" },
	{ "question": "衝突", "answers": [ "しょうとつ" ], "comment": "collision; crash; running into\nconflict; quarrel; clashing" },
	{ "question": "衣服", "answers": [ "いふく" ], "comment": "clothes" },
	{ "question": "表", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "surface\nface (i.e. the visible side of an object)\nfront (of a building, etc.); obverse side (i.e. \"head\") of a coin\noutside; exterior\nappearance\npublic\nfirst half (of an inning); top (of an inning)\ncover (for tatami mats, etc.)\nforeground\ntable (e.g. Table 1); chart; list" },
	{ "question": "表す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known\nto express; to show" },
	{ "question": "表情", "answers": [ "ひょうじょう" ], "comment": "facial expression; countenance\nlook; appearance; expression (vocal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "表現", "answers": [ "ひょうげん" ], "comment": "expression; presentation\nrepresentation; notation" },
	{ "question": "表面", "answers": [ "ひょうめん" ], "comment": "surface; face\noutside; exterior\nappearances; superficiality" },
	{ "question": "袋", "answers": [ "ふくろ" ], "comment": "bag; sack; pouch\nskin of an orange (and other like fruits)\ndead end\nplot of land surrounded by water\ncounter for things inside a bag" },
	{ "question": "袖", "answers": [ "そで" ], "comment": "sleeve\nwing (of a stage, desk, gate, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "被る", "answers": [ "かぶる" ], "comment": "to put on (one's head); to wear; to have on; to pull over (one's head); to crown (oneself)\nto be covered with (dust, snow, etc.); to pour (water, etc.) on oneself; to dash on oneself; to ship water\nto bear (e.g. someone's debts, faults, etc.); to take (blame); to assume (responsibility); to shoulder (burden)\nto overlap (e.g. sound or color)\nto be similar; to be redundant\nto be fogged (due to overexposure, etc.)\nto close; to come to an end\nto get a full house; to sell out\nto blunder; to bungle; to fail\nto be deceived\nto suffer; to receive (kindness, rebuke, support); to sustain (damage)" },
	{ "question": "被害", "answers": [ "ひがい" ], "comment": "(suffering) damage; injury; harm" },
	{ "question": "裁判", "answers": [ "さいばん" ], "comment": "trial; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "装置", "answers": [ "そうち" ], "comment": "equipment; installation; apparatus; device" },
	{ "question": "裏切る", "answers": [ "うらぎる" ], "comment": "to betray; to turn traitor to; to double-cross" },
	{ "question": "裸", "answers": [ "はだか" ], "comment": "naked; nude; bare" },
	{ "question": "製品", "answers": [ "せいひん" ], "comment": "manufactured goods; finished goods; product" },
	{ "question": "製造", "answers": [ "せいぞう" ], "comment": "manufacture; production" },
	{ "question": "褒める", "answers": [ "ほめる" ], "comment": "to praise; to admire; to speak well of someone" },
	{ "question": "要するに", "answers": [ "ようするに" ], "comment": "in a word; after all; the point is ...; in short ...; to put simply; the long and short of it is that ...." },
	{ "question": "要る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "to need; to want" },
	{ "question": "要求", "answers": [ "ようきゅう" ], "comment": "demand; firm request; requisition; requirement; desire" },
	{ "question": "要点", "answers": [ "ようてん" ], "comment": "gist; main point" },
	{ "question": "要素", "answers": [ "ようそ" ], "comment": "component; factor; item (e.g. in list)\nelement (e.g. in array); member (e.g. data structure)" },
	{ "question": "覆う", "answers": [ "おおう" ], "comment": "to cover; to hide; to conceal; to wrap; to disguise" },
	{ "question": "見事", "answers": [ "みごと" ], "comment": "splendid; magnificent; beautiful; admirable\npraiseworthy act; feat; commendable deed\nutter (esp. defeat); total; complete" },
	{ "question": "見当", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "aim; mark; estimate; guess; approximation; direction" },
	{ "question": "見舞い", "answers": [ "みまい" ], "comment": "visiting ill or distressed people; writing get-well letters\nget-well gifts; get-well letters\nexpression of sympathy; expression of concern; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "見解", "answers": [ "けんかい" ], "comment": "opinion; point of view" },
	{ "question": "見送り", "answers": [ "みおくり" ], "comment": "seeing one off; farewell; escort" },
	{ "question": "覚ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "to awaken\nto disabuse\nto sober up" },
	{ "question": "覚める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "to wake; to wake up\nto become sober; to sober up; to regain consciousness (e.g. after anaesthesia)\nto come to one's senses; to be disillusioned" },
	{ "question": "覚悟", "answers": [ "かくご" ], "comment": "resolution; resignation; readiness; preparedness" },
	{ "question": "親しい", "answers": [ "したしい" ], "comment": "intimate; close (e.g. friend)\nintimate; close" },
	{ "question": "親友", "answers": [ "しんゆう" ], "comment": "close friend; bosom (old, intimate) friend; buddy; crony; chum" },
	{ "question": "親戚", "answers": [ "しんせき" ], "comment": "relative; relation; kin" },
	{ "question": "観光", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "sightseeing" },
	{ "question": "観客", "answers": [ "かんきゃく" ], "comment": "audience; spectator; spectators" },
	{ "question": "観察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "observation; survey; watching" },
	{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "カク", "かど", "つの" ], "comment": "angle\nsquare (or cube)\nbishop\nthird degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nChinese \"horn\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\njiao (monetary unit of China; one-tenth of a yuan)\ncorner (e.g. desk, pavement)\nedge\nhorn\ncorner; nook; recess\ndownstage right (on a noh stage)" },
	{ "question": "解く", "answers": [ "とく", "ほどく" ], "comment": "to untie; to unfasten; to unwrap; to undo; to unbind; to unpack\nto unsew; to unstitch\nto solve; to work out; to answer\nto dispel (misunderstanding, etc.); to clear up; to remove (suspicion); to appease\nto dissolve (a contract); to cancel; to remove (a prohibition); to lift (a ban); to raise (a siege)\nto release (from duty); to relieve; to dismiss\nto comb (out); to card; to untangle (hair)\nto unfasten; to untie; to unwrap (e.g. parcel)" },
	{ "question": "解ける", "answers": [ "とける", "ほどける" ], "comment": "to be solved\nto loosen; to come untied\nto be removed (e.g. restrictions); to be cleared (e.g. misunderstandings); to be broken (e.g. spells, curses)\nto melt\nto come lose; to come untied; to come undone; to unravel\nto loosen up (e.g. tension)" },
	{ "question": "解決", "answers": [ "かいけつ" ], "comment": "settlement; solution; resolution" },
	{ "question": "解釈", "answers": [ "かいしゃく" ], "comment": "explanation; interpretation" },
	{ "question": "触れる", "answers": [ "ふれる" ], "comment": "to touch; to feel\nto experience; to come in contact with; to be emotionally moved (by); to perceive\nto touch on a subject; to allude to\nto be in conflict (with); to violate (law, copyright, etc.)\nto proclaim" },
	{ "question": "言わば", "answers": [ "いわば" ], "comment": "so to speak; so to call it; as it were" },
	{ "question": "言語", "answers": [ "げんご" ], "comment": "language" },
	{ "question": "計る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "計画", "answers": [ "けいかく" ], "comment": "plan; project; schedule; scheme; program; programme" },
	{ "question": "計算", "answers": [ "けいさん" ], "comment": "calculation; reckoning; count\nforecast" },
	{ "question": "訓", "answers": [ "くん" ], "comment": "teaching; instruction; teachings; precept; lesson; doctrine\nnative Japanese reading (rendering) of a Chinese character" },
	{ "question": "訓練", "answers": [ "くんれん" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training" },
	{ "question": "記事", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "article; news story; report; account" },
	{ "question": "記入", "answers": [ "きにゅう" ], "comment": "entry; filling in of forms" },
	{ "question": "記念", "answers": [ "きねん" ], "comment": "commemoration; celebration; honoring the memory of something; turning something into a memento; memory" },
	{ "question": "記憶", "answers": [ "きおく" ], "comment": "memory; recollection; remembrance\nstorage" },
	{ "question": "記者", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "reporter" },
	{ "question": "記録", "answers": [ "きろく" ], "comment": "record; minutes; document\nrecord (e.g. in sports); results; score\nto record; to document\nto set a record (e.g. in sports); to show a result; to reach a value" },
	{ "question": "訪問", "answers": [ "ほうもん" ], "comment": "call; visit" },
	{ "question": "設備", "answers": [ "せつび" ], "comment": "equipment; device; facilities; installation" },
	{ "question": "設計", "answers": [ "せっけい" ], "comment": "plan; design; layout" },
	{ "question": "許す", "answers": [ "ゆるす" ], "comment": "to permit; to allow; to approve; to tolerate\nto exempt (from fine); to excuse (from); to pardon; to forgive; to release; to let off\nto confide in\nto give up; to yield" },
	{ "question": "訴える", "answers": [ "うったえる" ], "comment": "to raise; to bring to (someone's attention)\nto appeal to (reason, emotions, etc.); to work on (one's emotions); to play on (one's sympathies)\nto complain\nto sue (a person); to take someone to court\nto resort to (e.g. arms, violence)" },
	{ "question": "診察", "answers": [ "しんさつ" ], "comment": "medical examination" },
	{ "question": "証明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "proof; verification; certification" },
	{ "question": "評価", "answers": [ "ひょうか" ], "comment": "valuation; estimation; assessment; evaluation; rating\nto value; to assess; to rate; to estimate value\nto appreciate; to value highly; to acknowledge the value (of something)" },
	{ "question": "評判", "answers": [ "ひょうばん" ], "comment": "fame; reputation; popularity\nrumour (rumor); talk" },
	{ "question": "試し", "answers": [ "ためし" ], "comment": "trial; test" },
	{ "question": "試す", "answers": [ "ためす" ], "comment": "to attempt; to test; to try out" },
	{ "question": "詩", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "modern poetry\npoem; verse of poetry" },
	{ "question": "詩人", "answers": [ "しじん" ], "comment": "poet" },
	{ "question": "詰める", "answers": [ "つめる" ], "comment": "to stuff into; to jam; to cram; to pack; to fill; to plug; to stop up\nto shorten; to move closer together\nto reduce (spending); to conserve\nto focus intently on; to strain oneself to do\nto work out (details)\nto be on duty; to be stationed\nto corner (esp. an opponent's king in shogi); to trap; to checkmate\nto cut off (one's finger as an act of apology); to catch (one's finger in a door, etc.)\nto continue ...; to keep doing ... without a break\nto do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly\nto force someone into a difficult situation by ..." },
	{ "question": "話し合う", "answers": [ "はなしあう" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk together" },
	{ "question": "話題", "answers": [ "わだい" ], "comment": "topic; subject" },
	{ "question": "詳しい", "answers": [ "くわしい" ], "comment": "detailed; full; accurate\nknowing very well; well-acquainted; well-informed" },
	{ "question": "誇り", "answers": [ "ほこり" ], "comment": "pride; boast" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる", "したためる" ], "comment": "to write up\nto recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "誕生", "answers": [ "たんじょう" ], "comment": "birth; creation; formation" },
	{ "question": "誘う", "answers": [ "さそう" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask; to call (for)\nto tempt; to lure; to induce" },
	{ "question": "語", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "language\nword\ntalk; recital\nnarration\ntopic" },
	{ "question": "語る", "answers": [ "かたる" ], "comment": "to talk about; to speak of; to tell; to narrate\nto recite; to chant\nto indicate; to show" },
	{ "question": "語学", "answers": [ "ごがく" ], "comment": "language study" },
	{ "question": "誤り", "answers": [ "あやまり" ], "comment": "error; mistake; slip; bug" },
	{ "question": "誤解", "answers": [ "ごかい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding" },
	{ "question": "説", "answers": [ "せつ" ], "comment": "theory; doctrine\nopinion; view\nrumour; rumor; gossip; hearsay" },
	{ "question": "読み", "answers": [ "よみ" ], "comment": "reading" },
	{ "question": "読書", "answers": [ "どくしょ" ], "comment": "reading" },
	{ "question": "誰か", "answers": [ "だれか" ], "comment": "someone; somebody" },
	{ "question": "課", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "lesson\nsection (in an organization); division; department\ncounter for lessons and chapters (of a book)" },
	{ "question": "調子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "tune; tone; key; pitch; time; rhythm\nvein; mood; way; manner; style; knack\ncondition; state of health\nimpetus; spur of the moment; strain\ntrend" },
	{ "question": "調査", "answers": [ "ちょうさ" ], "comment": "investigation; examination; inquiry; enquiry; survey" },
	{ "question": "請求", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "claim; demand; charge; application; request; billing (for a service)" },
	{ "question": "論じる", "answers": [ "ろんじる" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk about; to deal with (a topic)\nto argue; to dispute\nto take into consideration; to make an issue of" },
	{ "question": "論争", "answers": [ "ろんそう" ], "comment": "dispute; controversy" },
	{ "question": "論文", "answers": [ "ろんぶん" ], "comment": "thesis; essay; treatise; paper; article" },
	{ "question": "諦める", "answers": [ "あきらめる" ], "comment": "to give up; to abandon (hope, plans); to resign oneself (to)" },
	{ "question": "謎", "answers": [ "なぞ" ], "comment": "riddle; puzzle; enigma; mystery\nenigmatic; mysterious" },
	{ "question": "講演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "lecture; address; speech" },
	{ "question": "警告", "answers": [ "けいこく" ], "comment": "warning; advice" },
	{ "question": "議会", "answers": [ "ぎかい" ], "comment": "congress; parliament; diet; legislative assembly" },
	{ "question": "議員", "answers": [ "ぎいん" ], "comment": "member of the Diet, congress or parliament" },
	{ "question": "議論", "answers": [ "ぎろん" ], "comment": "argument; discussion; dispute; controversy" },
	{ "question": "議長", "answers": [ "ぎちょう" ], "comment": "chairman; speaker (e.g. of assembly); president (e.g. of council, senate, etc.); moderator (e.g. of a newsgroup)" },
	{ "question": "譲る", "answers": [ "ゆずる" ], "comment": "to turn over; to assign; to hand over; to transmit; to convey; to sell; to dispose of\nto yield; to surrender; to concede" },
	{ "question": "谷", "answers": [ "たに" ], "comment": "valley" },
	{ "question": "豆", "answers": [ "まめ" ], "comment": "legume (esp. edible legumes or their seeds, such as beans, peas, pulses, etc.); beans; peas\nsoya bean (Glycine max); soybean; soy\nfemale genitalia (esp. the clitoris)\nkidney\nminiature; tiny\nchild" },
	{ "question": "豊か", "answers": [ "ゆたか" ], "comment": "abundant; wealthy; plentiful; rich; affluent\nvery; extremely; full of; great" },
	{ "question": "豊富", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "abundance; wealth; plenty; bounty" },
	{ "question": "象", "answers": [ "ぞう" ], "comment": "phenomenon\nelephant (Elephantidae spp.)" },
	{ "question": "豪華", "answers": [ "ごうか" ], "comment": "wonderful; gorgeous; splendor; splendour; pomp; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "負け", "answers": [ "まけ" ], "comment": "defeat; loss; losing (a game)" },
	{ "question": "財産", "answers": [ "ざいさん" ], "comment": "property; fortune; assets" },
	{ "question": "貢献", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "contribution (furthering a goal or cause); services (to a cause)" },
	{ "question": "貧しい", "answers": [ "まずしい" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking (quantity and quality-wise); poor; scanty; skimpy; slight; inadequate" },
	{ "question": "販売", "answers": [ "はんばい" ], "comment": "sales; selling; marketing" },
	{ "question": "責める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "to condemn; to blame; to criticize; to criticise; to reproach; to accuse\nto urge; to press; to pester\nto torture; to torment; to persecute\nto break in (a horse)" },
	{ "question": "責任", "answers": [ "せきにん" ], "comment": "duty; responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)\nliability; onus" },
	{ "question": "貯金", "answers": [ "ちょきん" ], "comment": "putting money aside; savings; deposit (e.g. in a bank)\naccumulated surplus of wins; wins in the bank" },
	{ "question": "貴重", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "precious; valuable" },
	{ "question": "費用", "answers": [ "ひよう" ], "comment": "cost; expense" },
	{ "question": "資本", "answers": [ "しほん" ], "comment": "funds; capital" },
	{ "question": "資源", "answers": [ "しげん" ], "comment": "resources" },
	{ "question": "賛成", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "approval; agreement; support; favour; favor" },
	{ "question": "賞", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "prize; award" },
	{ "question": "賢い", "answers": [ "かしこい" ], "comment": "wise; clever; smart" },
	{ "question": "質", "answers": [ "しつ", "しち", "たち" ], "comment": "quality; value\nnature; inherent quality; character\nlogical quality\nquality; nature (of person)\ncollateral; pledge; pawned article" },
	{ "question": "贅沢", "answers": [ "ぜいたく" ], "comment": "luxury; extravagance\nto live in luxury; to indulge oneself\nlavish (use of something); abundant; copious; wasteful" },
	{ "question": "贈る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "to give (as a gift); to present\nto confer; to bestow; to award" },
	{ "question": "起こる", "answers": [ "おこる" ], "comment": "to occur; to happen" },
	{ "question": "越える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to cross; to pass through; to pass over (out of)\nto exceed" },
	{ "question": "越す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "to cross over (e.g. mountain); to go across\nto go over (e.g. with audience)\nto pass time (e.g. a winter)\nto surpass; to be better than; to exceed\nto move house\nto go; to come" },
	{ "question": "跡", "answers": [ "あと" ], "comment": "trace; tracks; mark; sign\nsite; remains; ruins\nscar\ntrace" },
	{ "question": "身", "answers": [ "み" ], "comment": "body\noneself\none's place; one's position\nmain part; meat (as opposed to bone, skin, etc.); wood (as opposed to bark); blade (as opposed to its handle); container (as opposed to its lid)\n(dead) body; corpse" },
	{ "question": "身体", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "body\ntorso; trunk\nbuild; physique; constitution\nhealth\ncorpse; dead body\nbody; physical system; person" },
	{ "question": "身長", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "height (of body); stature" },
	{ "question": "軍", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "army; force; troops\nwar; battle; campaign; fight\ntroops; forces" },
	{ "question": "軍隊", "answers": [ "ぐんたい" ], "comment": "armed forces; military; troops" },
	{ "question": "軒", "answers": [ "のき", "けん" ], "comment": "eaves\nnarrow aisle surrounding the core of a temple building\ncounter for buildings (esp. houses)\nsuffix for a pen name, stage name, etc." },
	{ "question": "転ぶ", "answers": [ "ころぶ" ], "comment": "to fall down; to fall over" },
	{ "question": "輝く", "answers": [ "かがやく" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to sparkle" },
	{ "question": "輪", "answers": [ "わ", "りん" ], "comment": "counter for wheels and flowers\nring; circle; loop\nhoop\nwheel\ncircle (e.g. of friends)" },
	{ "question": "輸入", "answers": [ "ゆにゅう" ], "comment": "importation; import; introduction\nafferent" },
	{ "question": "輸出", "answers": [ "ゆしゅつ" ], "comment": "export\nefferent" },
	{ "question": "辛い", "answers": [ "つらい", "からい" ], "comment": "spicy; hot\nsalty\nharsh (criticism); severe (punishment); strict\npainful; bitter; difficult; tough\npainful; bitter; heart-breaking; difficult (emotionally)\ntough; difficult; hard (usu. of situations)\ncruel; harsh; cold\ndifficult to ...; hard to ..." },
	{ "question": "辞める", "answers": [ "やめる" ], "comment": "to resign; to retire; to quit; to leave (one's job, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "農家", "answers": [ "のうか" ], "comment": "farmer; farming family\nfarmhouse" },
	{ "question": "農業", "answers": [ "のうぎょう" ], "comment": "agriculture" },
	{ "question": "農民", "answers": [ "のうみん" ], "comment": "farmer; peasant" },
	{ "question": "辺り", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "on the bank of; by the side of (e.g. a river, pond)\n(in the) neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity; nearby\naround (Sunday, last year, etc...)\nfor instance" },
	{ "question": "迎え", "answers": [ "むかえ" ], "comment": "meeting; greeting; welcome" },
	{ "question": "近代", "answers": [ "きんだい" ], "comment": "present day; modern times" },
	{ "question": "近頃", "answers": [ "ちかごろ" ], "comment": "lately; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "述べる", "answers": [ "のべる" ], "comment": "to state; to express; to mention" },
	{ "question": "迷子", "answers": [ "まいご" ], "comment": "lost child; lost person; stray child; missing child" },
	{ "question": "迷惑", "answers": [ "めいわく" ], "comment": "trouble; bother; annoyance" },
	{ "question": "追い付く", "answers": [ "おいつく" ], "comment": "to catch up (with); to draw level; to pull even; to reach\nto be compensated; to make up for one's loses" },
	{ "question": "追う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue\nto follow (a set order, a trend, etc.)\nto drive out; to oust; to expel\nto drive (e.g. a herd)\nto be pressed (e.g. for time)" },
	{ "question": "退屈", "answers": [ "たいくつ" ], "comment": "tedium; boredom" },
	{ "question": "逆", "answers": [ "ぎゃく" ], "comment": "reverse; opposite\nconverse (of a hypothesis, etc.)\ninverse (function)\ninverse; reverse" },
	{ "question": "逆らう", "answers": [ "さからう" ], "comment": "to go against; to oppose; to disobey; to defy" },
	{ "question": "途端", "answers": [ "とたん" ], "comment": "just (now, at the moment, etc.); just as; in the act of; as soon as; at the moment that" },
	{ "question": "通じる", "answers": [ "つうじる" ], "comment": "to be open (to traffic); to lead to; to communicate (with)\nto flow (liquid, current); to pass; to get through to\nto be understood; to be comprehended\nto be honored; to be good\nto be well versed in; to be well-informed\nto communicate clandestinely; to keep in touch (e.g. with the enemy)\nto form a liaison; to be intimate\nto spread widely; to disseminate" },
	{ "question": "通す", "answers": [ "とおす" ], "comment": "to stick through; to force through\nto spread throughout; to thoroughly diffuse\nto make a path between two points\nto proceed in a logical manner\nto let pass; to allow through\nto lead (someone) into (a house, room, etc.); to show in\nto go through (a middleman)\nto (look, listen) through (a window, wall, etc.)\nto pass (a law, applicant, etc.)\nto force to accept; to force agreement\nto continue (in a state); to persist in\nto do to the entirety of; to cover all of; to span the whole ...\nto do from beginning to end without a break\nto convey (one's ideas, etc.) to the other party\nto do to the end; to carry through; to complete" },
	{ "question": "通り", "answers": [ "とおり" ], "comment": "avenue; street; way; road\ncoming and going; street traffic\nflow (of water, air, etc.)\ntransmission (of sound); reach (e.g. of voice)\nfame; reputation; popularity\nthe same status or way; as (e.g. as expected, as I said)\nunderstanding; comprehension\ncounter for sets of things; counter for methods, ways, types\nin accordance with; following\nroughly; about\nStreet; Avenue" },
	{ "question": "通り過ぎる", "answers": [ "とおりすぎる" ], "comment": "to pass; to pass through" },
	{ "question": "通信", "answers": [ "つうしん" ], "comment": "correspondence; communication; transmission; news; signal; telecommunications" },
	{ "question": "通学", "answers": [ "つうがく" ], "comment": "commuting to school; school commute" },
	{ "question": "通行", "answers": [ "つうこう" ], "comment": "passage; passing\ncommon usage" },
	{ "question": "通過", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "passage through (e.g. train skipping a station); transit\npassing (e.g. exam, bill through parliament)" },
	{ "question": "速度", "answers": [ "そくど" ], "comment": "speed; velocity; rate" },
	{ "question": "連れ", "answers": [ "つれ" ], "comment": "companion; company" },
	{ "question": "連想", "answers": [ "れんそう" ], "comment": "association (of ideas); being reminded (of something); suggestion" },
	{ "question": "連続", "answers": [ "れんぞく" ], "comment": "serial; consecutive; continuity; occurring in succession; continuing" },
	{ "question": "逮捕", "answers": [ "たいほ" ], "comment": "arrest; apprehension; capture" },
	{ "question": "週", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "week" },
	{ "question": "週間", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "weeks (period of)" },
	{ "question": "進める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to advance; to promote; to hasten" },
	{ "question": "進学", "answers": [ "しんがく" ], "comment": "entering a higher-level school, esp. going on to university" },
	{ "question": "進歩", "answers": [ "しんぽ" ], "comment": "progress; advance; improvement; development" },
	{ "question": "遅刻", "answers": [ "ちこく" ], "comment": "lateness; late coming" },
	{ "question": "運", "answers": [ "うん" ], "comment": "fortune; luck" },
	{ "question": "運動", "answers": [ "うんどう" ], "comment": "exercise; physical training; work-out\nappeal; campaign; drive; crusade; movement; lobbying\nmotion; movement" },
	{ "question": "運転", "answers": [ "うんてん" ], "comment": "operation (of a machine, etc.); operating; running; run\ndriving\nworking (capital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "過ごす", "answers": [ "すごす" ], "comment": "to pass (time); to spend\nto overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption); to drink (alcohol)\nto take care of; to support\nto overdo; to do too much\nto ... without acting on it" },
	{ "question": "過去", "answers": [ "かこ" ], "comment": "the past; bygone days; the previous\na past (i.e. a personal history one would prefer remained secret); one's past\npast (tense); preterit; preterite\nprevious life" },
	{ "question": "道徳", "answers": [ "どうとく" ], "comment": "morals" },
	{ "question": "道路", "answers": [ "どうろ" ], "comment": "road; highway" },
	{ "question": "達する", "answers": [ "たっする" ], "comment": "to reach; to get to; to arrive at" },
	{ "question": "違い", "answers": [ "ちがい", "たがい" ], "comment": "difference; discrepancy" },
	{ "question": "違いない", "answers": [ "ちがいない" ], "comment": "(phrase) sure; no mistaking it; for certain" },
	{ "question": "違反", "answers": [ "いはん" ], "comment": "violation; offense; offence; breach; transgression; infringement; contravention\nbreaking (a contract, promise, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "適する", "answers": [ "てきする" ], "comment": "to fit; to suit" },
	{ "question": "適切", "answers": [ "てきせつ" ], "comment": "pertinent; appropriate; adequate; relevance" },
	{ "question": "適度", "answers": [ "てきど" ], "comment": "moderate" },
	{ "question": "適用", "answers": [ "てきよう" ], "comment": "applying (e.g. a technology); adoption" },
	{ "question": "選手", "answers": [ "せんしゅ" ], "comment": "player (in game); team member" },
	{ "question": "選択", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "selection; choice; option" },
	{ "question": "部分", "answers": [ "ぶぶん" ], "comment": "portion; section; part" },
	{ "question": "郵便", "answers": [ "ゆうびん" ], "comment": "mail service; postal service; mail; post\nmail; postal matter; postal items" },
	{ "question": "都会", "answers": [ "とかい" ], "comment": "city\nTokyo Metropolitan Assembly" },
	{ "question": "都市", "answers": [ "とし" ], "comment": "town; city; municipal; urban" },
	{ "question": "配達", "answers": [ "はいたつ" ], "comment": "delivery; distribution" },
	{ "question": "酒", "answers": [ "さけ" ], "comment": "alcohol; sake" },
	{ "question": "重大", "answers": [ "じゅうだい" ], "comment": "serious; important; significant; grave; weighty" },
	{ "question": "重要", "answers": [ "じゅうよう" ], "comment": "important; momentous; essential; principal; major" },
	{ "question": "重視", "answers": [ "じゅうし" ], "comment": "importance; stress; serious consideration\nto take something seriously; to attach importance; to stress" },
	{ "question": "野", "answers": [ "の" ], "comment": "plain; field\nhidden (structural) member\nwild\nlacking a political post" },
	{ "question": "量", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "quantity; amount; volume; portion (of food)\nprogress" },
	{ "question": "金", "answers": [ "きん", "かね" ], "comment": "gold\nmoney\nmetal\ngold (Au); golden (color); gold (medal, cup)\nvaluable; of highest value\nmoney; gold coin (orig. meaning)\nFriday\nmetal (fourth of the five elements)\nJin (dynasty of China; 1115-1234 CE)\ngold general\ntesticles\nkarat; carat" },
	{ "question": "金属", "answers": [ "きんぞく" ], "comment": "metal" },
	{ "question": "金庫", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "safe; strongbox; cashbox; vault; strongroom\ndepository; cash office; treasury; provider of funds\ntreasure house; treasury\nfinancial supporter; patron; financier; backer" },
	{ "question": "金曜", "answers": [ "きんよう" ], "comment": "Friday" },
	{ "question": "金額", "answers": [ "きんがく" ], "comment": "amount of money" },
	{ "question": "針", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "needle; pin\nhook\nstinger; thorn\nhand (e.g. clock, etc.); pointer\nstaple (for a stapler)\nneedlework; sewing\nmalice\ncounter for stitches" },
	{ "question": "釣り", "answers": [ "つり" ], "comment": "fishing; angling\nchange (e.g. for a purchase)\ntrolling; writing false posts online" },
	{ "question": "鉄", "answers": [ "てつ", "くろがね" ], "comment": "money\nmetal\niron (Fe)\nstrong and hard (as iron)\nrailway\nrailway enthusiast\niron" },
	{ "question": "鉄道", "answers": [ "てつどう" ], "comment": "railroad; railway; rail transport" },
	{ "question": "銀", "answers": [ "ぎん" ], "comment": "money\nmetal\nsilver (Ag)\nsilver coin; money\nsilver medal\nsilver colour; silver color\nbank\nsilver general" },
	{ "question": "銃", "answers": [ "じゅう" ], "comment": "gun; rifle; small arms" },
	{ "question": "銅貨", "answers": [ "どうか" ], "comment": "copper coin" },
	{ "question": "鋭い", "answers": [ "するどい" ], "comment": "sharp (blade); pointed\nsharp (pain); stabbing; cutting (remark); stinging; pointed (question or look); screeching (noise)\nperceptive; keen; quick (mind); astute; shrewd; discerning\nnimble; agile; quick" },
	{ "question": "鍋", "answers": [ "なべ" ], "comment": "saucepan; pot\nstew; hot pot" },
	{ "question": "鍵", "answers": [ "かぎ" ], "comment": "key\nlock\nkey (of a piano, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "鎖", "answers": [ "くさり" ], "comment": "chain; chains\nlock; padlock\ntablet; lozenge; pill" },
	{ "question": "長期", "answers": [ "ちょうき" ], "comment": "long-term" },
	{ "question": "閉じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.); to shut" },
	{ "question": "開始", "answers": [ "かいし" ], "comment": "start; commencement; beginning; initiation" },
	{ "question": "間", "answers": [ "ま", "あいだ", "かん" ], "comment": "space (between); gap; interval; distance\ntime (between); pause; break\nspan (temporal or spatial); stretch; period (while)\nrelationship (between, among)\nmembers (within, among)\ndue to; because of\ntime; pause\nspace\nroom\ninterval; space; interstice; threshold\nvalley; gorge; ravine\nloophole (in a wall); crenel; eyelet\ninterval; period of time\namong; between; inter-\n1.818 m (6 shaku)\ncounter used to number the gaps between pillars" },
	{ "question": "間違い", "answers": [ "まちがい" ], "comment": "mistake; error; blunder\naccident; mishap; trouble\nimproper conduct (e.g. between man and woman); indiscretion" },
	{ "question": "関する", "answers": [ "かんする" ], "comment": "to concern; to be related" },
	{ "question": "関心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "concern; interest" },
	{ "question": "関連", "answers": [ "かんれん" ], "comment": "relation; connection; relevance" },
	{ "question": "防ぐ", "answers": [ "ふせぐ" ], "comment": "to defend against; to protect against\nto prevent; to avert; to avoid" },
	{ "question": "降りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "降る", "answers": [ "くだる", "ふる" ], "comment": "to descend; to go down; to come down\nto be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.)\nto pass (of time)\nto surrender; to capitulate\n(often in neg. form) to be less than; to be inferior to\nto have the runs; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to be discharged from the body\nto precipitate; to fall (e.g. rain)" },
	{ "question": "降ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "限る", "answers": [ "かぎる" ], "comment": "to restrict; to limit; to confine\nto be restricted to; to be limited to; to be confined to" },
	{ "question": "限界", "answers": [ "げんかい" ], "comment": "limit; bound" },
	{ "question": "除く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to eliminate; to eradicate\nto exclude; to except" },
	{ "question": "陰", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "yin (i.e. the negative)\nunseen location (i.e. somewhere private)\nshade; shadow\nother side; back; background\nfemale private parts; female genitals" },
	{ "question": "陸", "answers": [ "りく" ], "comment": "satisfactory; decent; good; worthy\nland; shore\nsix" },
	{ "question": "陽気", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "cheerful; jovial; merry; lively\nweather; season\nspirit of yang" },
	{ "question": "隅", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "corner; nook; recess" },
	{ "question": "随分", "answers": [ "ずいぶん" ], "comment": "very; extremely; surprisingly; considerably\ncontemptible; reprehensible" },
	{ "question": "際", "answers": [ "さい", "きわ" ], "comment": "edge; brink; verge; side\ntime; moment of\non the occasion of; circumstances; juncture" },
	{ "question": "障害", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "obstacle; impediment; hindrance; difficulty; barrier\nhandicap; impairment; disability; disorder; malfunction" },
	{ "question": "隠す", "answers": [ "かくす" ], "comment": "to hide; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "隠れる", "answers": [ "かくれる" ], "comment": "to hide; to be hidden; to conceal oneself; to disappear" },
	{ "question": "集まり", "answers": [ "あつまり" ], "comment": "gathering; meeting; assembly; collection; attendance" },
	{ "question": "集中", "answers": [ "しゅうちゅう" ], "comment": "concentration; convergence; centralization; integration; gathering together" },
	{ "question": "集団", "answers": [ "しゅうだん" ], "comment": "group; mass" },
	{ "question": "雇う", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "to employ\nto hire; to charter" },
	{ "question": "離す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to separate; to part; to divide; to keep apart" },
	{ "question": "離れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "to be separated; to be apart; to be distant\nto leave; to go away\nto leave (a job, etc.); to quit; to give up\nto lose connection with; to drift away from" },
	{ "question": "離婚", "answers": [ "りこん" ], "comment": "divorce" },
	{ "question": "雰囲気", "answers": [ "ふんいき" ], "comment": "mood; ambience; ambiance; aura; feel\na certain air; presence; special aura; something (about someone)\nair; atmosphere" },
	{ "question": "雷", "answers": [ "かみなり" ], "comment": "lightning; thunder; thunderbolt\ngod of thunder; god of lightning\nanger; fit of anger\nthunder" },
	{ "question": "電子", "answers": [ "でんし" ], "comment": "electron\nelectronic" },
	{ "question": "需要", "answers": [ "じゅよう" ], "comment": "demand; request" },
	{ "question": "震える", "answers": [ "ふるえる" ], "comment": "to shiver; to shake; to quake; to tremble; to quaver; to quiver" },
	{ "question": "霜", "answers": [ "しも" ], "comment": "frost" },
	{ "question": "青年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "非常", "answers": [ "ひじょう" ], "comment": "emergency\nextraordinary; unusual" },
	{ "question": "面", "answers": [ "めん", "おもて", "つら" ], "comment": "face\nsurface\nmask (esp. a noh or kyogen mask)\nface; mug\nsurface\nsurrounding area\ncheek; cheeks\nface\nmask; face guard\n(in kendo) striking the head\nsurface (esp. a geometrical surface)\npage\naspect; facet; side\nchamfer\ncounter for broad, flat objects, levels or stages, e.g. in a video game\nlooking like a ...; acting as if a ...." },
	{ "question": "面倒", "answers": [ "めんどう" ], "comment": "trouble; bother\ntrouble; difficulty\ncare; attention" },
	{ "question": "革", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "leather\nleather; tanned animal hide\nkanji \"leather\" radical (radical 177)" },
	{ "question": "頂く", "answers": [ "いただく" ], "comment": "to receive; to get; to accept; to take; to buy\nto eat; to drink\nto be crowned with; to wear (on one's head); to have (on top)\nto have (as one's leader); to live under (a ruler); to install (a president)\nto get somebody to do something" },
	{ "question": "頂上", "answers": [ "ちょうじょう" ], "comment": "top; summit; peak" },
	{ "question": "頃", "answers": [ "ころ" ], "comment": "(approximate) time; around; about; toward\nsuitable time (or condition)\ntime of year; season\nqing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu)\ntime; period; days" },
	{ "question": "順", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "order; turn\nobedient; docile; submissive; meek" },
	{ "question": "順番", "answers": [ "じゅんばん" ], "comment": "turn (in line); order of things; sequential order" },
	{ "question": "順調", "answers": [ "じゅんちょう" ], "comment": "favourable; favorable; doing well; OK; all right" },
	{ "question": "預ける", "answers": [ "あずける" ], "comment": "to give into custody; to leave (a child) in the care of; to entrust; to deposit\nto lean on; to put one's weight on" },
	{ "question": "頬", "answers": [ "ほお" ], "comment": "cheek (of face)\nface; mug\nsurface\nsurrounding area\ncheek; cheeks" },
	{ "question": "頭痛", "answers": [ "ずつう" ], "comment": "headache" },
	{ "question": "頼る", "answers": [ "たよる" ], "comment": "to rely on; to have recourse to; to depend on" },
	{ "question": "題", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "title; subject; theme; topic\nproblem (on a test); question\ncounter for questions (on a test)" },
	{ "question": "額", "answers": [ "ひたい", "がく" ], "comment": "picture (framed)\namount or sum (of money)\nforehead; brow" },
	{ "question": "願い", "answers": [ "ねがい" ], "comment": "desire; wish; request; prayer; petition; application" },
	{ "question": "願う", "answers": [ "ねがう" ], "comment": "to desire; to wish; to hope\nto beg; to request; to implore; to pray\nto have something done for oneself" },
	{ "question": "風景", "answers": [ "ふうけい" ], "comment": "scenery; scene; landscape; view; sight\nscene (e.g. of a crime)" },
	{ "question": "飛ばす", "answers": [ "とばす" ], "comment": "to fly; to fire; to hurl; to launch; to make fly\nto skip over; to omit; to drop (e.g. stitch)\nto run or drive fast; to gallop\nto spread a rumour (rumor); to tell a story; to tell a joke\nto remove; to get rid of; to transfer\nto attack; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "飛び出す", "answers": [ "とびだす" ], "comment": "to jump out; to rush out; to fly out\nto appear (suddenly)\nto protrude; to project\nto butt in" },
	{ "question": "飛行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "aviation; flight; flying\nto fly; to take a flight\nflying without hindrance" },
	{ "question": "食う", "answers": [ "くう" ], "comment": "to eat\nto live; to make a living; to survive\nto bite; to sting (as insects do)\nto tease; to torment; to taunt; to make light of; to make fun of\nto encroach on; to eat into; to consume\nto defeat a superior; to threaten a position\nto consume time and-or resources\nto receive something (usu. an unfavourable event)\nto have sexual relations with a woman, esp. for the first time" },
	{ "question": "食事", "answers": [ "しょくじ" ], "comment": "meal\nto eat" },
	{ "question": "食卓", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "dining table" },
	{ "question": "食品", "answers": [ "しょくひん" ], "comment": "food; food products; foodstuffs" },
	{ "question": "食料", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "food" },
	{ "question": "食欲", "answers": [ "しょくよく" ], "comment": "appetite (for food)" },
	{ "question": "食物", "answers": [ "しょくもつ" ], "comment": "food; foodstuff\nfood; foodstuff\nprey; victim" },
	{ "question": "食糧", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "food (esp. staple food such as rice or wheat); provisions; rations; food supply" },
	{ "question": "飯", "answers": [ "めし" ], "comment": "cooked rice\nmeal; food\none's livelihood\ncooked rice\ncooked rice" },
	{ "question": "飽きる", "answers": [ "あきる" ], "comment": "to get tired of; to lose interest in; to have enough" },
	{ "question": "首相", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "Prime Minister; Chancellor (Germany, Austria, etc.); Premier" },
	{ "question": "首都", "answers": [ "しゅと" ], "comment": "capital city; metropolis" },
	{ "question": "香り", "answers": [ "かおり" ], "comment": "aroma; fragrance; scent; smell" },
	{ "question": "馬", "answers": [ "うま" ], "comment": "horse\nhorse racing\npromoted bishop" },
	{ "question": "馬鹿", "answers": [ "ばか" ], "comment": "fool; idiot\ntrivial matter; folly; absurdity\nfoolish; stupid; dull; absurd; ridiculous\nMactra chinensis (species of trough shell)" },
	{ "question": "駄目", "answers": [ "だめ" ], "comment": "no good; not serving its purpose; useless; broken\nhopeless; wasted; in vain; purposeless\ncannot; must not; not allowed\nneutral point (in go); intersection owned by neither player at the end of a game" },
	{ "question": "駐車", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "parking (e.g. car)" },
	{ "question": "騒ぎ", "answers": [ "さわぎ" ], "comment": "uproar; disturbance" },
	{ "question": "騒音", "answers": [ "そうおん" ], "comment": "noise" },
	{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね" ], "comment": "knack; skill; trick; secret; know-how; the ropes; hang\nbone\nframe\noutline; core\nbackbone; spirit; fortitude\nlaborious; troublesome; difficult" },
	{ "question": "骨折", "answers": [ "こっせつ" ], "comment": "bone fracture" },
	{ "question": "高価", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "high price" },
	{ "question": "高速", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "high speed; high gear\nhighway; freeway; expressway; motorway" },
	{ "question": "髪の毛", "answers": [ "かみのけ" ], "comment": "hair (head)" },
	{ "question": "鬼", "answers": [ "おに" ], "comment": "oni; ogre; demon\nspirit of a deceased person\nogre-like person (i.e. fierce, relentless, merciless, etc.)\nit (in a game of tag, hide-and-seek, etc.)\nChinese \"ghost\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nvery; extremely; super-" },
	{ "question": "魅力", "answers": [ "みりょく" ], "comment": "charm; fascination; glamour; glamor; attraction; appeal" },
	{ "question": "鳴る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "to sound; to ring; to resound; to echo; to roar; to rumble" },
	{ "question": "黒板", "answers": [ "こくばん" ], "comment": "blackboard" },
	{ "question": "鼻", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "nose" }
]
}
